<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<articles>
<article id="0000001" published-at="2017-09-10" title="After DeVos Announced Plans To Reexamine Title IX, Texas Attorney Tweets He Would 'Be Ok If [She] Was Sexually Assaulted'"><p>When explaining her decision to reevaluate Title IX guidelines as they pertain to sexual assault on college campuses, Secretary of Education Betsy DeVos <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/betsy-devos-overhaul-obama-era-guidance-campus-sex-assault-n799471" type="external">said</a>: ?Every survivor of sexual misconduct must be taken seriously. Every student accused of sexual misconduct must know that guilt is not predetermined.?</p> 
<p>The Obama administration?s changes to Title IX have been <a href="" type="internal">criticized</a> for, among other things, substantially lowering the burden of proof as it pertains to sexual assault, as well as denying elements of due process to the accused.</p> 
<p>However, many progressives are lashing out at DeVos because they hate her, and also rape culture and stuff.</p> 
<p>Perhaps the most grotesque attack came when Rob Ranco, a Texas attorney, tweeted Friday that ?I'm not wishing for it ? but I'd be ok if #BetsyDevos was sexually assaulted. #Sexual Assault #TitleIX.?</p> 
<p><a href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2017/sep/9/rob-ranco-texas-lawyer-says-he-would-be-ok-if-bets/" type="external">The Washington Times</a> reports that in several other tweets (condensed for this publication), Ranco wrote: ?Perhaps Betsy doesn?t understand how horrible rape is. She?s made the world more dangerous for my daughters. I need her to understand,? and ?Make the world more dangerous for my daughters ? intentionally ? and your well being is not my concern. Full stop.?</p> 
<p>Ranco's additional tweets don't make his first one any less vile.</p> 
<p>In the wake of the overwhelming negative response, Ranco locked his Twitter profile, then <a href="https://www.redstate.com/brandon_morse/2017/09/09/cowardly-austin-lawyer-wished-sexual-assault-betsy-devos-locked-twitter-account/" type="external">deleted</a> it.</p> 
<p>Many on social media are calling for the attorney to be fired from The Carlson Law Firm, where he is a partner, or even disbarred:</p> 
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/PrisonPlanet" type="external">@PrisonPlanet</a> I'm wishing for it... but I'd be ok if <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RobRanco?src=hash" type="external">#RobRanco</a> was disbarred.</p> 
<p>As of this publication, the law firm?s Twitter account has also been locked, though Ranco is still listed on the official website?s ? <a href="https://www.carlsonattorneys.com/team-member/robert-ranco/" type="external">Team</a>? section.</p> 
<p>A <a href="https://www.change.org/p/texas-bar-association-removal-of-law-license-for-misogynistic-tweet-of-approval-of-sexual-assault-on-woman?recruiter=778517695&amp;amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share_twitter_responsive" type="external">petition</a>, which currently boasts nearly 2,200 signatures, has also been started in an effort to get the attorney disbarred.</p></article>
<article id="0000002" published-at="2017-05-05" title="University To Award Trayvon Martin With Posthumous Degree In Aviation"><p>A Florida university will honor Trayvon Martin with a posthumous Bachelor of Science Degree in Aviation at a May 13 commencement ceremony. The degree will be accepted by his parents, Tracy Martin and Sabrina Fulton.</p> 
<p>Seventeen-year-old Martin was killed in February of 2012 by former neighborhood watch captain George Zimmerman, who is Hispanic, in self-defense. After a long, racially-charged public debate and court trial, Zimmerman was completely exonerated in July of 2013.</p> 
<p>Florida Memorial University officially <a href="https://www.facebook.com/FLMemorialUniv/" type="external">announced</a>the posthumous degree via Facebook on Wednesday.</p> 
<p>"The University will confer upon TRAYVON MARTIN a posthumous degree in Aeronautical Science with a concentration in Flight Education, in honor of the steps he took during his young life toward becoming a pilot," says the Facebook post. "This particular Bachelor?s degree is designated for those studying to be pilots. Martin?s parents, both social justice activists and co-founders of The Trayvon Martin Foundation ... will accept the degree on behalf of their son."</p> 
<p>?Of special significance is awarding posthumously the Bachelor of Science Degree in Aviation to Trayvon Martin. Sybrina, our alum, epitomizes strength and dignity as she uplifts other victims of violence while effecting change for a more equal and just society," said Florida Memorial University President Dr. Roslyn Clark Artis.</p> 
<p>Additionally, the school will host a post-commencement fundraiser which will partly support The Trayvon Martin Foundation.</p></article>
<article id="0000008" published-at="2017-11-15" title="Texas State University suspends Greek life after student death"><p>Nov. 15 (UPI) ? Texas State University has suspended all Greek life activity on campus after a pledge died after attending an event hosted by a university fraternity.</p> 
<p>Police officers found Matthew Ellis, a 20-year-old Phi Kappa Psi pledge, dead on Monday after they responded to an off-campus call. Ellis attended a Greek life event on Sunday hosted by fraternity members, but it is unclear if the event was hosted by one fraternity or multiple fraternities.</p> 
<p>Although an autopsy has been ordered, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/storyline/hazing-in-america/texas-state-university-suspends-greek-life-activity-after-frat-pledge-n820946" type="external">a preliminary investigation suggested alcohol poisoning</a> as a factor in the student?s death.</p> 
<p>Phi Kappa Psi Executive Director Mark Guidi said that the organization is ?heartbroken.?</p> 
<p>?Our thoughts and prayers are with his family, friends and the entire TSU student body during this difficult time,? Giudi said.</p> 
<p>Texas State University President Denise M. Trauth <a href="http://www.txstate.edu/news/news_releases/news_archive/2017/November-2017/Greeks111417.html" type="external">released a statement</a> announcing the suspension of Greek life activity on campus.</p> 
<p>?I am deeply saddened by the tragic death of one of our students who attended an off-campus social event on Sunday evening hosted by members of a university fraternity,? Trauth said.</p> 
<p>?As a result of this tragedy, I have suspended activities of all Greek fraternity and sorority chapters at Texas State. These chapters are prohibited from holding new-member events, chapter meetings, social functions, and philanthropic activities until a thorough review of the Greek Affairs system is completed.?</p> 
<p>Trauth also said Vice President for Student Affairs Dr. Joanne Smith would ?immediately initiate this review? and would ?propose recommendations? for the Greek chapters to show their ?commitment to the core values of Texas State.?</p> 
<p>?It is imperative that our entire university community develop a culture that places the highest priority on the safety of its students, faculty, and staff.?</p></article>
<article id="0000009" published-at="2015-06-10" title="Red Sox waste Rodriguez outing in 1-0 loss to Orioles"><p>BALTIMORE (AP) ? On a night in which Boston didn?t score a run and plummeted into last place in the AL East, there was reason for optimism in Red Sox Nation.</p> 
<p>Rookie Eduardo Rodriguez turned in another sharp performance, one that made a 1-0 loss to the Baltimore Orioles on Tuesday night far easier to swallow.</p> 
<p>Rodriguez allowed three hits and three walks over six shutout innings. The former Orioles prospect was vying to become the first left-hander since Kazuhisa Ishii of the Dodgers in 2002 to win his first three major league appearances.</p> 
<p>?Through three starts, we?re looking at a pretty special young man,? Red Sox manager John Farrell said.</p> 
<p>Obtained by Boston last July in the trade that sent reliever Andrew Miller to Baltimore, Rodriguez struck out seven and lowered his ERA to 0.44. The 22-year-old has yielded only eight hits and a run over 20 1/3 innings.</p> 
<p>?What he does so well is he?s able to come back out and establish strike one, even to the first hitter of the inning,? Farrell said. ?He?s done a great job of remaining focused pitch-to-pitch.?</p> 
<p>After spending four years in the Orioles? minor league system, Rodriguez is now a star with one of Baltimore?s division rivals.</p> 
<p>?I?m sure there?s some guys, if they could pick a scenario, that he would pitch well and we?d win,? Orioles manager Buck Showalter said. ?I don?t wish bad on anybody. I know one thing: The Red Sox will trade with us again. If you always make a pretty even trade, they like working with you.?</p> 
<p>Steve Pearce scored in the seventh inning on a wild pitch by Matt Barnes, and the Orioles won for the fourth time in five games. Chad Roe (1-0) pitched 1 1/3 innings to earn his first AL victory, and Zach Britton got five outs for his 16th save.</p> 
<p>Barnes (2-1) entered in the seventh and immediately gave up the game?s first run. Pearce doubled, took third on a single by J.J. Hardy and came home when Barnes bounced a breaking ball past catcher Blake Swihart.</p> 
<p>With two on and one out in the eighth, Britton replaced Roe and struck out David Ortiz and Mike Napoli to blunt Boston?s final threat.</p> 
<p>Red Sox left fielder Hanley Ramirez was removed in the third inning with a bruised left knee. After fouling a ball off his leg, Ramirez remained on the ground for several minutes before resuming his at-bat. He drew a walk and left for a pinch runner.</p> 
<p>Orioles starter Miguel Gonzalez departed in the fifth inning with a right groin strain after giving up four hits and a pair of walks.</p> 
<p>He was replaced by T.J. McFarland, who got two straight outs to strand a runner on third base.</p> 
<p>In the bottom half, Baltimore got two runners on with no outs before Rodriguez retired Manny Machado on a fielder?s choice and struck out Delmon Young and Adam Jones. After Jones swung through a third strike, Rodriguez enthusiastically pounded his right fist into his glove four times as he walked off the mound.</p> 
<p>?Men on first and second with two outs and then strike him out like that,? the lefty said. ?It?s big for me.?</p> 
<p>Rodriguez finished with a 1-2-3 sixth inning, getting the final out on a close play at first base in which Nolan Reimold was ruled out after a replay review overturned the initial call.</p> 
<p>THIS AND THAT</p> 
<p>Red Sox: Rodriguez is the first Red Sox pitcher since 1914 to begin his career with at least seven strikeouts in each of his first three starts. ... Boston has lost seven of its last eight road games. ... It was the fifth time Boston has been shut out since May 8.</p> 
<p>Orioles: Showalter has 1,286th career wins, one behind Charlie Grimm for 32nd place on the career list. ... The last time Baltimore beat Boston 1-0 and neither team recorded an RBI was April 9, 1976.</p> 
<p>TRAINERS ROOM</p> 
<p>Red Sox: RHP Justin Masterson (right shoulder tendinitis) worked out with the Red Sox on the eve of his third rehab appearance, Wednesday for Triple-A Pawtucket.</p> 
<p>Orioles: RHP Kevin Gausman (right shoulder tendinitis) will continue his rehab assignment with a start for Double-A Bowie on Thursday.</p> 
<p>ON DECK</p> 
<p>Red Sox: RHP Rick Porcello starts for Boston on Thursday. He?s lost three straight starts and is 3-6 lifetime against Baltimore.</p> 
<p>Orioles: LHP Wei-Yin Chen makes his 12th start, looking to double his season win total. He?s got a 3.18 ERA, but is 1-4 and winless since May 9.</p> 
<p>BALTIMORE (AP) ? On a night in which Boston didn?t score a run and plummeted into last place in the AL East, there was reason for optimism in Red Sox Nation.</p> 
<p>Rookie Eduardo Rodriguez turned in another sharp performance, one that made a 1-0 loss to the Baltimore Orioles on Tuesday night far easier to swallow.</p> 
<p>Rodriguez allowed three hits and three walks over six shutout innings. The former Orioles prospect was vying to become the first left-hander since Kazuhisa Ishii of the Dodgers in 2002 to win his first three major league appearances.</p> 
<p>?Through three starts, we?re looking at a pretty special young man,? Red Sox manager John Farrell said.</p> 
<p>Obtained by Boston last July in the trade that sent reliever Andrew Miller to Baltimore, Rodriguez struck out seven and lowered his ERA to 0.44. The 22-year-old has yielded only eight hits and a run over 20 1/3 innings.</p> 
<p>?What he does so well is he?s able to come back out and establish strike one, even to the first hitter of the inning,? Farrell said. ?He?s done a great job of remaining focused pitch-to-pitch.?</p> 
<p>After spending four years in the Orioles? minor league system, Rodriguez is now a star with one of Baltimore?s division rivals.</p> 
<p>?I?m sure there?s some guys, if they could pick a scenario, that he would pitch well and we?d win,? Orioles manager Buck Showalter said. ?I don?t wish bad on anybody. I know one thing: The Red Sox will trade with us again. If you always make a pretty even trade, they like working with you.?</p> 
<p>Steve Pearce scored in the seventh inning on a wild pitch by Matt Barnes, and the Orioles won for the fourth time in five games. Chad Roe (1-0) pitched 1 1/3 innings to earn his first AL victory, and Zach Britton got five outs for his 16th save.</p> 
<p>Barnes (2-1) entered in the seventh and immediately gave up the game?s first run. Pearce doubled, took third on a single by J.J. Hardy and came home when Barnes bounced a breaking ball past catcher Blake Swihart.</p> 
<p>With two on and one out in the eighth, Britton replaced Roe and struck out David Ortiz and Mike Napoli to blunt Boston?s final threat.</p> 
<p>Red Sox left fielder Hanley Ramirez was removed in the third inning with a bruised left knee. After fouling a ball off his leg, Ramirez remained on the ground for several minutes before resuming his at-bat. He drew a walk and left for a pinch runner.</p> 
<p>Orioles starter Miguel Gonzalez departed in the fifth inning with a right groin strain after giving up four hits and a pair of walks.</p> 
<p>He was replaced by T.J. McFarland, who got two straight outs to strand a runner on third base.</p> 
<p>In the bottom half, Baltimore got two runners on with no outs before Rodriguez retired Manny Machado on a fielder?s choice and struck out Delmon Young and Adam Jones. After Jones swung through a third strike, Rodriguez enthusiastically pounded his right fist into his glove four times as he walked off the mound.</p> 
<p>?Men on first and second with two outs and then strike him out like that,? the lefty said. ?It?s big for me.?</p> 
<p>Rodriguez finished with a 1-2-3 sixth inning, getting the final out on a close play at first base in which Nolan Reimold was ruled out after a replay review overturned the initial call.</p> 
<p>THIS AND THAT</p> 
<p>Red Sox: Rodriguez is the first Red Sox pitcher since 1914 to begin his career with at least seven strikeouts in each of his first three starts. ... Boston has lost seven of its last eight road games. ... It was the fifth time Boston has been shut out since May 8.</p> 
<p>Orioles: Showalter has 1,286th career wins, one behind Charlie Grimm for 32nd place on the career list. ... The last time Baltimore beat Boston 1-0 and neither team recorded an RBI was April 9, 1976.</p> 
<p>TRAINERS ROOM</p> 
<p>Red Sox: RHP Justin Masterson (right shoulder tendinitis) worked out with the Red Sox on the eve of his third rehab appearance, Wednesday for Triple-A Pawtucket.</p> 
<p>Orioles: RHP Kevin Gausman (right shoulder tendinitis) will continue his rehab assignment with a start for Double-A Bowie on Thursday.</p> 
<p>ON DECK</p> 
<p>Red Sox: RHP Rick Porcello starts for Boston on Thursday. He?s lost three straight starts and is 3-6 lifetime against Baltimore.</p> 
<p>Orioles: LHP Wei-Yin Chen makes his 12th start, looking to double his season win total. He?s got a 3.18 ERA, but is 1-4 and winless since May 9.</p></article>
<article id="0000010" title="Eve and the New Jerusalem"><p>Imaginings of a utopian, or utopian socialist, future can be traced from chapters in Scripture to present-day works. The 19th century was particularly fruitful in this respect; it not only produced works of literary imagination but abounded in significant, organized movements in Europe, some of them exported to this country, aiming to mobilize communities on egalitarian principles. But as it concerns the liberation of women, none was more energetic than that of the Owenites in England (who were among those roundly condemned as ?unscientific? by Friedrich Engels). They were founded by Robert Owen, a Welsh manufacturer who first experimented with a kind of anticapitalist ?social engineering? in his own mills, then turned to organizing a general movement for the betterment of men and women? and to this Barbara Taylor directs her primary interest in a richly detailed book, Eve and the New Jerusalem, from which we excerpt a brief section below.</p> 
<p>Feminism and socialism were not always partners but they did come together, the author argues, in the Owenite movement. She writes: ?One hundred and fifty years later, however, it is precisely this aspect of Owenism?its theoretical and practical commitment to women?s liberation?which is least remembered. . . . To Robert Owen and his followers, particularly his feminist followers, socialism represented a struggle to achieve ?perfect equality and perfect freedom at every level of social existence.'? In this book, Barbara Taylor has rectified a gap in historical scholarship, including that of the left. We have had to delete numerous footnotes that provide evidence in support of her contentions.?Eds.</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000012" published-at="2016-09-26" title="Jewish Organization's Huge Day Of Unity On Tuesday"><p>Against the backdrop of an increasingly polarized political landscape, one organization is issuing a clarion call for collective unity and understanding. On Tuesday, Acheinu, a Jewish missionary group working to draw Jews closer to the traditional core of Judaism, is holding a <a href="http://dayofjewishunity.com/" type="external">Day of Jewish Unity</a> to consolidate the disparate voices of the diaspora in a seven-hour period (7 am- 2pm) of sober reflection.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>?Orchestrated by the Acheinu organization, the Day of Jewish Unity was born: a revolutionary initiative designed to unify all Jewish people from around the world in a day of prayer on behalf of the current -and cautioning ? state of affairs, both nationally and internationally,? explains the event?s webpage.</p> 
<p>Under the hashtag #DayofJewishUnity, Acheinu is working to mobilize one million Jews of varied ideological orientations from around the world to take a step back and reexamine the often petty and disorienting political divisions that divide us. The event is open to people of all faiths, but Acheinu is specifically marketing its message to Jews, many of whom have felt marginalized or overshadowed by the forceful social currents of grievance-based identity politics.</p> 
<p>Watch Acheinu?s promotional video below:</p> 
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/182868992" type="external">Will the character assassination ever stop...</a> from <a href="https://vimeo.com/dayofjewishunity" type="external">Day of Jewish Unity</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com" type="external">Vimeo</a>.</p> 
<p>In previous years, the annual Day of Jewish Unity has galvanized hundreds of thousands of people from Jerusalem to New York City, thanks to Acheinu?s powerful videos and promotional material. In fact, the organization drew a record-setting 500,000 participants in the 2015 event. This year, they plan on doubling that.</p> 
<p>As Americans, and quite frankly, people across the world, set to watch what will likely be one of the most cynical and rancorous debates in modern history on Monday night, it?s worth remembering that tribalism and partisanship don?t have to define us.</p> 
<p>?There is no civility in politics anymore. Our politicians cannot get anything passed because of so much animosity,? notes the event?s webpage. adding:</p> 
<p>We need to have bipartisan decency and respect for our counterparts. There once was a time when members of Congress would call their colleagues from the other side of the aisle their "friends." This year, the Presidential candidates didn't even congratulate each other after they won their respective races.</p> 
<p>Purposely scheduled less than 24 hours after the Clinton-Trump showdown, the Day of Jewish Unity is designed to counter the scourge of bitter political division infecting public discourse.</p> 
<p>If you?re feeling jaded after Monday?s debate, then there may be an outlet or perhaps even a way to reinstate your faith in humanity. To partake in Tuesday?s Day of Jewish Unity, Acheinu is asking event participants to do two simple things:</p> 
<p>Recite two chapters of Psalms</p> 
<p>Refrain from speaking gossip and harmful speech</p> 
<p>For more information about the event, see <a href="http://dayofjewishunity.com/" type="external">here</a>.</p></article>
<article id="0000015" published-at="2016-11-29" title="BREAKING: Trump Reaches Agreement To Keep 1,000 Carrier Jobs In Indiana, Keeping Major Campaign Promise"><p>President-elect Donald Trump has reached an agreement with United Technologies (UTC) to keep 1,000 Carrier jobs in the state of Indiana, according to CNBC. Both Trump's transition and Carrier have confirmed that a deal has indeed been struck.</p> 
<p>BREAKING: Trump team and United Technologies reach agreement on keeping close to 1,000 factory jobs in Carrier plant in Indiana - sources</p> 
<p>We are pleased to have reached a deal with President-elect Trump &amp;amp; VP-elect Pence to keep close to 1,000 jobs in Indy. More details soon.</p> 
<p>The company had planned on moving thousands of jobs to Mexico, to the chagrin of workers and labor groups. On Thanksgiving Day, Trump said via Twitter that he was ?working hard? to ?get Carrier A.C. company to stay in the U.S. (Indiana).? After days of negotiation with Carrier, he seems to have succeeded in keeping his campaign promise.</p> 
<p>I am working hard, even on Thanksgiving, trying to get Carrier A.C. Company to stay in the U.S. (Indiana). MAKING PROGRESS - Will know soon!</p> 
<p>Manufacturing jobs have been increasingly exported to foreign countries, including China and Mexico over the last few decades. Hundreds of thousands of blue collar workers have been laid off as a result. American manufacturers say, however, that in order to stay competitive in the global economy they need to keep costs low. The most efficient way to do that is to hire cheap foreign labor. Carrier Corp was looking to follow this formula to keep profit margins in the green.</p> 
<p>?The jobs at Carrier Corp. are on the way to Mexico because the company concluded that it could not stay competitive and reward its shareholders unless it took advantage of lower production costs south of the border,? <a href="http://www.courant.com/business/hc-trump-carrier-20161128-story.html" type="external">reports</a> CNBC. ?Things are as simple as that??</p> 
<p>But Trump (or Mike Pence, who is still the governor of Indiana) managed to work his magic and convince Carrier?s parent company, UTC, to keep 1,000 jobs in Indiana where manufacturing jobs have been hemorrhaging for decades.</p> 
<p>Promising a combination of tax relief and regulation easing, Trump made an offer UTC couldn?t refuse. Left-wing economic populists like Bernie Sanders pushed Trump to make Carrier stay in the United States, suggesting that it was something the Trumpian right and labor left could agree on. Rather than incentivizing the conglomerate, Sanders and his allies were looking to use UTC?s multi-billionaire business relationship with the Pentagon as leverage. While Trump had promised to deploy similarly coercive tactics, such as high tariffs and penalties on companies that ship jobs abroad, he ultimately took a free market approach to the problem.</p> 
<p>During the presidential campaign, Trump called out Carrier by name and used the air conditioning company as an example of the worker unfriendly economic environment the United States has become.</p> 
<p>?From the earliest days of his campaign, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/topic/person/donald-trump?inline=nyt-per" type="external">Donald J. Trump</a> made keeping manufacturing jobs in the United States his signature economic issue, and the decision by Carrier, the big air-conditioner company, to move 2,000 of them from Indiana to Mexico was a tailor-made talking point for him on the stump,? <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/29/business/trump-to-announce-carrier-plant-will-keep-jobs-in-us.html?smid=tw-share" type="external">explains</a> The New York Times.</p> 
<p>Championing a populist economic message, Trump vowed to keep more jobs here in the United States. While technology will likely continue replacing manufacturing jobs at a much faster rate than foreign labor ever could, the billionaire businessman?s Carrier deal is a symbolic victory for the ?America first? Trump movement.</p> 
<p>Without a doubt, it?s a good way to start a presidency. However, there?s only so much the federal government can do to alleviate the economic hardship of the Rust Belt, America?s manufacturing heartland. The steamboat of globalization and technological innovation cannot be tamed, let alone reversed. In short, there won?t be a manufacturing renaissance. That?s a pipe dream.</p> 
<p>Nonetheless, it looks like Trump came through this time around.</p> 
<p>Trump and future vice-president/current Indiana governor. Mike Pence plan on holding a event at the Carrier plant in Indiana on Thursday.</p></article>
<article id="0000016" published-at="2017-12-27" title="Winning numbers drawn in ?2 By 2? game"><p>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) _ The winning numbers in Tuesday evening?s drawing of the ?2 By 2? game were:</p> 
<p>Red Balls: 9-21, White Balls: 10-19</p> 
<p>(Red Balls: nine, twenty-one; White Balls: ten, nineteen)</p> 
<p>Estimated jackpot: $22,000</p> 
<p>? Top Prize $22,000.</p> 
<p>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) _ The winning numbers in Tuesday evening?s drawing of the ?2 By 2? game were:</p> 
<p>Red Balls: 9-21, White Balls: 10-19</p> 
<p>(Red Balls: nine, twenty-one; White Balls: ten, nineteen)</p> 
<p>Estimated jackpot: $22,000</p> 
<p>? Top Prize $22,000.</p></article>
<article id="0000020" title="ANALYSIS: Does gay debate mirror church dispute on slavery?"><p>WASHINGTON&amp;#160;(RNS) ? One group of Christians confidently proclaims that a plain reading of the Bible is a slam-dunk in their favor. The other side appeals to Scripture?s grand narrative toward freedom and inclusive love.</p> 
<p>The argument boils over and ripples through the wider culture.</p> 
<p>The search for middle ground proves futile. Denominations break apart.</p> 
<p>Sound familiar? It could be 2010 ? or the mid-19th century.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>As churches and denominations in the United States slog through divisive and long-running arguments over homosexuality, many Protestant progressives have sought to claim the historical and moral high ground by aligning their cause with abolitionism.</p> 
<p>?I think almost everybody who makes the liberal argument about homosexuality makes the connection with abolition and slavery,? said Jeffrey Krehbiel, a Washington, D.C., pastor in the Presbyterian Church (USA) who supports gay rights.</p> 
<p>Abolitionists, he said, ?were the first to make the argument that the plain reading of the text maybe isn?t the most fruitful way to read the Bible.?</p> 
<p>But while there are striking parallels between the slavery and homosexuality debates, historians caution that important differences emerge upon close examination.</p> 
<p>In both eras, cultural trends forced Christians to question practices that long had been taken for granted, said Mark Noll, a professor of American religious history at the University of Notre Dame and author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0807830127?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wwwbaptiststa-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0807830127" type="external">The Civil War as a Theological Crisis</a>.</p> 
<p>Likewise, the Bible, and how to interpret it, has played a central role both then and now, Noll said.</p> 
<p>In the 19th century, even some Northern abolitionists concluded the Bible condoned slavery.</p> 
<p>Many, therefore, sought other sources of morality and methods of biblical interpretation; conservatives countered that such appeals undermined the power of the sacred text.</p> 
<p>As conflict heated up, Noll writes in his book, slavery?s defenders increasingly saw ?doubts about biblical defense of slavery as doubts about the authority of the Bible itself.?</p> 
<p>As with slavery, few Christians are neutral on homosexuality.</p> 
<p>?Like the situation in the 1830s and ?40s, once a certain kind of heat is generated, it becomes really hard to talk through these various kinds of debating strategies and implications,? Noll said.</p> 
<p>Methodists, Presbyterians, Baptists ? and to some extent, Episcopalians ? all split over slavery, mainly along the Mason-Dixon Line. Some reunited decades later. Baptists re-main apart to this day.</p> 
<p>Likewise, in the last few years, a number of mainline Protestant congregations have parted with their denominations over homosexuality, although in far fewer numbers than during mid-19th century splits.</p> 
<p>But the exodus may not be over. For example, conservative Presbyterians and United Methodists have threatened to leave en masse if their denominations decides to allow gay clergy and same-sex marriages.</p> 
<p>?The parallels to the contemporary debate are fairly striking,? said Mark Valeri, a professor of church history at <a href="http://www.upsem.edu/" type="external">Union Presbyterian Seminary</a> in Richmond, Va.</p> 
<p>?You have a long-simmering moral dispute that heats up an ecclesiastical and political question, which results in a division.</p> 
<p>?And the question is, when the division creates branches, how courts adjudicate those disputes.?</p> 
<p>But there are key differences between the disputes over slavery and homosexuality, some historians say.</p> 
<p>For instance, many conservatives say that it is not simply the gay issue that is driving them out the door, but a long liberal trend in mainline denominations that stretches back 30 years or more.</p> 
<p>Second, Scripture shows only a grudging tolerance of slavery, a far cry from its ringing endorsement of heterosexual unions, argues <a href="http://www.robgagnon.net/" type="external">Robert Gagnon</a>, an associate professor of New Testament at Pittsburgh Theological Seminary.</p> 
<p>?What kind of legitimate analogy can be made between the two? In my opinion, absolutely none. It?s just night and day,? he said.</p> 
<p>Moreover, what seem like similar clashes over biblical interpretation can mask the role of self-interest in the debates.</p> 
<p>Southern plantation owners ? and the pastors they built churches for ? had a huge financial stake in the slavery debate, said Charles Irons, an assistant professor of church history at North Carolina?s Elon University.</p> 
<p>Today, it is not easy to see where the financial?or political?advantage lies in supporting or opposing gay rights, he said.</p> 
<p>There?s one final ? and significant ? difference. Noll notes the theological crisis over slavery ultimately was decided politically by generals and armies.</p> 
<p>Almost everyone agrees the homosexuality debate more likely will be settled by judges and lawmakers.</p></article>
<article id="0000021" published-at="2012-01-06" title="Slideshow: Salvaging Burned Books in Egypt"><p>In December, clashes in Egypt between pro-democracy protesters and security forces shook downtown Cairo for nearly two weeks. The clashes reportedly began after a pro-democracy protester was beaten by the police.</p> 
<p>In the ensuing chaos, more than a dozen people died. But they weren't the only casualties.</p> 
<p>Egypt's Scientific Institute, formed in 1798 by Napoleon Bonaparte, was burned and thousands of rare books were destroyed.</p> 
<p>In the basement of the Egyptian National Library, a remarkable rescue effort is underway. Teams of researchers, book restorers and volunteers are attempting to save 193,000 rare manuscripts, books and scientific journals.</p> 
<p>The books are in a sad state. Burned by fire and then drenched when desperate firefighters tried to extinguish the flames.</p> 
<p>Magdi Montassir is vacuuming-packing the wet books. He gently places each book into a plastic bag, then puts the book into a machine that looks a little like a photocopier.</p> 
<p>He closes the lid, turns a dial and the bag fills up with air. Then, every bit of air is pushed out with a sharp whoosh.</p> 
<p>"The machine sealing the bag,"? Montassir says. "Empty oxygen, nitrogen, okay? Now, close the machine. Now the machine work. Look. And now it gives oxygen and becomes empty. No oxygen, no grow of bacteria or no fungi."?</p> 
<p>The vacuum-packed books are stacked haphazardly in a basement hallway. The sight of thousands of rare volumes cascading in piles in a dimly-lit hallway is shocking. But there's just no other place for them.</p> 
<p>Up on the roof of the Egyptian National Archives, even more books are drying out in the sun. They're lying on sheets of newspaper, held down by stones.</p> 
<p>The fastest and easiest way to dry them is simply take them up to the roof of the building and let the Egyptian sun beat down on them.</p> 
<p>Back downstairs, a young man in a white lab coat is slumped at a table aiming a neon blue hair dryer at a damp scientific journal.</p> 
<p>Behind him is the crown jewel of Egypt's collection: an original copy of the Description D'Egypt, a description of Egyptian customs, art, culture and history that dates back to Napoleon's 1798 campaign.</p> 
<p>The pages are burnt at the edges. Otherwise, the book is in decent shape.</p> 
<p>The books are from the Institut D'Egypt, or Egypt's Scientific Institute. The building was a national treasure that most Egyptians didn't even know existed. With no government funding and no digitization of the volumes, historians describe it as a sleepy library that attracted researchers with lots of time and patience on their hands.</p> 
<p>Whoever started the fire during the height of clashes between Egyptian protesters and security forces in December, probably didn't even know what he was destroying.</p> 
<p>"We are a cultured people,"? says Zain El Din Mohammed Abdel Hati, chairman of the Egyptian National Library.</p> 
<p>He's furious with the protesters who burned the Institute.</p> 
<p>"I think who did this is the enemy of the Egyptian culture. In this moment, we have a lot of enemies,"? he says.</p> 
<p>Abdel Hati has spent a good portion of the library's budget on the recovery effort. He is running out of money. And the rescuers are tired. Their nerves are frayed. Many of them are heartbroken about the loss.</p> 
<p>Researcher Mohammed Hassan kneels in a basement room where fans have been turned on full-blast to help dry the books. The fans are pointed up at the ceiling to avoid disturbing the ashes and loose pages -all that is left of many books.</p> 
<p>He is gently sifting burnt pages with a gloved hand.</p> 
<p>Hassan won't throw away anything though ? not even the charred scraps.</p> 
<p>Hassan: "Little, little, little paper. I keep it here,"? Hassan says.</p> 
<p>Ruxandra Guidi: "It's impossible to tell which books those scraps of paper come from."?</p> 
<p>Hassan: "Yes."?</p> 
<p>GR: "So, why save them?"?</p> 
<p>Hassan: "I need somebody who is specialist in these cases to tell me to throw it away. OK, I will throw. But until now, I must keep it safe."?</p> 
<p>Until the experts can decide which books can be saved and which can't, volunteers will continue working for hours at a stretch ? with hair dryers and shrink wrap machines ? trying to salvage history, one page at a time.</p></article>
<article id="0000025" published-at="2016-02-11" title="How schools in Brazil are teaching kids to eat their vegetables"><p>On a hilly slope in S?o Paulo City, a group of sixth graders is busy at work. They?re armed with seeds, soil and a range of gardening tools. Upside-down soda bottles, filled with water, outline a series of rectangular garden plots. A boy named Felipy Pigato tells me they are preparing the soil for planting.</p> 
<p>?Yesterday we mixed regular soil with coconut fiber,? he says. ?The coconut fiber holds the seeds in the soil.? &amp;#160;</p> 
<p>Today, he says they will add in the compost. As the students dig, they pull back chunks of dirt, creating shallow pits, where earthworms wriggle in the freshly dug soil.&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>Mateus Feitosa de Almeida, 12, slowly pulls back the soil around a worm. ?We have to pull like that so we don?t hurt the worms,? he explains. ?If we take them out, it?s bad for the soil.?</p> 
<p>This digging is going on in a quiet middle-class neighborhood, in a garden that belongs to Le?o Machado School, a large public school.</p> 
<p>The students are working under the guidance of two teachers, Daniel Giglio Colombo and Marta Martins.</p> 
<p>This is the second year of the project, says Colombo, who helped start the garden. ?We?re going to grow the same things we did last year ? arugula, lettuce, radishes.?</p> 
<p>The vegetables they grow are used in school meals. But the real aim of the school garden is not to supply ingredients, he says, but to teach students where food comes from, so they can develop a connection to their food.</p> 
<p>?When we ask students where lettuce comes from, they say the market,? Colombo says. ?They have lost contact with nature, the soil, sowing, and growing of crops.?</p> 
<p>And that is reflected in their diets, he says, which are increasingly unhealthy.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Students say the school garden project is teaching them a lot about how to grow food, though it's still hard for some of them to appreciate vegetables.</p> 
<p>Rhitu Chatterjee</p> 
<p>Just like in the US, highly processed foods like fast food, soda, and high-fructose corn syrup have become all too popular here in Brazil. And obesity rates are rising, even among children. It is a nation-wide problem that has alarmed the government and public health experts in the country.&amp;#160;Brazil?s government has banned sodas, cakes&amp;#160;and cookies in school meals. It has restricted the amount of salt and sugar in them as well. It also requires at least one daily serving of fruits and vegetables.</p> 
<p>Initially, students used to reject fresh food, says Martins. She and her colleagues hoped that the school garden would change that.</p> 
<p>?We wanted to create better habits with this project,? Martins says. ?We wanted them to improve their eating and become healthier.?</p> 
<p>That idea is behind flourishing school gardens across Brazil. The program started 12 years ago as a pilot program in five schools, as part of a project by the United Nations Food and Agricultural Program. Today, there are a few thousand school gardens in 700 cities and towns. Many are run independently by schools. Others are supported by city governments.&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>It?s hard to know yet whether school gardens have improved children?s health, says Albaneide Peixinho, who ran Brazil?s school meal program for 13 years. But she says schools are reporting that the gardens have made students more aware of their food.</p> 
<p>?With school gardens, they see that food comes from the Earth,? Peixinho says, and they are eating healthier. Some studies even show that the students are influencing how their families eat. ?Parents say that the kids are eating a lot of fruits and vegetables, and they insist on eating those foods at home.?</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Sarah Campos (left) and Juliana Santos, former students of&amp;#160;the Le?o Machado School. Campos says she tried her first radish after working in the school garden. Now she loves them.</p> 
<p>Rhitu Chatterjee</p> 
<p>Sarah Campos, 14, took the school garden class last year at Le?o Machado in S?o Paulo. ?I had never eaten radishes before,? she says. But she tried some when she and her classmates cooked radishes they had grown in the school garden.</p> 
<p>?I loved it so much that I even had a second plate,? Campos says. Now, she says she eats radishes often. ?I ask my mom to make them for lunch sometimes. She puts them in the salad with carrots, and with potatoes. It?s very good.?</p> 
<p>She and her classmates say they are more open to eating vegetables now. They try to avoid fast food and they?re more conscious of their diets.Out in the garden, I ask Mateus, the student who told me about protecting earthworms, what he has learned in his gardening class.</p> 
<p>?Many things,? he says. ?Like digging, what organic fertilizer is, what animals do to make the soil better.?</p> 
<p>?What did you learn about vegetables?? I ask.</p> 
<p>?That they are good for our health and well-being.? &amp;#160;</p> 
<p>?Do you eat vegetables??</p> 
<p>?I?m not so keen on them, but I guess I do now with this project,? he says, laughing sheepishly. &amp;#160;</p> 
<p>The hope is that by the end of the school year, he will really enjoy them.</p> 
<p>Related:&amp;#160; <a href="http://pulitzercenter.org/project/south-america-brazil-school-lunch" type="external">What does Brazil feed its school kids?</a></p> 
<p>This story was produced with support from the&amp;#160; <a href="http://pulitzercenter.org/people/rhitu-chatterjee" type="external">Pulitzer Center on Crisis Reporting</a>.</p></article>
<article id="0000027" published-at="2017-08-18" title="Massive venomous snake found under New Orleans home"><p>Aug. 18 (UPI) ? Wildlife removal experts discovered a large venomous rattlesnake underneath a home in Louisiana.</p> 
<p>Gulf Coast Wildlife Removal <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/GulfCoastWildlifeRemoval/posts/?ref=page_internal" type="external">shared photos</a> Wednesday of the nearly 6-foot long canebrake rattlesnake that was found living under a homeowner?s deck in New Orleans.</p> 
<p>?By far the biggest venomous snake we?ve encountered near the city,? the wildlife removal company said. ?Please keep a close eye out in these last few hot months of summer.?</p> 
<p>Ryan Cook of Gulf Coast Wildlife removal <a href="http://www.fox8live.com/story/36159317/monster-snake-captured-beneath-new-orleans-east-home" type="external">told WVUE</a> he marveled at the size of the snake, noting that ?anything over 5 feet with a rattlesnake is considered a monster.?</p> 
<p>?This one was 5 foot 8 inches and has 13 rattles on it, so it?s been around a good long time,? he said.</p> 
<p>Cook added that he?s received reports of rattlesnakes in the area near the site of an old Six Flags amusement park.</p> 
<p>?I?ve been hearing of a lot more rattlesnake activity in the New Orleans East area. I believe especially around the Six Flags area because it?s so overgrown. No one?s really doing anything to knock the numbers down, so you?re starting to see more and more of these guys showing up in residential neighborhoods,? he said.</p> 
<p>The wildlife removal expert encouraged residents to keep their yards and homes clear of debris and other clutter that rattlesnakes can use to form a shelter.</p></article>
<article id="0000028" title="Meet The Anti-Refugee ?Hate? Group That Just Landed In The US From Finland"><p>A European-based anti-refugee group is finding a new home in the United States, according to a report from the <a href="http://www.adl.org/assets/pdf/combating-hate/Soldiers-of-Odin-USA-Report-web.pdf" type="external">Anti-Defamation League</a>, and catching fire with neo-Nazis and anti-government extremists.</p> 
<p>The group?Soldiers of Odin?launched in Finland in 2015 and is named for a Norse god. Members of the group can often be seen in Finland patrolling the streets, wearing black jackets inscribed with a Viking and the Finnish flag and attempting to be vigilante ?eyes and ears for the police,? according to the ADL report.</p> 
<p>The group represents a backlash to the rising number of refugees being resettled throughout Europe. In Finland, the number of refugees quickly ballooned from just little more than 3,000 in 2014 to 32,000 in 2015. The group has already spread across Europe from France to the U.K.</p> 
<p>Now, the Soldiers of Odin are making moves in the U.S.</p> 
<p>According to the ADL?s report, rumblings from the Soldiers of Odin USA began in February of this year. Unlike Europe, which is facing a massive refugee crisis, the number of refugees coming into the U.S. is still relatively small. And so far, Soldiers of Odin USA has mostly a web presence. Still, ADL estimates that there are at least 4,000 individuals linked to the U.S. group.</p> 
<p>In March, the Soldiers of Odin chapter in Denver, Colorado held its first patrol. And the ADL reported that in Montana?where there is not even a refugee resettlement office?the backlash against refugees was so strong that ?more than 200 people tried to crowd into a [Flathead County] March 10 county commissioners meeting to express anti-refugee and anti-Muslim sentiments.? In March, a Soldiers of Odin group emerged to encourage individuals in the Flathead Valley to protest any Muslim refugee resettlement in the area.</p> 
<p>?Europe waited until AFTER she was flooded with refugees to protest in large numbers. We will not make the same mistake in Montana,? <a href="https://www.facebook.com/SoldiersOfOdinFlathead/?fref=nf" type="external">the group?s Facebook page read.</a>?We all know that many of the Muslim refugees are causing massive amounts of crime, in particular sexual assault and rape of women and children. Soldiers of Odin peacefully patrols the streets to protect citizens.?</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Since April, the group has 42 state chapters in the U.S. and it has spent much of its time on recruiting and normalizing rules of the official organization. ADL?s Mark Pitcavage said that the group seems to be trying to build an organizational structure it can expand into. Members have also spent time trying to gather the official Soldiers of Odin gear.</p> 
<p>?In their short existence so far, the Soldiers of Odin USA have spent most of their energy on recruiting, organization and trying to obtain Soldiers of Odin shirts and jackets?something in which it is clear members place great stock.?</p> 
<p>The group maintains it?s not racist. In fact the Soldiers of Odin USA has taken special care to protect their image. In its patrol in Colorado, the group actually met to deliver food to the homeless. And its official by-laws include repeatedly the words ?non-racist.? The group has even selected a special marketing and research director to make sure that the group?s propaganda materials reflect a certain image, Pitcavage said.</p> 
<p>However, its Finnish founder Mika Ranta is a known neo-Nazi, according to the ADL. And ADL points out that many of the members within the U.S. branch of the organization also have ties to white nationalism.</p> 
<p>?An examination of the members and supporters leaves no room for doubt: though not all such adherents of the group are white supremacists or bigots, so many of them clearly are that the Soldiers of Odin can easily be considered a hate group,? the ADL wrote in its report.</p> 
<p>ADL noted that William Johnson, a leader of the American Freedom Party who organized robocalls earlier this year in Iowa, Minnesota and New Hampshire on behalf of Donald Trump who <a href="" type="internal">he claimed could halt ?white genocide</a>? was aligned with the group as were ADL ? identified Alabama Klan leader Bradley Jenkins and Maryland skinhead Jason Tankersley.</p> 
<p>It?s also clear that anti-Muslim sentiment is strong within the group. The ADL?s report included a dozen of the most brazen statements against Muslims posted from the group.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Pitcavage told TPM that one of the more confounding aspects of the new Soldiers of Odin group in the U.S. is that the organization seems to bring together both white nationalist and anti-government factions. The various extremist groups have typically kept their distance from one another, but the anti-Muslim sentiment appears to have united the previously incongruent groups in recent years.</p> 
<p>Whether or not the various factions can successfully survive together, however, remains to be seen.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000031" published-at="2018-01-12" title="AP Top Stories January 11 P"><p>Here?s the latest for Thursday, January 11th: Bipartisan senators reach a deal on DACA; Walmart to up salaries for U.S. workers, also closing dozens of Sam?s Clubs; Crews search for mudslide victims; Mudslide reaches Oprah?s backyard. (Jan. 11)</p> 
<p>Here?s the latest for Thursday, January 11th: Bipartisan senators reach a deal on DACA; Walmart to up salaries for U.S. workers, also closing dozens of Sam?s Clubs; Crews search for mudslide victims; Mudslide reaches Oprah?s backyard. (Jan. 11)</p></article>
<article id="0000035" published-at="2015-10-05" title="VIDEO: U.S. Reaches Trans-Pacific Partnership Deal With 11 Other Countries"><p>Almost 10 years in the making, the largest regional trade accord in history was agreed to Monday by the United States and 11 other Pacific Rim nations. The controversial <a href="" type="internal">Trans-Pacific Partnership</a> (TPP) represents ?a potentially precedent-setting model for global commerce and worker standards that would tie together 40 percent of the world?s economy, from Canada and Chile to Japan and Australia,? according to The New York Times.</p> 
<p>In this NYT video, U.S. Trade Representative Michael Froman declares, ?We, the trade ministers ? are pleased to announce that we have successfully concluded the Trans-Pacific Partnership negotiation.?</p> 
<p>Froman says that what he calls the ?historic? TPP agreement will ?support jobs, drive sustainable growth, foster inclusive development and promote innovation across the Asia-Pacific region,? while also raising living standards.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p></p> 
<p></p> 
<p>The New York Times reports:</p> 
<p>The Trans-Pacific Partnership still faces months of debate in Congress and will inject a new flash point into both parties? presidential contests.</p> 
<p>But the accord ? a product of nearly eight years of negotiations, including five days of round-the-clock sessions here ? is a potentially legacy-making achievement for President Obama, and the capstone for his foreign policy ?pivot? toward closer relations with fast-growing eastern Asia, after years of American preoccupation with the Middle East and North Africa.</p> 
<p>The Pacific accord would phase out thousands of import tariffs as well as other barriers to international trade. It also would establish uniform rules on corporations? intellectual property, open the Internet even in communist Vietnam and crack down on wildlife trafficking and environmental abuses.</p> 
<p>Its full 30-chapter text will not be available for perhaps a month, but labor unions, environmentalists and liberal activists are poised to argue that the agreement favors big business over workers and environmental protection. Donald Trump has repeatedly castigated the Pacific trade accord as ?a bad deal,? injecting conservative populism into the debate and emboldening some congressional Republicans who fear for local interests like sugar and rice, and many conservatives who oppose Mr. Obama at every turn.</p> 
<p>Long before an accord was reached, it was being condemned by both Mr. Trump, the Republican presidential front-runner, and Senator Bernie Sanders of Vermont, who is challenging Hillary Rodham Clinton for the Democrats? nomination. Other candidates also have been critical. Mrs. Clinton, who as secretary of state promoted the trade talks, has expressed enough wariness as she has campaigned among unions and other audiences on the left that her support is now in doubt.</p> 
<p>Read the full article <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/06/business/trans-pacific-partnership-trade-deal-is-reached.html?_r=0" type="external">here</a>.</p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">Click here</a> to read Ralph Nader?s 10 reasons why the TPP is not a ?progressive? trade agreement.</p> 
<p>?Posted by <a href="" type="internal">Roisin Davis</a></p></article>
<article id="0000038" published-at="2017-03-04" title="Trump?s Desperate Attempt to Distract Americans From His Scandals Backfires ?Bigly?"><p>Donald Trump?s Saturday morning Twitter meltdown was flat-out unhinged, but his incompetence may have ultimately done nothing more than screw himself over.</p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">To his supporters</a>, Trump did nothing more than pander to the right-wing paranoia and irrational hatred of Barack Obama that helped him become a superstar among millions of conservatives. For most Americans, even many on the left, the true severity of this rant went unnoticed.</p> 
<p>You see, when someone in Trump?s position does something like this, as opposed to a private citizen or even presidential candidate, there are a whole mess of legal issues that become involved.</p> 
<p>For starters, a&amp;#160;president doesn?t have the power to single-handedly order a wiretap. Meaning that, if Trump or anyone associated with him were&amp;#160;monitored, a Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (FISA court)&amp;#160;would have had to grant&amp;#160;a warrant to do so. And the only way the FISA court would have done that is if they found probable cause.</p> 
<p>In case you didn?t know, the FISA court was authorized under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to oversee requests for surveillance of spies inside the United States by U.S. intelligence agencies. The Chief Judge&amp;#160;appointed to oversee the court is Rosemary Collyer, a United States District Court judge who was appointed by George W. Bush. She was then given her position on the FISA court by Chief Justice of the United States John Roberts ? who was also&amp;#160;picked by Bush and heavily supported by the Republican party.</p> 
<p>So, right off the bat Trump?s claim, if true, would indicate that the evidence surrounding <a href="" type="internal">these Russian allegations</a> was sound enough that the FISA court found probable cause to approve the surveillance.</p> 
<p>In other words, if we?re to take Trump at his word, it?s not&amp;#160;Obama&amp;#160;who ?bugged Trump Tower,? it was U.S. intelligence officials presenting evidence to the FISA court which then approved the monitoring of communication within that building over suspicion that Trump, or members of his campaign, engaged in possible <a href="" type="internal">treasonous contact with Russian officials</a>.</p> 
<p>Most people have concluded that Trump?s tantrum was triggered by a Breitbart article ? which was based off comments made by right-wing conspiracy theorist Mark Levin ? claiming there?s a ?police state? being secretly run by Obama to create some sort of ?coup.?</p> 
<p>Again, any wiretapping of Trump Tower would have been granted by the FISA court amid&amp;#160;overwhelming&amp;#160;evidence of Russian links to Trump or his associates. If Trump wants to continue to claim this is true, then he?s either accusing Barack Obama of a blatant crime that&amp;#160;should be investigated immediately, or he?s admitting that the FISA court found enough evidence of Russian ties to approve these supposed wiretaps.</p> 
<p>So it?s either one or the other. Either Trump is:</p> 
<p>Well, then there?s always the possibility&amp;#160;that, because <a href="" type="internal">he?s an unhinged moron</a>, he simply read this article in Breitbart, threw&amp;#160;another ridiculous hissy fit on Twitter, and he has absolutely no damn idea what he?s talking about. Hell, he compared this to Watergate, proving that he doesn?t even understand what the Nixon-era scandal was about.</p> 
<p>But the kicker to this is, Trump?s incompetence has opened the door for a public reveal of the details surrounding why, if true, the FISA court approved any requests to monitor anything related to him or his associates. After all, even if you&amp;#160;think Trump?s mentally unstable, he was clearly serious when he made these comments. Considering the office he currently occupies, his words should then immediately require an independent investigation ? which means subpoenas ? that would ultimately bring practically anything and everything related to this into public light.</p> 
<p>Because he has no idea what he?s doing, Trump has screwed himself over in several ways. If you take him at his word, and this is like ?Watergate,? then he?s going to have to order extensive independent investigations, along with Congress being involved, into what he claims was a blatant and extremely illegal order by a Barack Obama to have Trump Tower put under surveillance.</p> 
<p>However, if he doesn?t do that, then he?s essentially admitting this whole rant was nothing more than pure ignorance, based on his trusting of a fringe, right-wing conspiracy site, and <a href="" type="internal">he?s too incompetent</a> to hold the position he currently occupies.</p> 
<p>That or he?s aware of the FISA court granting these warrants, he thinks they were illegal and not justified, so he should order all the information contained within them to be made public to ?clear his name.? And if any FISA warrants related to investigations into him or his associates do exist, but he doesn?t want to make any of that information public, then he?s more or less admitting that they were credible and he doesn?t want people to know about the information that was used that led to their approval.</p> 
<p>The bottom line is, Donald Trump?s stupidity has basically led to one of four main possibilities:</p> 
<p>That&amp;#160;means the only positive outcome for Trump and Republicans is the extremely unlikely possibility that his accusations against Barack Obama are right. Otherwise, nothing good is going to&amp;#160;come of this for Trump or the Republican party.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>21 Facebook comments</p></article>
<article id="0000039" published-at="2017-05-24" title="2017's 3 Best Index Funds"><p></p> 
<p>2017 has been a tumultuous year, with plenty going on in the political and financial realms. Yet the stock market has done quite well, and index funds that track popular stock benchmarks have given their investors solid returns. In particular, among the most popular exchange-traded funds, iShares MSCI Emerging Markets (NYSEMKT: EEM), PowerShares QQQ (NASDAQ: QQQ), and iShares Core MSCI EAFE (NYSEMKT: IEFA) have delivered some of the best returns.</p> 
<p>Continue Reading Below</p> 
<p>Data source: Fund providers, ETFdb.com.</p> 
<p>Among U.S.-oriented index funds, the PowerShares QQQ leads the field with strong returns in the upper teens. The ETF tracks the <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2017/01/11/2016s-10-best-nasdaq-100-stocks.aspx?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">Nasdaq 100 Index Opens a New Window.</a>, which is composed of the 100 top nonfinancial companies that trade on the Nasdaq exchange. Although intermingling of stocks across the Nasdaq and New York Stock Exchanges over the past several years has made both indexes more diverse, the Nasdaq still has a preponderance of technology companies within its upper echelon. That makes the index particularly susceptible to tech-stock trends, and when technology is in the ascendancy -- as it has been so far in 2017 -- the Nasdaq does well.</p> 
<p>The PowerShares QQQ does a good job of tracking the Nasdaq, with a relatively low 0.2% expense ratio taking only a minimal portion of the overall return of the index. With ample liquidity from plenty of trading volume every day, the PowerShares QQQ is an efficient way for you to tap into the profit potential of the Nasdaq and amplify your domestic stock exposure.</p> 
<p>Advertisement</p> 
<p>Image source: Getty Images.</p> 
<p>What's noteworthy, though, is that international markets have, in general, outpaced returns in the U.S. That's true both in other developed markets, where the MSCI EAFE index governs, and in emerging markets.</p> 
<p>The two iShares funds represented here not only blanket the world between them, but also have different approaches toward their investing strategies and business models. The iShares Emerging Markets ETF tracks emerging-market stocks, and it's designed for use by institutional investors, with high trading volumes and ample liquidity. However, as you can see from the 0.69% expense ratio, the index fund is relatively costly compared to other ETFs.</p> 
<p>It's true that investing in emerging markets involves more expense than buying and selling stocks in the U.S. and in other better-developed markets, but even so, the iShares offering isn't the most cost-effective solution. That's why it's noteworthy that the ETF has outpaced some of its lower-cost peers.</p> 
<p>Meanwhile, the iShares Core MSCI EAFE ETF is an example of a lower-cost philosophy from iShares. <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2016/08/29/investors-think-these-are-best-international-etfs.aspx?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">The core series of ETFs Opens a New Window.</a> are designed for longer-term investors, with less liquidity, but lower expenses. Investors have the opportunity to pay just 0.08% in annual expenses using the Core MSCI EAFE fund, and that compares quite favorably to the 0.33% expense ratio that its non-core iShares counterpart charges.</p> 
<p>Overseas markets have done well so far in 2017. Improving economic conditions suggest that a long period of sluggishness might finally be coming to an end, and many investors have seen international stocks as being better bargains than the U.S. stock market, especially after eight years of bull-market conditions. That has pushed up international index funds across the board, but iShares stands out with superior performance compared to other large providers so far this year.</p> 
<p>2017 has been kind to these three ETFs, and the trends that have supported their returns will likely continue further into the year. By understanding why these funds have done so well, you can get some insight into choosing ETFs that are likely to be the best in the future.</p> 
<p>10 stocks we like better than PowerShares QQQ Trust Series 1When investing geniuses David and Tom Gardner have a stock tip, it can pay to listen. After all, the newsletter they have run for over a decade, Motley Fool Stock Advisor, has tripled the market.*</p> 
<p>David and Tom just revealed what they believe are the <a href="http://infotron.fool.com/infotrack/click?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Fmms%2Fmark%2Fe-foolcom-sa-bbn-static%3Faid%3D8867%26source%3Disaeditxt0010449%26ftm_cam%3Dsa-bbn-evergreen%26ftm_pit%3D6312%26ftm_veh%3Dbbn_article_pitch&amp;amp;impression=c97ad2b9-3f6f-4f4c-b202-9aa2958a9ecb&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">10 best stocks Opens a New Window.</a> for investors to buy right now... and PowerShares QQQ Trust Series 1 wasn't one of them! That's right -- they think these 10 stocks are even better buys.</p> 
<p><a href="http://infotron.fool.com/infotrack/click?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Fmms%2Fmark%2Fe-foolcom-sa-bbn-static%3Faid%3D8867%26source%3Disaeditxt0010449%26ftm_cam%3Dsa-bbn-evergreen%26ftm_pit%3D6312%26ftm_veh%3Dbbn_article_pitch&amp;amp;impression=c97ad2b9-3f6f-4f4c-b202-9aa2958a9ecb&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">Click here Opens a New Window.</a> to learn about these picks!</p> 
<p>*Stock Advisor returns as of May 1, 2017</p> 
<p><a href="http://my.fool.com/profile/TMFGalagan/info.aspx" type="external">Dan Caplinger Opens a New Window.</a> has no position in any stocks mentioned. The Motley Fool has the following options: short January 2018 $114 puts on PowerShares QQQ Trust Series 1 and long January 2018 $125 puts on PowerShares QQQ Trust Series 1. The Motley Fool has a <a href="http://www.fool.com/Legal/fool-disclosure-policy.aspx?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">disclosure policy Opens a New Window.</a>.</p></article>
<article id="0000040" published-at="2015-05-18" title="Death Sentence for Morsi: Egypt?s Junta Takes Another Step Toward Being North Korea"><p>&amp;amp;amp;lt;i&amp;amp;amp;gt;This post originally ran on &amp;amp;amp;lt;a href="http://www.juancole.com/2015/05/sentence-another-toward.html" title="Juan Cole?s Web page"&amp;amp;amp;gt;Juan Cole?s website&amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;gt;.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/i&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;That the only freely elected president Egypt has ever known has been sentenced to death is only to be expected from the current military junta, which made a coup in July, 2013, and declared the former ruling party, the Muslim Brotherhood, to be a terrorist organization indistinguishable from al-Qaeda. Probably even under enormous pressure, some 20 percent of Egyptians at least somewhat identify with the Muslim Brotherhood (just as about 20 percent of Americans say they are evangelical Christians). To attempt to ban the entire religious Right as mere terrorists is a monstrous proceeding, and will inevitably produce the very terrorism it says it is trying to prevent.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;As with so many recent Egyptian court rulings, the surprising thing is the judiciary?s willingness to go along with crackpot conspiracy theories.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;Some Muslim Brotherhood leaders, including Muhammad Morsi, were imprisoned by the regime of Hosni Mubarak late in his presidency. On January 28, 2011, three days after big demonstrations broke out against Mubarak, Morsi and the others managed to escape from prison in the chaos of a collapsing regime. Afer Mubarak?s overthrow in mid-February, 2011, they set up a headquarters in the Muqattam Hills above the city. Ultimately they won both parliament and the presidency. But the judiciary struck down their victory in the national legislature on the grounds that they had cheated by running party candidates in independent constituencies (this is true). Then the presidency was taken away from them when millions came into the streets against Morsi on June 30, 2013, and the military took advantage of the unrest to stage a coup.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;div class="sidebar__ad-label"&amp;amp;amp;gt;Advertisement&amp;amp;amp;lt;/div&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;broadstreet-zone zone-id="58577"&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/broadstreet-zone&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;The charges on which Morsi could be executed &amp;amp;amp;lt;a href="http://elaph.com/Web/News/2015/5/1008423.html"&amp;amp;amp;gt; include that he and the other Muslim Brotherhood leaders smuggled out the plans of their high security jail&amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;gt; to members of Hamas, the Gaza party-militia, and to the Iranian Revolutionary Guards Corps and to the Lebanese Shiite party-miitia, Hizbullah. These nefarious terrorist forces then broke Morsi et al. out of jail on Jan. 28. It is being alleged that sharing the prison plans with terrorists is a form of espionage. That Morsi and the others escaped their incarceration is not in question. That they were broken out by Hamas, Hizbullah and the Revolutionary Guards in concert is a looney tunes theory for which there is no evidence, and it is a very dark matter to take a man?s life over charges that would elicit a derisive guffaw from most sane people.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;The other charge is that beginning in 2005, the top Muslim Brotherhood leadership began conspiring with Hamas to throw the country into turmoil, a plan that eventuated in the January 25, 2011, revolution. That Mubarak was overthrown by the Muslim Brotherhood or more precisely by the Palestinian Hamas organization is an absurd proposition. The majority of the demonstrators in the capital and big northern cities were left-of-center youth, not the older religious Right. In fact, the Brotherhood leadership was clearly uncomfortable with the demonstrations, and many Brotherhood youth stayed home as a result, though I found one estimate that about a fourth of the demonstrators in Tahrir Square were Brotherhood. If you know anything about Egypt, you?ll recognize that that is a tiny proportion for the country?s largest opposition movement. Hamas didn?t overthrow Mubarak, and it is an insult to the hundreds of youth martyrs who gave their lives in 2011 to suggest that it did.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;Ordinarily the Egyptian Field Marshall/ President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi is careful to praise the Jan. 25 revolution. But now his sycophantic judge is essentially declaring it, as well, a terrorist conspiracy and making it one of the grounds to execute the elected former president.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;Here is &amp;amp;amp;lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/press-releases/2015/05/egypt-court-recommends-death-sentences-for-morsi-more-than-100-others/%20"&amp;amp;amp;gt; Amnesty international?s&amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;gt; response:&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;blockquote&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt; ?An Egyptian court?s recommendation today to sentence ousted president Mohamed Morsi and more than 100 other defendants to death after grossly unfair trials shows the deplorable state of the country?s criminal justice system, said Amnesty International.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;?Condemning Mohamed Morsi to death after more grossly unfair trials shows a complete disregard for human rights. His trials were undermined even before he set foot in the courtroom. The fact that he was held for months incommunicado without judicial oversight and that he didn?t have a lawyer to represent him during the investigations makes these trials nothing but a charade based on null and void procedures,? said Said Boumedouha, Deputy Director of Amnesty International?s Middle East and North Africa Programme.?&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;I should underline that I think Morsi could well have been properly impeached for some of his actions while president and I am hardly a supporter of his wing of the Muslim Brotherhood. The 20 years Morsi was earlier given for sending plainclothes Brotherhood thugs to break up youth demonstrations late in 2012, in the course of which 6 youth were killed, seem to me to have at least the pretense of rationality and basic facts in their favor, though that wasn?t a fair trial, either.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;But these charges and this sentence are not rational. They are like the rumors that North Korean dictator Kim Jung Un has fed his uncle to the dogs. Sisi and his fellow officers are beginning to act like Kim. They are unhinged. They even claim to have discovered a cure of AIDS in their military labs. (They haven?t).&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;Egypt under the jackboot of the brigadiers is fast becoming an international pariah. Even Sisi?s recent visit to Spain produced howls of outrage that he was allowed into Madrid.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;Egypt?s stock market lost $26 billion &amp;amp;amp;lt;a href="http://www.albawaba.com/business/egypt%E2%80%99s-market-loses-26b-one-week-egx30-drops-5-percent-695184%20"&amp;amp;amp;gt; in the past week.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;gt; Tourism is still way down. Arbitrarily executing people is not a procedure calculated to give the public, whether domestic or international, any confidence.&amp;amp;amp;lt;/p&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;p&amp;amp;amp;gt;</p></article>
<article id="0000041" published-at="2017-04-20" title="With tensions high, protests erupt across Venezuela"><p>New clashes erupted Thursday between Venezuelan riot police and President Nicolas Maduro's opponents, inflaming the tension after a day of deadly unrest in the beleaguered oil-rich nation.</p> 
<p>Police backed by armored trucks fired tear gas to break up a large march as it reached a vital freeway in Caracas, then edged back slightly as masked protesters pelted them with stones.</p> 
<p>Demonstrators vowed not to flinch in their campaign to oust Maduro, despite three weeks of protest violence that has left eight people dead, including three on Wednesday.</p> 
<p>"Sure we're tired, but we've got to stand strong. I'm ready to take to the streets every day if I have to," said 22-year-old student protester Aquiles Aldazoro.</p> 
<p>Senior opposition leader Henrique Capriles vowed there would be "no surrender."</p> 
<p>"It is our duty to defend the constitution," he said.</p> 
<p>Protesters blame Maduro ? the heir of the leftist "Bolivarian revolution" launched by the late Hugo Chavez in 1999 ? for an economic crisis marked by severe shortages of food, medicine and basic goods.</p> 
<p>Pressure on Maduro has been mounting since 2014, as falling prices for&amp;#160;Venezuela's crucial oil exports have sent the once-booming economy into a tailspin.</p> 
<p>The crisis has escalated since March 30, when&amp;#160;Venezuela's Supreme Court moved to seize the powers of the legislature, the only lever of state authority not controlled by Maduro and his allies.</p> 
<p>Hundreds of thousands of protesters took part in Wednesday's marches, which erupted into clashes with security forces and armed groups of government supporters.</p> 
<p>A 17-year-old boy and a 23-year-old woman died after they were shot in the head, and Maduro's camp said a soldier outside Caracas was also killed.</p> 
<p>The opposition accuses Maduro of letting state forces and gangs of armed thugs violently repress demonstrators.</p> 
<p>Interior Minister Nestor Reverol said one person had been arrested for the soldier's death, which he called a pre-meditated "act of fascism."</p> 
<p>Numerous businesses and universities remained closed ? some in tacit support of the protests, others for fear of a repeat of the previous day's violence.</p> 
<p>Looting erupted amid the chaos Wednesday. In the Paradise neighborhood in western Caracas, looters carted off food and beer from a series of ransacked businesses, residents said.</p> 
<p>In poor neighborhoods traditionally loyal to Maduro, some protesters have cited hunger as their reason for joining calls for his ouster.</p> 
<p>The escalation of&amp;#160;Venezuela's political crisis since late March has galvanized the often divided opposition in its efforts to force Maduro from power.</p> 
<p>The president, in turn, has urged his supporters, the military and civilian militias to defend the "revolution."</p> 
<p>International concern meanwhile continues to mount.</p> 
<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on Thursday urged all sides in&amp;#160;Venezuela&amp;#160;to take steps to ease tensions.</p> 
<p>"We call for concrete gestures from all parties to reduce polarization and create the necessary conditions to address the country?s challenges," he said in a statement.</p> 
<p>The European Union added to the condemnation, calling the deaths of protesters "highly regrettable" and urging all sides to "de-escalate."</p> 
<p>The opposition has called for the military ? a pillar of Maduro's power ? to abandon him.</p> 
<p>But the defense minister, General Vladimir Padrino Lopez, has pledged the army's "unconditional loyalty" to Maduro.</p> 
<p>The president accuses the opposition of inciting a "coup" backed by the United States.</p> 
<p>According to a survey by pollster Venebarometro, seven in 10 Venezuelans disapprove of Maduro, whose term does not end until 2019.</p> 
<p>The president said Wednesday that he is ready to face his opponents at the ballot box.</p> 
<p>"I want to have elections soon ... to seek a peaceful path so the revolution can put the conspirators, murderers and interventionist right-wingers in their place," he told a rally of supporters in central Caracas.</p> 
<p>Regional elections due in December were indefinitely postponed and there is still no date for local polls due this year. The next presidential election is due in December 2018.</p></article>
<article id="0000043" published-at="2017-08-24" title="Survey: Nearly 80 Percent of Americans Live Paycheck to Paycheck"><p>Nearly 80 percent of Americans are living paycheck to paycheck, according to a survey released Thursday by <a href="http://press.careerbuilder.com/2017-08-24-Living-Paycheck-to-Paycheck-is-a-Way-of-Life-for-Majority-of-U-S-Workers-According-to-New-CareerBuilder-Survey" type="external">CareerBuilder.</a></p> 
<p>The results:</p> 
<p>?Living paycheck to paycheck is the new way of life for U.S. workers,? CareerBuilder spokesman Mike Erwin told <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/americans-living-paycheck-to-paycheck/" type="external">CBS News</a>. ?It?s not just one salary range. It?s pretty much across the board, and it?s trending in the wrong direction. Jobs have come back, but we haven?t seen salaries rebound.?</p> 
<p>Further, 59 percent of Americans making $100,000&amp;#160;or more say they are in debt, and 70 percent of those making between $50,000&amp;#160;and $99,000&amp;#160;are in debt, according to the survey.</p> 
<p>?As an employer, your employees? financial problems become your financial problems,? said Rosemary Haefner, chief human resources officer for CareerBuilder. ?If workers are constantly thinking about their financial struggles, their quality of work can decrease, and it can take a hit on their morale and productivity.?</p> 
<p>The survey was conducted online within the U.S. by Harris Poll on behalf of CareerBuilder among 2,369 hiring and human resource managers ages 18 and over and 3,462 employees ages 18 and over between May 24 and June 16, 2017. There?s a 95 percent probability that the results have sampling errors of up to +/- 2 percentage points.</p></article>
<article id="0000046" published-at="2013-07-11" title="The truth about secession"><p>According to <a href="http://denver.cbslocal.com/2013/07/09/effort-to-create-new-state-called-north-colorado-grows/" type="external">CBS in Denver</a>, ?There?s a growing effort to create a 51st state out of parts of northeast Colorado.?</p> 
<p>Organizers of the secessionist effort in a dozen rural counties in what some hope will become the state of ?North Colorado? say their interest in breaking away stems from the fact that their ?interests are not being represented at the state Capitol.?</p> 
<p>We?re not talking here about a classic secession from the union, the kind Texas is always rumored to be on the verge of, but of the simple formation of a new state out of an existing one. West Virginia was created this way many moons ago, as were Maine, Kentucky, and Vermont.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Three other counties in Colorado and two in Kansas have also expressed interest in joining the secessionist movement. Leaders hope to have the measure voted on as early as November. Even if most voters decide that ?North Colorado? is a good idea, however, the bill will still have to gain approval from the Colorado General Assembly and the U.S. Congress.</p> 
<p>It may just be a temporary answer to the problem, anyway. Liberals have a way of invading the loveliest places in America and making them uninhabitable: e.g. Boulder, CO, Santa Fe, NM, and everywhere in California. What?s to stop liberals from moving in and undoing all the good secession might do? New Hampshire, where ?Live Free or Die? was once taken seriously, is looking more and more like Massachusetts every day. With massive immigration, even Texas is not immune from the trend.&amp;#160;Northern Colorado is a fast-growing area with lots of oil and gas that needs to be regulated.</p> 
<p>Anti-secessionists love smugly to call Texas secession a pipe-dream on the basis that it <a href="http://ideas.time.com/2012/11/19/can-texas-really-secede-from-the-union-not-legally/" type="external">?isn?t legal.?</a> If you?re seceding, though, the goal is to break from the rules imposed upon you by the institution, so why would you stop and ask for its permission first? ?Is it alright, parent, if I refuse to heed the rule you told me to obey?? And why are <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jeff-schweitzer/secession-movement_b_2191701.html" type="external">liberals against secession</a> in the first place? Do they enjoy tormenting conservatives so much that they?d rather live in disharmony with them than let us go our separate ways? As <a href="" type="internal">Pat Buchanan</a> put it, ??Can we all just get along?? Well, if we can?t, we can at least dwell apart.?</p> 
<p>Another thing. Do these North Coloradoans not consider the aesthetics of the American flag? Maybe Texas should secede for real and then we won?t have to worry about an odd number of stars.</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000053" published-at="2010-12-08" title="Calling From a Migrant Lockup in Arizona"><p>?We?re not criminals,? says the young man on the phone. ?I?m not here to use the system.?</p> 
<p>If he could address the US Congress when it votes on the long-lost DREAM Act, 21-year-old Hector Lopez would ask for freedom from a ?106-day nightmare? that started in late August when American immigration authorities ripped him out of his tax-paying, college-going, hard-working life and deported him to Mexico.</p> 
<p>He would happily save American taxpayers the money they are now spending on his room and board in a lockup built for migrants near Florence, Arizona.</p> 
<p>?What I?ve said the whole time is that people like us?the college dreamers?didn?t have any choice. We were brought to this country as children and now we?re your future doctors, lawyers, and neighbors. We?re the future of this country and they?re trying to kick us out. Here you have people who are willing to fight for this country and all we?re asking is permission to call this country our home for the rest of our lives.</p> 
<p>?Congress could enable so many productive people by passing the DREAM Act,? says Lopez. ?And they would be foolish not to.? With all the things that Lopez has to worry about on Tuesday night, the main thing that keeps his mind busy is how to manage the expectations of what Congress will do with the DREAM Act on Wednesday. ?The DREAM Act is finally being voted on,? he says. ?I?m trying not to think about it, but it?s making me a nervous wreck.?</p> 
<p>Hope is a serious thing to contend with when you?re locked up in Arizona thinking about holiday food. If Congress passes the DREAM Act, Lopez has been advised by attorneys that he would be made a free man. The DREAM Act would make it legal for young folks like him to return to college, get back to work, and make a future in the hometowns of America.</p> 
<p>?We could ask for my immediate release,? he says, letting his hope build up momentarily. ?So I?m hoping for the best. But on the other hand, I?m trying to stay pessimistic, too.? After all, it?s the US Congress we?re talking about here. They have had good days in history. Maybe even enough good days to make up for the bad.</p> 
<p>Whichever way the DREAM Act goes this week, Lopez has backup plans. It?s been three weeks since he crossed the border from Mexico with papers in hand requesting a hearing for ?credible fear.? The hearing is usually done in two parts, says immigrant advocate Ralph Isenberg. Lopez is still waiting for part one.</p> 
<p>?If people have to wait a long time for the hearing process to begin, that?s a problem in itself,? argues Isenberg from the office of his real estate business in Dallas. ?ICE (Immigration and Customs Enforcement) has the discretion to release Hector to his home immediately.? Alongside the effort to free Lopez, Isenberg is also working for the return of another college dreamer, Saad Nabeel, who was deported from Texas in 2009 during the first semester of his freshman year.</p> 
<p>If Congress and ICE continue to harass Hector, Saad, and the millions of college dreamers that they typify, then Isenberg will sponsor a civil rights delegation to visit Hector on Friday.</p> 
<p>Rev. Peter Johnson was born into a civil rights family in Plaquemine, Louisiana. He was at the Freedom Rock Baptist Church the night state troopers rode their horses right up to the pulpit. That was the night James Farmer had to be smuggled out of town alive in a coffin.</p> 
<p>?I want to tell Hector that he is not alone,? says Rev. Johnson over speaker phone. ?There are people all over the world who believe in dignity for all human beings and who have a problem with America when it sets out to destroy families.</p> 
<p>?There is a long history of America destroying families,? says Johnson. ?Under slavery, they would send the father to Georgia, the mother to Alabama, and the children to Virginia. Today America is literally destroying families. I know of cases where a mother puts her kids in school for the day. The mother is picked up by immigration and sent to Haskell (Texas) prison. And when the children get out of school their mother is gone. They are literally destroying families.?</p> 
<p>Johnson plans to take books by Gandhi and King as gifts for Lopez. He has a Gandhi book on nonviolence and a favorite by King, Where Do We Go from Here: Chaos or Community?&amp;#160; Destroying families is chaos, not community. Where will we go from here?</p> 
<p>?Look here,? says Isenberg jumping into the conversation. ?I?m reading the inscription in Rev. Johnson?s copy of Where Do We Go from Here? It says: ?Peter, Read this book. There will be a test. In fact, now that I think about it, life will be a test for you, (signed) Martin.??</p> 
<p>?That?s right,? says Rev. Johnson, ?and when Dr. King gave you a book to read you made sure you read it because you knew he was going to question you about it.&amp;#160; Where Do We Go from Here was a book written in preparation for the Poor People?s Campaign (of 1968).&amp;#160; The Poor People?s campaign was going to unite Black and White and Hispanic people so they could confront the trap of poverty and unemployment.?&amp;#160; It was a handbook for a movement to come.</p> 
<p>?King specifically talked about people South of the border. He said it was America?s moral obligation to help them find a better life.? The timing of Friday?s visit to Florence, Arizona will have three dimensions of significance for Rev. Johnson. It?s nearly a month away from the annual celebration of King?s birthday. The holiday season is coming, which is ?a season of forgiveness and atonement.? And finally, Dec. 10 will be the 62nd Anniversary for the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p> 
<p>?Fundamentally, the case of Hector Lopez is a question of human rights,? says Rev. Johnson. ?America is punishing a man who was brought here only weeks after he was born. In our treatment of Hector Lopez, we need to remember the human rights values of dignity and respect for all.?</p> 
<p>GREG MOSES is editor of <a href="http://www.TexasWorker.org" type="external">TexasWorker.org</a>.&amp;#160; He can be reached at <a href="mailto:gmosesx@gmail.com" type="external">gmosesx@gmail.com</a>.</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000054" published-at="2016-01-29" title="Where is Apple?s ?Next Big Thing??"><p></p> 
<p>Bad news for Apple (NASDAQ:AAPL): The company needs to launch the ?next big thing? in order to reverse investors? soured sentiment according to Barclays Capital analyst Ben Reitzes, and that next big thing could be Apple?s HDTV.</p> 
<p>Continue Reading Below</p> 
<p>Why is that bad news? Because according to a recent report from The Wall Street Journal, the company?s TV set won?t be launching any time soon ? if it even launches at all.</p> 
<p><a href="http://bgr.com/2012/12/12/apple-tv-next-big-thing/" type="external">See more tech stories on the FOX Business Technology homepage. Opens a New Window.</a></p> 
<p>In a research note sent to clients on Tuesday evening, Reitzes ponders what might snap investors out of their ?recent funk.? Shares of Apple stock plummeted by as much as 25% in November from a high of $705.07, which was hit just before the iPhone 5 launched this past September. While some say ?people overbelieved in Apple? and the end is nigh, Reitzes thinks Apple just needs to launch the ?next big thing? to remind investors why it is the most successful consumer electronics company in the world.</p> 
<p>Reitzes goes on to say that an Apple HDTV might be just what the doctor ordered and that a set-top box and service combination could do the trick as well. He sees Apple unveiling its big plans for the living room some time in 2013, and he says he believes Apple is ?exploring a new service that integrates iOS, iCloud, iTunes and more content that would bring customers a new experience around a TV-like device.?</p> 
<p>The analyst continued, ?We believe that the Apple version of TV may evolve into a product that is ?always on? with the ability to display a variety of messages (texts, Facebook postings, Tweets, email, etc.), weather, pictures, news and other key information as well as even act as a video conferencing device [...] any Apple solution seems like it will need to work along side traditional cable and media arrangements. However, we see opportunity in Apple being able to perhaps work out deals with providers to gain access to channel guides and other key information in order to provide a more elegant integration experience.?</p> 
<p>MORE FROM BGR:</p> 
<p>Advertisement</p></article>
<article id="0000056" published-at="2016-02-27" title="Supporters of Both Hillary Clinton and Bernie Sanders Need to Acknowledge This Crucial Fact"><p>Currently there is a bit of a ?civil war? going on among progressives between Hillary Clinton and Bernie Sanders supporters. During a primary season, that?s to be expected. Undoubtedly, it?s at this point during an election year when voters are most emotionally tied to a particular candidate. Primary elections often resemble sporting events more than political contests.</p> 
<p>But what?s alarmed me most about this particular primary season&amp;#160;is the number of people threatening to ?sit out? or ?write-in? a candidate if their particular candidate doesn?t happen to win the nomination. A belief that I think is one of the <a href="" type="internal">most asinine stances I?ve ever heard</a>. If you think either Donald Trump, Ted Cruz or Marco Rubio would be better (or just as bad) as voting for either Hillary Clinton or Bernie Sanders, you are out of your damn mind.</p> 
<p>I don?t care what your thoughts are of either Clinton or Sanders, on their worst day, either candidate is a million times better than anyone from the Republican party. And with the rights for millions of Americans at risk, as well as the Supreme Court and our progress on climate change, <a href="" type="internal">there?s too much at stake this election</a> to have any group of people not support the eventual Democratic nominee.</p> 
<p>And while I have encountered a few Clinton supporters who?ve vowed not to support Sanders if he becomes the nominee (I?ve even been blocked by a few of them for calling them idiots), the ?my candidate or no one? crowd <a href="" type="internal">is mostly found among Sanders supporters</a>. Though I will gladly admit that the majority of those supporting Sanders do&amp;#160;understand the bigger picture and have said they plan to support whichever candidate ultimately wins the nomination.</p> 
<p>To those people, I can?t thank them enough. In fact, I can?t thank anyone enough for realizing what?s on the line this election and why it?s so crucial that we all get out and ?vote blue, no matter who.? I don?t even want to think about how much damage Republicans will be able to do to this nation if we hand them the White House this November. <a href="" type="internal">It will make George W. Bush?s eight years</a> seem like a wonderful dream compared to the nightmare that a President Trump/Rubio/Cruz would inflict upon the country.</p> 
<p>But there?s an irony to anyone who says that they?re going to take their ball and go home if their candidate doesn?t win, and it?s this:&amp;#160;Neither candidate can win without help from the supporters of their primary rival.</p> 
<p>If Hillary Clinton wins the nomination, then half of all Sanders supporters decide not to support her, she likely&amp;#160;loses and we?re stuck with a President Trump/Rubio/Cruz.</p> 
<p>But guess what?</p> 
<p>If Bernie Sanders wins the nomination, then half of all Clinton supporters decide not to support him, he?s likely&amp;#160;going to lose and we?re going to be stuck with a President Trump/Rubio/Cruz.</p> 
<p>The truth of the matter is, whether each side wants to admit it or not, they both need each other this&amp;#160;November. Because come election day, if one group decides to let selfish ego and pride get in the way by not supporting the Democratic nominee, guess what?</p> 
<p>We all lose.&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>So, no matter what Clinton or Sanders supporters might think of one another, the reality is, they?re in this together ? whether they like it or not.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">I Asked Liberals to Unite to Protect the Rights of Millions, Here are Some of the Responses</a></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">Ultra Pro-Bernie Backer Robert Reich Feels the Wrath of Sanders Supporters for Preaching Unity</a></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">For the Last Time: Here's Proof the Democratic Primary Wasn't Rigged Against Bernie Sanders</a></p> 
<p>0 Facebook comments</p></article>
<article id="0000058" published-at="2014-06-11" title="California Bill Demands ?Verbal or Written Consent? for Sex on College Campuses"><p>Don?t get me wrong, rape?on college campuses or anywhere else?is a very serious crime that should be punished severely. But when <a href="http://www.breitbart.com/Breitbart-California/2014/06/04/College-Students-May-Need-Verbal-or-Written-Consent-to-Have-Sex-on-Campus" type="external">lawmakers start demanding that college students obtain ?written or verbal consent?</a> before having sex, it?s a sign we?ve become a tad hysterical on this issue.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal"></a> <a href="" type="internal"></a> <a href="http://www.laweekly.com/informer/2014/06/04/verbal-or-written-permission-could-be-required-for-college-sex" type="external">From LA Weekly:</a></p> 
<p>Sounds quite unspontaneous. But a law co-authored by L.A. state Sen. Kevin de Leon would have state-run college campuses establish an ?affirmative consent? standard for its students.</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>According to the language of the bill, SB 967, students who want to have sex must essentially establish that there has been ?an affirmative, unambiguous, and conscious decision by each participant to engage in mutually agreed-upon sexual activity.??No more making sexy faces and sounds for you. You?ve got to verbalize. Or get it on paper.</p> 
<p>Why not just require a notarized letter from an attorney, or better yet, a license? If we?re going to go this far, maybe college kids who want to have sex should go to a DMV-like office to get permission.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>All joking aside, the fact that this is even an issue suggests that a lot of college kids are having sex they?re not comfortable with having. People don?t sign a waiver when they?re engaging in any activity with someone they know and trust. (My advice to college kids: if you feel like you need to have a written contract drawn up with your ?partner,? you shouldn?t be having sex with them.)&amp;#160; <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/05/01/college-sexual-assault_n_5247267.html" type="external">Some of the colleges under investigation right now for mishandling sexual assault cases</a> are the most liberal, anything-goes, sexually open institutions in America. They host extravagant ?Sex Week? events and pass out condoms to freshmen. They talk a lot about ?consent,? but very little about respect, caring, or good judgment. Plying a ?yes? out of someone is all that matters.</p> 
<p>In an environment like this, the boundaries of consent begin to break down. Students?who face enormous peer pressure to participate in this free-for-all?have trouble saying ?no? when they want to. Other students simply don?t respect a ?no.? Add a huge amount of alcohol into the mix, and chaos ensues.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>This is the problem that college administrators and lawmakers are trying to fix. But until they have the guts to criticize the culture on college campuses, they?ll get nowhere.</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000059" published-at="2018-07-14" title="Unemployed Workers Need Benefits, but Republicans Still Say ?No.?"><p>On Sunday, Kentucky Senator Rand Paul explained his opposition to $26 billion in extended unemployment benefits for more than 1.3 million workers. ?I do support unemployment benefits for the 26 weeks that they?re paid for. If you extend it beyond that, you do a disservice to these workers,? he said in an <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/12/08/rand-paul-unemployment-benefits_n_4408046.html" type="external">interview</a> on Fox News Sunday. ?When you allow people to be on unemployment insurance for 99 weeks, you?re causing them to become part of this perpetual unemployed group in our economy,? he continued.</p> 
<p>But this is wrong. The long-term unemployed are <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2013/12/rand-paul-couldnt-be-more-wrong-about-unemployment-insurance/282144/" type="external">victims of timing</a>; they lost their jobs at the start of the Great Recession, and were already long out-of-work by the following year, when the labor market began to improve in earnest. Additional stimulus would have helped?by filling the demand shortfall and strengthening the labor market?but Republican opposition left it off of the table. In other words, our inadequate response to the recession yielded a sluggish economy that can?t accommodate the millions of workers who lost their jobs in the initial crash and its aftermath.</p> 
<p>Worse, employers <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/economy/2013/08/26/2524361/fault-long-term-unemployed-jobs/" type="external">all but punish people</a> for their absence from the workforce. In the eyes of a potential employer, being out of work for longer than nine months is equal to losing years of experience. Long-term joblessness?for the most part?is a recipe for permanent exclusion from the workforce, regardless of circumstances.</p> 
<p>As for unemployment benefits? Rand Paul has it backwards. If generous benefits yield higher joblessness, it?s because people are more <a href="http://d.pr/f/55tK" type="external">willing to stay in the labor market</a> when they can afford food and shelter. Far from discouraging work, extending unemployment insurance would encourage people to look for jobs longer than they would have otherwise.</p> 
<p>Unfortunately, while Paul is wrong on the effects of unemployment benefits, he might get his way on the policy. Yes, Democrats and Republicans?led by Senator Patty Murray and Rep. Paul Ryan, respectively?are negotiating a budget agreement, and yes, Democrats want to extend unemployment insurance for the next year. But conservative Republicans <a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/12/10/the_fools_are_at_it_again_conservatives_inane_new_budget_strategy/" type="external">refuse to budge</a> from the current spending levels, and right-wing groups like Heritage Action and FreedomWorks have already announced their opposition to a deal that raises spending. ?It?s disingenuous for Republicans to surrender the only real spending reforms accomplished under the Obama Administration, and call that a deal," FreedomWorks President Matt Kibbe said in a <a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/freedomworks-key-votes-against-emerging-ryan-murray-budget-deal" type="external">statement</a>. And <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2013/12/09/morning-plum-sequester-will-be-lifted-but-unemployed-likely-to-be-left-behind/" type="external">according</a> to Greg Sargent at the Washington Post, senior Democrats are willing to support a deal that doesn?t include an extension of benefits:</p> 
<p>?Of course we?d want to have the extension in the budget deal,? the aide says. ?But we?re dealing with Paul Ryan here. We?ve negotiated with Ryan to increase spending for the next two years in exchange for savings over the next 10 years. Replacing as much of sequestration as possible will be far better for families and the economy than the alternative, another CR at sequester levels ? and we can?t let the perfect be the enemy of the good.?</p> 
<p>It?s possible that Democrats could get an extension through Congress without tying it to a broader deal, but I wouldn?t hold my breath. Not only would the Senate have to break a likely Republican filibuster, but John Boehner would have to buck his conservative members and risk his standing. Either Congress extends unemployment insurance as part of the Murray-Ryan deal, or it doesn?t at all. And if it doesn?t, the economic costs are high: <a href="http://www.cbo.gov/publication/44929" type="external">According</a> to the Congressional Budget Office, we give up 200,000 jobs and a boost to GDP by rejecting an extension.</p> 
<p>It?s fair to want a smaller federal budget, even if the difference is marginal. In this case, however, it?s not worth the price in economic growth. But if Republicans couldn?t see this in 2011 or 2012?when they demanded even larger spending cuts?I doubt they?ll see it now.</p></article>
<article id="0000060" published-at="2018-01-06" title="Dem?cratas en los estados preparan respuestas a ley fiscal"><p>CHERRY HILL, Nueva Jersey, EE.UU. (AP) ? En Nueva Jersey y California, altos funcionarios dem?cratas quieren permitir que la gente haga donaciones de bien p?blico al estado en lugar de pagar ciertos impuestos. En Connecticut y Nueva York, funcionarios est?n explorando un cambio de impuestos sobre la renta a impuestos sobre la n?mina. Unos pocos gobernadores han propuesto incluso por recortes de impuestos.</p> 
<p>Las ideas abundan en momentos en que los legisladores estatales comienzan sus sesiones del 2018 y eval?an los defectos de la reforma republicana de impuestos que el presidente Donald Trump firm? el mes pasado. Legisladores y gobernadores en algunos estados est?n tratando de ver c?mo protegen a sus constituyentes.</p> 
<p>La pol?tica federal implementa un laberinto de cambios. Recorta las tasas de impuestos y aumenta a casi el doble la deducci?n est?ndar. Pero tambi?n pone l?mites en ciertas deducciones populares y fija las exenciones personales en cero.</p> 
<p>Para muchos estadounidenses, el resultado deber? ser obligaciones tributarias m?s bajas, al menos inicialmente. Se espera que quienes enfrenten cuentas mayores estar?n concentrados en algunos estados con impuestos altos.</p> 
<p>Con los legisladores comenzando sus sesiones y los gobernadores redactando presupuestos estatales, la respuesta es una prioridad pol?tica. Las propuestas son atrevidas, aunque no detalladas.</p> 
<p>Esta semana, el gobernador de Nueva York, Andrew Cuomo, us? su informe al estado para prometer una demanda contra el plan fiscal republicano que calific? de ?asalto? por el gobierno federal. Una demanda a?adir?a los impuestos a la creciente lista de pol?ticas de Trump que estados dem?cratas han demandado en las cortes.</p> 
<p>Otros estados no se han comprometido a demandar, pero algunos l?deres han indicado que explorar?n la idea.</p> 
<p>?Ciertamente no soy un abogado constitucional, pero la noci?n de que esto (la reforma) no es constitucional es algo que queremos explorar?, dijo Phil Murphy, el gobernador electo dem?crata de Nueva Jersey.</p> 
<p>Funcionarios en California y Connecticut dijeron tambi?n esta semana que estaban ponderando opciones legales.</p> 
<p>En estados de impuestos altos, los funcionarios se est?n concentrando en proteger a los contribuyentes del impacto de un nuevo l?mite de 10.000 d?lares a las deducciones por pagar impuestos estatales y locales. En California, Connecticut, Massachusetts, Nueva Jersey y Nueva York, m?s de una tercera parte de los contribuyentes se acogen a la deducci?n en los impuestos federales. La deducci?n promedio en cada estado es de m?s de 15.000 d?lares.</p> 
<p>E presidente pro tempore del senado de California, Kevin de Leon, un dem?crata que se presentar? a las elecciones para el senado del pa?s, introdujo una propuesta de ley esta semana que permitir?a a las personas hacer donaciones caritativas al estado en lugar de pagar impuestos sobre la renta. Eso les permitir?a pedir la deducci?n caritativa en los impuestos federales.</p> 
<p>En Nueva Jersey, el gobernador electo Murphy anunci? un plan similar el viernes, pero dijo que los gobiernos locales pudieran implementarlo tambi?n y aplicarlo a los impuestos sobre la propiedad.</p> 
<p>CHERRY HILL, Nueva Jersey, EE.UU. (AP) ? En Nueva Jersey y California, altos funcionarios dem?cratas quieren permitir que la gente haga donaciones de bien p?blico al estado en lugar de pagar ciertos impuestos. En Connecticut y Nueva York, funcionarios est?n explorando un cambio de impuestos sobre la renta a impuestos sobre la n?mina. Unos pocos gobernadores han propuesto incluso por recortes de impuestos.</p> 
<p>Las ideas abundan en momentos en que los legisladores estatales comienzan sus sesiones del 2018 y eval?an los defectos de la reforma republicana de impuestos que el presidente Donald Trump firm? el mes pasado. Legisladores y gobernadores en algunos estados est?n tratando de ver c?mo protegen a sus constituyentes.</p> 
<p>La pol?tica federal implementa un laberinto de cambios. Recorta las tasas de impuestos y aumenta a casi el doble la deducci?n est?ndar. Pero tambi?n pone l?mites en ciertas deducciones populares y fija las exenciones personales en cero.</p> 
<p>Para muchos estadounidenses, el resultado deber? ser obligaciones tributarias m?s bajas, al menos inicialmente. Se espera que quienes enfrenten cuentas mayores estar?n concentrados en algunos estados con impuestos altos.</p> 
<p>Con los legisladores comenzando sus sesiones y los gobernadores redactando presupuestos estatales, la respuesta es una prioridad pol?tica. Las propuestas son atrevidas, aunque no detalladas.</p> 
<p>Esta semana, el gobernador de Nueva York, Andrew Cuomo, us? su informe al estado para prometer una demanda contra el plan fiscal republicano que calific? de ?asalto? por el gobierno federal. Una demanda a?adir?a los impuestos a la creciente lista de pol?ticas de Trump que estados dem?cratas han demandado en las cortes.</p> 
<p>Otros estados no se han comprometido a demandar, pero algunos l?deres han indicado que explorar?n la idea.</p> 
<p>?Ciertamente no soy un abogado constitucional, pero la noci?n de que esto (la reforma) no es constitucional es algo que queremos explorar?, dijo Phil Murphy, el gobernador electo dem?crata de Nueva Jersey.</p> 
<p>Funcionarios en California y Connecticut dijeron tambi?n esta semana que estaban ponderando opciones legales.</p> 
<p>En estados de impuestos altos, los funcionarios se est?n concentrando en proteger a los contribuyentes del impacto de un nuevo l?mite de 10.000 d?lares a las deducciones por pagar impuestos estatales y locales. En California, Connecticut, Massachusetts, Nueva Jersey y Nueva York, m?s de una tercera parte de los contribuyentes se acogen a la deducci?n en los impuestos federales. La deducci?n promedio en cada estado es de m?s de 15.000 d?lares.</p> 
<p>E presidente pro tempore del senado de California, Kevin de Leon, un dem?crata que se presentar? a las elecciones para el senado del pa?s, introdujo una propuesta de ley esta semana que permitir?a a las personas hacer donaciones caritativas al estado en lugar de pagar impuestos sobre la renta. Eso les permitir?a pedir la deducci?n caritativa en los impuestos federales.</p> 
<p>En Nueva Jersey, el gobernador electo Murphy anunci? un plan similar el viernes, pero dijo que los gobiernos locales pudieran implementarlo tambi?n y aplicarlo a los impuestos sobre la propiedad.</p></article>
<article id="0000062" published-at="2017-12-08" title="British Independent Film Awards Shine a Spotlight on Newcomers"><p>Among the front-runners in the race for the British Independent Film Awards are three films by first-time directors: <a href="http://variety.com/t/william-oldroyd/" type="external">William Oldroyd</a>?s ?Lady Macbeth,? <a href="http://variety.com/t/rungano-nyoni/" type="external">Rungano Nyoni</a>?s ?I Am Not a Witch,? and <a href="http://variety.com/t/francis-lee/" type="external">Francis Lee</a>?s ?God?s Own Country.? This reflects the depth of new directing talent in Britain, and its diversity, with each helmer arriving at this point by different routes.</p> 
<p>Oldroyd had served as a stage director for more than a decade, tackling contemporary adaptations of European classics, and had also directed two short films. ?Lady Macbeth? was also the debut feature for screenwriter Alice Birch, a rising British playwright, and producer Fodhla Cronin O?Reilly.</p> 
<p>Producing a period film on a budget of ?500,000 ($667,000) was a challenge, Oldroyd says, and the decision to limit themselves to one location, Lambton Castle in Northern England, helped them stay within that.</p> 
<p>Oldroyd sought two conditions in particular. ?Coming from theater I was very aware that there were certain things I wanted to carry across to give stability and certainty: one was rehearsal time [he had 10 days of rehearsals with the key cast at the location] and the other was to shoot in chronological order.?</p> 
<p>He sought out the assistance of a storyboard artist in order to focus on shot selection. ?What I had to learn was where to put the camera, because I?m so used to watching a scene play out from one point of view on stage,? he says.</p> 
<p>Oldroyd surrounded himself with experienced behind-the-camera talent, such as first assistant director George Every, who has 20 years? film experience, including time on Merchant Ivory movies. ?That was fantastic [to have] somebody who absolutely could tell me how a film would work, how it can be structured, and how we could shoot it in the time we had,? Oldroyd says.</p> 
<p>Nyoni had shot a series of shorts, including the BAFTA-nominated ?Mwansa the Great,? before developing her Zambia-set script for ?I Am Not a Witch? through Cannes? Cinefondation residency. As part of her preparation for her feature, which was produced by Juliette Grandmont and feature debutante Emily Morgan, she read a lot of accounts of other directors? first-time experiences, including Paul Thomas Anderson on ?Hard Eight.?</p> 
<p>?It sounded really harrowing,? she says. She also spoke to other directors about their debuts and found that ?everyone had a hard time.?</p> 
<p>She sought to avoid common errors, such as running out of shooting time. When pre-production proved difficult, she sat down with cinematographer David Gallego and cut about 20 pages from the script to ?make our lives a little bit easier.? Their relationship was key. ?Thank god he was on the same page as me because if you get a cinematographer who?s more experienced than you and better known, if they decide to be the boss of your production you are screwed as a director,? she says.</p> 
<p>Like Nyoni, Lee is self-taught as a writer-director, although he has many years? experience as an actor. He wrote the script for ?God?s Own Country? on spec, without having a producer attached. ?The whole experience was a huge learning curve. Making your first film is a big battle,? he says. ?The biggest influence on me was the idea of trusting your instinct, and being very clear about the kind of film you wanted to make.?</p> 
<p>When choosing his film?s heads of department he was guided by the kinds of films they?d worked on before, such as with cinematographer Joshua James Richards, whose credits included ?Songs My Brothers Taught Me.? ?I absolutely fell in love with the way he depicted landscape and characters, and that felt very akin to how I saw [my film],? Lee says.</p> 
<p>His primary concern was the actors, and those who would be closest to them on set. ?I wanted to shoot this film very intimately with the actors, and there were going to be some difficult things for them to do,? he says. ?It was super-important that [the DP and boom operator] could be supportive, sympathetic and build a bond with the actors.?</p> 
<p>His own experience as an actor informed his approach on the film, which is about the love between an English sheep farmer and a Romanian farm worker. ?Having stood in front of the camera and knowing how vulnerable you feel, and how difficult it can be to deliver an emotional truth, it was my mission to make the actors feel secure, and that my focus would always be on them,? he says.</p></article>
<article id="0000063" published-at="2012-10-15" title="Gays Are ?Doing To Christians? What ?Nazis Used To Do To Jews? Says LaBarbera"><p><a href="" type="internal">Peter LaBarbera</a> is claiming that gays, or, as he calls them, ?homosexual activists,? are are ?doing to Christians? what the ?Nazis used to do to the Jews.? LaBarbera, head of the <a href="http://www.splcenter.org/get-informed/intelligence-files/ideology/anti-gay/active_hate_groups" type="external">certified anti-gay hate group</a>, <a href="" type="internal">Americans For Truth About Homosexuality</a>(AFTAH), was speaking with <a href="" type="internal">Judith Reisman</a>, of Jerry Falwell?s&amp;#160; <a href="" type="internal">Liberty University</a>. <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/labarbera-homosexual-activists-doing-to-christians-what-nazis-used-used-to-do-to-jews" type="external">Right Wing Watch</a>, which has the audio of this conversation, calls Reisman ?Liberty University?s&amp;#160; <a href="http://www.alternet.org/story/20744/her_kinsey_obsession" type="external">resident junk scientist</a>.?</p> 
<p>?Homosexual activists in many ways drive our culture, they decide what?s going to be in a movie, we see all the portrayals, homosexuals are the most positively portrayed in the movies and on TV, Christians are often negatively portrayed and stereotyped,? LaBarbera claims in his conversation with Reisman. ?In many ways, in fact Judith you are Jewish, I think you?re starting to see Hollywood what they?re doing to Christians and to people of faith who actually adhere to traditional values, they?re demonizing them like the Nazis used to do to the Jews. They would compare Jews to rats and we see these vicious, ugly caricatures of Christians coming out of Hollywood. How did we go from that in such a short amount of time to homosexuality being deviant conduct which wasn?t spoken about to now driving our culture??</p> 
<p>Brian Tashman at <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/labarbera-homosexual-activists-doing-to-christians-what-nazis-used-used-to-do-to-jews" type="external">Right Wing Watch</a> notes ?while the two anti-gay activists in their last interview&amp;#160; <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/labarbera-gays-muslims-power-oppressing-freedom" type="external">likened gays to Soviet spies and radical Islamists</a>, LaBarbera and Reisman went straight to the Nazi comparisons this time.? Tashman adds:</p> 
<p>Reisman eagerly agreed and likened public education in the US to schools in Hitler?s Germany and said that just as Nazis put up Hitler posters instead of the Ten Commandments, ?here in the United States we removed the Ten Commandments but we didn?t put up Hitler we put up the AIDS posters, which is just as telling, isn?t it??</p> 
<p>For the record, the Nazis systematically murdered ? <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holocaust" type="external">between 11 million and 17 million people</a>,? including Jewish people, gay people,&amp;#160;Polish&amp;#160;and&amp;#160;Soviet&amp;#160;civilians,&amp;#160;Romani,&amp;#160;communists, and&amp;#160;Soviet prisoners of war, among many others.</p> 
<p>Related:</p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">?The New Normal? Makes LaBarbera Lament There Are No ?Healthy, Contented Ex-Gays? On TV</a></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">Homosexuality: How Much Difference Lies Between US Anti-Gay Groups And Iran?</a></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">What Peter LaBarbera Will Never Understand</a></p> 
<p><a href="" type="internal">Call For ?Dictator? Obama To Be Impeached For ?Celebration Of Homosexuality?</a></p> 
<p>Tagged as: <a href="" type="internal">call</a>, <a href="" type="internal">Christianity</a>, <a href="" type="internal">claims</a>, <a href="" type="internal">date of birth missing</a>, <a href="" type="internal">doing</a>, <a href="" type="internal">Gay</a>, <a href="" type="internal">gay hate groups</a>, <a href="" type="internal">gays</a>, <a href="" type="internal">human behavior</a>, <a href="" type="internal">human sexuality</a>, <a href="" type="internal">jerry falwell</a>, <a href="" type="internal">judith reisman</a>, <a href="" type="internal">labarbera</a>, <a href="" type="internal">nazis</a>, <a href="" type="internal">nazism</a>, <a href="" type="internal">Peter LaBarbera</a>, <a href="" type="internal">reisman</a>, <a href="" type="internal">social issues</a>, <a href="" type="internal">the nazis</a></p> 
<p>Friends:</p> 
<p>We invite you to <a href="http://visitor.r20.constantcontact.com/manage/optin?v=001whLQo73KzGhEjdskYG07rHNy_XoDDkSBBO4INZHx6oD9kfp2yeeQAJeMQUu9oTviZa0VEl5k0rNiLifxlZsOFScMz8rVGmIaN-FFOO3GTKc%3D" type="external">sign up for our new mailing list</a>, and&amp;#160; <a href="http://feedburner.google.com/fb/a/mailverify?uri=TheNewCivilRightsMovement&amp;amp;amp;loc=en_US" type="external">subscribe to The New Civil Rights Movement via email</a> or <a href="http://feeds2.feedburner.com/thenewcivilrightsmovement" type="external">RSS</a>.</p> 
<p>Also, please&amp;#160; <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/The-New-Civil-Rights-Movement/358168880614" type="external">like us on Facebook</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/gaycivilrights" type="external">follow us on Twitter</a>!</p></article>
<article id="0000064" title="The rocking chairs"><p>Heritage column for Nov. 25</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>In the great division of things that follows the closing of a family home, the rocking chairs were not the kind of pieces over which there would have been a tug of war. They were not particularly attractive. They would not have much monetary value. They do not match with the d?cor.</p> 
<p>But the two old rockers offered something that no new pieces of furniture could match, no amount of money could buy and no home should be without. They represented memories and I claimed the rockers and the memories.</p> 
<p>My earliest memories center on those two rocking chairs that occupied prominent spaces in my grandparents' home. They always were in the dining room. Actually the dining room was a dining and sitting room because it was the only room in the house which was heated in the winter. Instead of some comfortable easy chair, my grandfather had a large oak rocker with a wooden back and leather seat. Instead of some comfy and cozy upholstered chair, my grandmother had a small cherry rocker with a cane bottom. I hardly can pass the two chairs, now in my home, without imagining the persons with whom they were so long associated.</p> 
<p>Papa's big rocking chair was where he sat to read the newspaper and the Saturday Evening Post. He was one of the first persons in town to own a radio and the young people on the block would gather around the chair to hear broadcasts. He was one of the last persons to own a television; but when he finally surrendered, he sat in the chair to watch the comedies and Westerns that filled the airwaves of the early '60s.</p> 
<p>Papa's rocking chair was a favorite place for his grandchildren. We would sit there in his lap. When he was not around, we would rock each other so furiously that it would be a constant source of frustration for the other adults who worried that we would break the rockers or break the head of the one taking the wild ride. Indeed the rockers are so worn and flat that the chair barely deserves the description of a rocker.</p> 
<p>Grandma's rocker was a good size for a child and we usually could occupy it because she was too busy to sit for very long. Sometimes she sat there with some sewing in her lap. She sat and read her Sunday school lesson. She paused to enjoy some favorite soap operas: ?Our Gal Sunday,? ?Young Doctor Malone,? ?As the World Turns.?</p> 
<p>I remember the night that my grandfather died. It all happened in a brief time and I still remember wondering how death had slipped into our home without advance notice. The next evening when we returned after the viewing at the funeral home, I broke down when I saw the empty chair and recognized clearly that everything had changed. It shocks me to realize that 42 years have passed since that night.</p> 
<p>My grandmother lived for another 10 years. She wrote me several times a week throughout my college days and in my first year of teaching. The letters always closed with ?I love you, Grandma.? She lived to hold her first great-grandchild, our son Chris.</p> 
<p>On this very day, November 25th, in 1972, now 32 years ago, she died-full of years and held in respect by all that knew her.</p> 
<p>No words of tribute could ever be adequate to describe the blessing that my grandparents were to my life. They loved me before I was born. They nurtured me through my childhood. They wiped away tears, shared laughs and brought glasses of water in the night. They hired taxicabs to take me to the fairgrounds. They walked with me to the park. My grandfather walked with me down the church aisle when I joined the church; and much to everyone's amazement, he joined too. That very morning we were baptized together.</p> 
<p>They never gave a second thought when we three children came to live with them following our parents' divorce. It was not until I was grown that I realized the disruption of their lives and the financial sacrifice that our presence must have required.</p> 
<p>Something else happened on this very day, November 25th, in 1972. Just hours after my grandmother died, our son, Matthew, was born. Now he is grown and a father himself. Now I am the grandparent who sits in the rocking chair with a grandchild on my lap. The years move along and the old rocking chairs remain. And so do the memories on this Thanksgiving Day.</p> 
<p>Fred Anderson is executive director of the Virginia Baptist Historical Society and the Center for Baptist Heritage and Studies. He can be reached at P.O. Box 34, University of Richmond, VA 23173.</p></article>
<article id="0000065" published-at="2017-08-29" title="Second Holiest City In Judaism Finally Gets Designation As Jewish Settlement"><p>Jews in the ancient Biblical city of Hebron, the second holiest city in Judaism and the city where King David was anointed king, got <a href="http://www.jpost.com/Israel-News/Israel-declares-Hebron-an-official-Jewish-settlement-503705" type="external">great news</a> on Friday: Israeli Defense Minister Avigdor Liberman made an upgrade that gave them separate powers from the Palestinian Municipality that governs Hebron. Roughly 1,000 Jews live in Hebron, the site of the Cave of Machpelah where the ancient ancestors of the Jewish people, Abraham, Sarah, Isaac, Rebecca, Jacob, and Leah are buried. The Bible states in Genesis that Abraham (Abram) ?dwelt in the plain of Mamre, which is in Hebron? where ?he built an altar to the Lord.?</p> 
<p>Hebron was the site of the 1929 massacre, in which Arabs slaughtered 67 Jews while the British looked the other way. As Bernard Wasserstein quoted in The British in Palestine: The Mandatory Government and the Arab-Jewish Conflict 1917-1929, one survivor reported, ?On hearing screams in a room I went up a sort of tunnel passage and saw an Arab in the act of cutting off a child?s head with a sword.? In May 1980, six yeshiva students <a href="http://www.camera.org/index.asp?x_context=7&amp;amp;x_issue=75&amp;amp;x_article=3670" type="external">were killed</a> and 20 wounded by Palestinian terrorists as they returned from prayers at the Tomb of the Patriarchs in Hebron; in 1983, another yeshiva student was gunned down in the center of Hebron.</p> 
<p>As recently as the end of June, a Palestinian gunman <a href="http://www.jpost.com/Arab-Israeli-Conflict/Palestinian-gunman-opens-fire-on-Israeli-troops-in-Hebron-is-shot-dead-498242" type="external">opened fire</a> on Israeli troops as they attempted to uncover an arms cache in Hebron. He was shot and killed. In August, Israeli troops <a href="http://www.timesofisrael.com/in-hebron-troops-arrest-parents-who-stashed-bullets-in-kids-rooms/" type="external">arrested</a> a Palestinian couple in Hebron who had hidden over 200 rounds of ammunition in their children?s bedrooms.</p> 
<p>Tayseer Abu Sneineh was elected mayor of Hebron in 2017; he was one of four Palestinian terrorists who on May 2, 1980 <a href="http://www.timesofisrael.com/palestinian-terrorist-in-killing-of-6-jews-elected-hebron-mayor/" type="external">attacked a group of Israelis and Jews</a> in a Hebron alley with grenades, killing U.S. citizens Tzvi Glatt and Eli HaZe?ev, Canadian Shmuel Marmelstein and Israelis Hanan Krauthammer, Gershon Klein and Ya?akov Zimmerman. Another 20 people were injured.</p> 
<p>In 1997 the city was officially split between the Arabs and the Jews; 220,000 Palestinians now live there, with <a href="http://www.jpost.com/Magazine/Hebron-The-conflict-in-a-nutshell-490446" type="external">barbed wire</a> that surrounds Jewish buildings and the 12 IDF checkpoints.</p> 
<p>The new upgrade allows the Jews to independently seek services from the Civil Administration. Deputy Defense Minister Eli Dahan (Bayit Yehudi) said, ?For years, Hebron?s Jewish residents lived without a municipal authority to take care of all the services required for normative civilian life.? He added, ?After the election of a murderer for mayor of Hebron, the idea that they will receive these services from the municipality has become even more absurd. This is another important step in normalizing the lives of the Jews in Hebron in particular and in all of Judea and Samaria in general.?</p></article>
<article id="0000066" published-at="2018-01-25" title="Public schools paid for private school crossing guard"><p>WESTERLY, R.I. (AP) ? A Rhode Island public school district has been paying for a crossing guard at a private school for 18 years, now the superintendent says it needs to stop.</p> 
<p>Westerly Superintendent Mark Garceau told the school committee Wednesday that the deal with St. Pius X Regional Academy came to light earlier this month when the department's payroll office was preparing for the upcoming budget.</p> 
<p>The Sun <a href="http://www.thewesterlysun.com/News/Westerly/Regular-Westerly-School-Committee-meeting.html" type="external">reports</a> that Garceau said the crossing guard was costing the school district about $5,000 a year. He called the principal of St. Pius X to tell her the situation would end.</p> 
<p>The Catholic school's principal said the crossing guard is important because the school is on a dangerous street.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>Information from: The Westerly Sun, <a href="http://www.thewesterlysun.com" type="external">http://www.thewesterlysun.com</a></p> 
<p>WESTERLY, R.I. (AP) ? A Rhode Island public school district has been paying for a crossing guard at a private school for 18 years, now the superintendent says it needs to stop.</p> 
<p>Westerly Superintendent Mark Garceau told the school committee Wednesday that the deal with St. Pius X Regional Academy came to light earlier this month when the department's payroll office was preparing for the upcoming budget.</p> 
<p>The Sun <a href="http://www.thewesterlysun.com/News/Westerly/Regular-Westerly-School-Committee-meeting.html" type="external">reports</a> that Garceau said the crossing guard was costing the school district about $5,000 a year. He called the principal of St. Pius X to tell her the situation would end.</p> 
<p>The Catholic school's principal said the crossing guard is important because the school is on a dangerous street.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>Information from: The Westerly Sun, <a href="http://www.thewesterlysun.com" type="external">http://www.thewesterlysun.com</a></p></article>
<article id="0000067" published-at="2018-07-18" title="North Dakota Gas Average Hits 28-month High"><p>The average price for a gallon of regular gasoline in North Dakota has hit a 28-month high. Today?s statewide average is $2.54. The last time North Dakota motorists paid a higher average was in September 2015. During 2015 the average was as high as $2.76 during the summer months.</p> 
<p>Last year, North Dakotans paid an average of $2.36 for regular gas. Motorist this year can expect to pay an additional 15 cents or more at the pump as the price of oil continues to trade at multi-year highs. While the statewide average isn?t expected to hit $3 at any point during the year, some communities may see prices at or above that level.</p> 
<p>The spread between the low and high averages in communities across the state is often 40 cents or more, according to AAA data.</p></article>
<article id="0000072" published-at="2018-01-21" title="Montecito Mudslides Leave Debris, Destruction and Traumatized Residents"><p>Tonight is a big night in Santa Barbara County California. &amp;#160;For the first time since January 9th, Highway 101 is open. &amp;#160;It?s taken workers nearly two weeks to clear the rivers of mud and debris from the freeway. &amp;#160;</p> 
<p>The residents of Santa Barbara County have been through hell. &amp;#160;First, it was the Thomas fire back in December. &amp;#160;Then it was a wall of water and mud that came down the mountain, washing away parts of Montecito earlier this month. &amp;#160;20 people died. &amp;#160;It will take months for the area to return to anything resembling normal. &amp;#160;We spoke to two families who lived through it all. &amp;#160;This is their story.</p> 
<p>????</p> 
<p>On the night a wall of mud and ash descended on their quiet neighborhood, Bill Ekeler?s wife, Heather, shook him awake with a start.&amp;#160; ?Bill, there?s something strange?the skylight is orange,? she told him. So the father of three went down to the kitchen to get a better look. There, he saw a ?massive orange glow? coming from the low hills to the north and east.</p> 
<p>Worried for the safety of his wife and kids, as well as the well-being of his in-laws and their two children who had been evacuated the day before and were asleep in the basement,&amp;#160;Ekeler jumped in his son?s car and drove in the direction of the glow.</p> 
<p>The rain was pouring hard, and Ekeler heard a strange roar?what sounded like a jet engine. &amp;#160;He soon realized the fire was the least of his worries. ?Right in front of me there was a wall of 6 or 8 feet of water and the fastest growing river that you?ve ever seen,? Ekeler says. He didn?t waste any time getting back to his home.&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>In the week that has passed since the worst mudslides in 20 years enveloped this otherwise picturesque community, shellshocked families like the Ekelers are doing their best to cope with the trauma of that night and its aftermath?both mindful and fearful of the fact that another heavy rain could cause yet more damage.</p> 
<p>It was just last month when a fire created the conditions for all this mud. &amp;#160;It was called the Thomas fire and it burned nearly 300,000 acres across southern California. &amp;#160;The hills around Montecito was ground zero for the fire. &amp;#160;Vegetation was incinerated for miles.</p> 
<p>But by New Year?s Eve, thinking the worst was finally behind them, Montecito residents were able to settle back in. &amp;#160; The fires were under control. &amp;#160;A voluntary evacuation alert was issued when the rain started falling, but most residents stayed put. Having survived the fires, they could not imagine what was about to come.</p> 
<p>Meanwhile, state and local officials are scrambling to clear debris.&amp;#160;Cable and gas companies are working around the clock to restore service to thousands of customers. Emergency water distribution sites have been set up. A fleet of bulldozers and dump trucks have been deployed to clear an impassable stretch of Highway 101 though officials caution the crucial freeway will&amp;#160;remain closed ?indefinitely.?&amp;#160; By the last count, 120 homes have been lost and 20 people have died. Three are still missing.</p> 
<p>Down Olive Mill Road, the Ekelers? friend Susan Moe woke up that night to the same roaring noise and livid sky. From her window, she watched as both her front yard and her backyard were inundated with mud and water. ?We were completely&amp;#160;trapped,? she says. ?It was just a wall of water and trees and cars and debris and things that were flowing down.?</p> 
<p>Moe spent the next few hours anxiously texting and waiting with the Ekelers and other friends. The storm intensified around 3:30 a.m., as Montecito was battered by more than a half-inch of rain in five minutes, sending boulders and mud shooting down the canyons. The rain didn?t ease up until&amp;#160;daybreak when the Moes were rescued by firefighters.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Surveying the destruction, they soon realized that the wall separating their property from their neighbor?s had, in fact, saved their lives. ?These trees and cars were stopped by that wall and that prevented them from coming into our bedroom windows,? she says. ?It makes me shake just thinking about it.?</p> 
<p>As the day went on, neighbors picked through the rubble and joined impromptu search parties looking for missing residents.&amp;#160;A mother and one of her daughters were found, but a second daughter and stepdaughter remained unaccounted for. Even these modest efforts were quickly hampered by adverse conditions, however, and the sheriff soon asked volunteers to let the professionals take over. ?The mud itself was so thick, it was almost the consistency of Cream of Wheat,? Ekeler says, ?Almost like quicksand.?</p> 
<p>The bodies of the two girls were later recovered.</p> 
<p>With no access to cable TV or the Internet for news, residents relied on word of mouth to learn about the fate of their neighbors. Ekeler soon learned that Connor McManigal, 23, had been swept into the storm along with his father John, 61. ?Connor ended up almost a mile down in the 101 with broken ribs,? says Ekeler. His father did not survive. ?It?s stuff like that,? Ekeler says. ?When you see that people traveled that far and survived, and some didn?t.? Ekeler later went to check on the McManigals? home to see if he could find their cat for Connor, who is recovering in a local hospital. What he found shocked him anew.&amp;#160;?When I got up to where his house was,? Ekeler says, ?the house wasn?t there.?</p> 
<p>Harder still is explaining to his three kids that some of their school friends and classmates? parents were lost in a tragic instant. ?It?s been very, very traumatic for him,? says Ekeler of son Blake, 13, with whom he watched the National Championship college football game only hours before all hell broke loose. ?He doesn?t really understand it and, as a parent, you really don?t know what to say.?</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p></article>
<article id="0000074" published-at="2012-09-26" title="Staples says its closing 60 stores, mostly in Europe, to cut costs"><p>Staples announced Tuesday that it would close 60 of its stores mostly in Europe to cut $250 million by 2015.</p> 
<p>Europe will see 45 stores closed while the US stores will see total square footage reduced by 15 percent.</p> 
<p>The move is part of a restructuring in which the office supply giant likely hopes to sell off its European printing business while strengthening its online presence.</p> 
<p>Office supply retailers like Staples have been badly bruised in the recession during which business customers declined.</p> 
<p>They have also had to face growing competition from online retailers like Amazon, while dealing with an increasingly paper-less world, <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/deals/2012/09/25/staples-plans-restructuring-and-store-closings-but-no-word-of-sale/" type="external">said the Wall Street Journal</a>.</p> 
<p>More from GlobalPost:&amp;#160; <a href="http://www.globalpost.com/dispatch/news/regions/asia-pacific/china/120925/top-11-wealthiest-economy-slowdown-finance" type="external">Meet the top 11 wealthiest people in China</a></p> 
<p>The company reported a large fall of its net income in the first and second quarters of the fiscal year, <a href="http://www.sfgate.com/business/bloomberg/article/Staples-to-Close-60-Stores-in-Plan-to-Save-250-3893495.php" type="external">said Bloomberg</a>, and has been hurt by a lack of job creation in the US and Europe.</p> 
<p>Foot traffic is also down at Staples stores across the country and in Europe in particular, <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/Business/Latest-News-Wires/2012/0925/Staples-speeds-up-store-closures-focuses-online" type="external">said the Christian Science Monitor</a>.</p> 
<p>Apart from closing stores and increasing its online presence, the company also named a new executive, Demos Parneros to run its US retail and online division, <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/deals/2012/09/25/staples-plans-restructuring-and-store-closings-but-no-word-of-sale/" type="external">said the Wall Street Journal</a>.</p> 
<p>The Framingham, Mass., company currently operates in 26 countries and on every continent except Africa.</p> 
<p>Staples's stock slipped 5 cents to $12.30 with the news of the shake-up.</p></article>
<article id="0000076" published-at="2017-12-07" title="A single mother of two found shot to death inside her car in Fort Bend County"><p>An area resident made a shocking discovering around 7:30 p.m. Tuesday night in Four Corners, near Mission Bend.</p> 
<p>RELATED: <a href="" type="internal">Like Houston?s curfew, Fort Bend County is instituting a similar policy for the time being</a></p> 
<p><a href="https://www.click2houston.com/news/woman-shot-to-death-inside-vehicle-near-mission-bend" type="external">Lieu Nguyen, 39, was found dead</a> in the driver?s seat of her car near the intersection of Bissonnet and Addicks Clodine roads.&amp;#160;She suffered multiple gunshot wounds, according to police.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Residents reported hearing gunshots in the area, although a gun was not recovered at the location.</p> 
<p>Police believe Nguyen, a single mother of two, was in her normal routine that day, driving home from work at an insurance office around 6 p.m. when the shooting occurred. As investigators search for a motive, they say the shooting may have been triggered by road rage.</p> 
<p>According to <a href="http://www.khou.com/news/crime/reward-offered-for-info-on-woman-fatally-shot-near-mission-bend/497305881" type="external">KHOU</a>, police say Nguyen was driving side-by-side with another vehicle Tuesday night when someone in the other vehicle pulled out a gun and began firing.</p> 
<p>Sheriff?s investigators are waiting to interview&amp;#160;a witness. They also have a video from a home near where the shooting occurred.</p> 
<p>The only description deputies say they have of the shooter?s vehicle is a dark colored, mid-sized passage car.</p> 
<p>Nguyen leaves behind 11-year-old and 8-month-old sons.</p> 
<p>Fort Bend County Crime Stoppers is offering a $5,000 reward for information leading to an arrest.</p> 
<p>RELATED: <a href="" type="internal">Fort Bend ISD officials say they are making drop-off changes after last week?s fatal accident</a></p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000081" published-at="2011-04-15" title="MSNBC?s Matthews Calls Fox News a ?Roach Motel? for GOP Candidates"><p>Chris Matthews was on a roll last night.&amp;#160; First it was the fawning interview with Rep. Debbie Wasserman Schultz on her new role as the DNC Chairman, then it was this segment about Donald Trump, where he compared Fox News to being a roach motel for Republican candidates.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>Visit msnbc.com for <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com" type="external">breaking news</a>, <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/3032507" type="external">world news</a>, and <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/3032072" type="external">news about the economy</a></p> 
<p>Matthews: By the way, working at Fox has kind of turned out to be kind of the roach motel. I mean anybody who?s going over there to work seems like they?re getting the sticky stuff on the floor over there. They haven?t been able to come back.</p> 
<p>Any real or perceived implosion by prospective Republican candidates as a result of their appearances on Fox would be of their own doing and has nothing to do with being associated with Fox. But for liberals like Matthews any chance to link conservative or Republican failure to Fox, no matter how much it strains credulity, is just too good to pass up.</p> 
<p>But who needs real facts when you have Chris Matthews?</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p></article>
<article id="0000083" published-at="2017-04-20" title="Lagarde: IMF can Cooperate with Trump to Improve Global Trade"><p></p> 
<p>International Monetary Fund Managing Director Christine Lagarde said on Thursday she believes the IMF can work successfully with the Trump administration to improve the global trading system, but added that open trade must be preserved as a growth engine.</p> 
<p>Continue Reading Below</p> 
<p>Lagarde told a news conference at the opening of the IMF and World Bank spring meetings in Washington that the IMF saw the need to reduce subsidies and other trade distortions that limit competition, but also said "protectionist measures" needed to be avoided.</p> 
<p>"From the various contacts that I've had with the administration so far, I have every reason to believe that we will make progress, that we will cooperate all together in order to support and indeed improve the system as we have it," Lagarde said. (Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Paul Simao)</p></article>
<article id="0000084" published-at="2014-01-15" title="Poll: Christie Cruising Through Bridge Scandal (So Far)"><p>Nearly 70 percent of Americans say the bridge-closure scandal engulfing Chris Christie has not changed their opinion about the New Jersey governor, according to a new NBC News/Marist poll. In addition, 44 percent of respondents believe he?s telling the truth about his knowledge of the events surrounding the controversy.</p> 
<p>And far more Americans view him as a strong leader rather than as a bully.</p> 
<p>But the survey also shows that the potential 2016 Republican candidate has lost ground to former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton in an early hypothetical presidential match up and now trails her by 13 points.</p> 
<p>Lee Miringoff, director of the Marist College Institute for Public Opinion, explains that, overall, this is good news for Christie.</p> 
<p>?The numbers suggest it?s far from politically fatal for him,? he says of the scandal, adding: ?This is a developing story, so the extent of the damage down the road is an open proposition.?</p> 
<p>But the down side for Christie, according to Miringoff: Americans ?are getting to know to him, and that?s maybe not the best way to introduce himself to a national audience.?</p> 
<p>The poll ? conducted Jan. 12-14 ? comes after <a href="" type="internal">released emails</a> showing that a top Christie aide, as well as his Port Authority appointees, conspired to close local-access lanes to the busy George Washington Bridge as retribution against the Democratic mayor of Fort Lee, N.J.</p> 
<p>?Time for some traffic problems in Fort Lee,? Christie Deputy Chief of Staff Bridget Anne Kelly emailed Christie Port Authority aide David Wildstein back in Aug. 2013, just weeks before the lane closures.</p> 
<p>?Got it,? Wildstein replied.</p> 
<p>In a subsequent news conference last Thursday, Christie announced that he had fired Kelly, but also said that he had no knowledge of or role in the lane closings.</p> 
<p>Most haven?t changed their opinion of Christie</p> 
<p>According to the survey, 18 percent of American adults say the scandal makes them like Christie less, compared with 5 percent who say it makes them like him more.</p> 
<p>But a whopping 69 percent say it hasn?t changed their opinion of the New Jersey governor.</p> 
<p>Still, a combined 71 percent of respondents say they know either ?a lot? or ?some? about the story.</p> 
<p>In addition, a plurality ? 44 percent ? believe Christie is mostly telling the truth, 33 percent say he?s not and another 23 percent are unsure.</p> 
<p><a href="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/i/MSNBC/Sections/A_Politics/_Today_Stories_Teases/ChristiePoll.pdf" type="external">Read the full poll</a></p> 
<p>(There?s a political divide to these responses, however: 61 percent of Republicans say he?s telling the truth, while 41 percent of Democrat don?t think he is.)</p> 
<p>And more respondents view him as a strong leader (47 percent) than as a bully (27 percent).</p> 
<p>Christie trails Clinton in a national match up</p> 
<p>Despite those numbers, Christie has lost ground to Hillary Clinton in an early hypothetical presidential match up. In this current poll, he trails Clinton by 13 points, 50 percent to 37 percent among nationwide voters.</p> 
<p>But in the same poll a month ago, Clinton?s lead was a mere three points, 48 percent to 45 percent.</p> 
<p>?Up against a likely Hillary candidacy, the argument that Christie is positioned to win back the White House [for Republicans] is far from automatic,? Miringoff says.</p> 
<p>What?s also problematic for Christie is that his favorability rating is upside down ? with 28 percent viewing him positively and 30 percent viewing him negatively.</p> 
<p>By comparison, Clinton?s fav/unfav rating is a net positive (50 percent positive, 38 percent negative), while President Barack Obama?s is a net negative (41 percent to 48 percent).</p> 
<p>Measuring the GOP?s 2016 field</p> 
<p>That said, Christie is leading the pack ? barely ? in an early trial heat of potential Republican candidates.</p> 
<p>When Republicans voters were asked whom they support if the GOP primary or caucus were held today, 16 percent picked Christie, 12 percent sided with 2012 running mate Paul Ryan, 9 percent said Sen. Rand Paul, R-Ky., and 8 percent said former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush.</p> 
<p>Those percentages are virtually unchanged from last month.</p> 
<p>Rounding out the rest of the field: Sen. Marco Rubio, R-Fla., (7 percent); Texas Gov. Rick Perry (6 percent); former presidential candidate Rick Santorum (5 percent); Sen. Ted Cruz, R-Texas, (5 percent); Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker (4 percent); and Louisiana Gov. Bobby Jindal (3 percent).</p> 
<p>Still, 25 percent said they were undecided.</p> 
<p>?It?s about as wide open as it can get,? Miringoff says.</p> 
<p>The NBC/Marist poll was conducted Jan. 12-14 of 1,200 national adults (margin of error of plus-minus 2.8 percentage points), 1,039 registered voters (plus-minus 3.0 percentage points) and 385 Republican voters (plus-minus 5.0 percentage points).</p></article>
<article id="0000086" published-at="2017-10-02" title="How Long, America?"><p>Empires die.&amp;#160; Some abruptly, by cataclysmic defeat and destruction; most in stages, over years, decades.&amp;#160; Our own meltdown?early in the fantasized ?New American Century??will not be exceptional? unlike our arrogance.</p> 
<p>When human injury results in coma, a victim is assessed on the Glasgow Coma Scale.&amp;#160; Eye function, and sound and motion capability, indicate if death is imminent or not.</p> 
<p>Empires? ends are unpredictable, but three criteria seem determinant: military overreach, state insolvency, and economic inequity.</p> 
<p>Our overreach is obvious, ridiculous, and inalterable: our criminal economy demands it.&amp;#160; America attacks, invades, and destroys so our murderous war machine can engorge itself on wealth extracted from our own blood and marrow.</p> 
<p>Our State?absolutely insolvent, existing on loans?runs a giant shell game using keystroke fiat money on nations so gigantically bankrupt, so utterly captive, that they have to accept the wildly bogus dollar?s value or crash and burn.</p> 
<p>Economic inequity is at a level unmatched in any empire since Ninevah and all financial levers work to increase it.</p> 
<p>So then, for America, is it all over but the shouting?</p> 
<p>Or can this absurdly precarious condition continue?&amp;#160; It probably can, until a Black Swan event roars out of the dark and sweeps the whole moribund structure away.</p> 
<p>So, a clumsily provoked war, perhaps, against a real adversary, not one of the tiny, poor, primitive ?enemies? that routinely stalemate our glitzy war machine.&amp;#160; Or a category 5 typhoon of 200 trillion in derivatives that blows Wall Street?s house down?&amp;#160; A ?people?s revolution?..?&amp;#160; Nah.</p> 
<p>The unique feature of our Empire may be the stunning contrast between its ponderous material might and the imbecility of its human owners.&amp;#160; Wherever one looks in the stratosphere of American authority, instead of wisdom and probity there is rabid vacuity or what-me-worry bufoonery.</p> 
<p>Our President is the incarnation of infantile autism.&amp;#160; His Braindead Trust of dotty warlords are brass boobs with the intellectual acuity of ventriloquists? dummies.&amp;#160; His cabinet is a looney gaggle of retro clowns and Snerd goofuses, embarrassing even to that stumblebum Congress of sociopathic criminals and defectives that confirmed them.</p> 
<p>And the Goldberg Machine of US Empire churns on.&amp;#160; And so it goes, as Vonnegut said.&amp;#160; In his view humans were put on earth to fart around, and this seems certain in our case.</p> 
<p>But listen!&amp;#160; The sound you hear behind the idiocy of official fake news is the tectonic rumble of imperial earthquake.</p></article>
<article id="0000087" published-at="2012-10-11" title="Six Critical Foreign Policy Questions That Won?t Be Raised in the Debates"><p>&amp;lt;a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-113023426/stock-photo-grunge-map-of-the-world.html?src=8b075e6f7b16c8d418ba3931f392d22d-1-2"&amp;gt;javarman&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;/Shutterstock</p> 
<p>This <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/blog/175603/" type="external">story</a> first appeared on the <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/" type="external">TomDispatch</a> website.</p> 
<p>We had a debate club back in high school. Two teams would meet in the auditorium, and Mr. Garrity would tell us the topic, something 1970s-ish like ?Resolved: Women Should Get Equal Pay for Equal Work? or ?World Communism Will Be Defeated in Vietnam.? Each side would then try, through persuasion and the marshalling of facts, to clinch the argument. There?d be judges and a winner.</p> 
<p>Today?s presidential debates are a long way from Mr. Garrity?s club. It seems that the first rule of the debate club now is: no disagreeing on what matters most. In fact, the two candidates rarely interact with each other at all, typically ditching whatever the question might be for some rehashed set of campaign talking points, all with the complicity of the celebrity media moderators preening about democracy in action. Waiting for another quip about Big Bird is about all the content we can expect.</p> 
<p>But the joke is on us. Sadly, the two candidates are stand-ins for Washington in general, a ?war? capital whose denizens work and argue, sometimes fiercely, from within a remarkably limited range of options. It was D.C. on autopilot last week for domestic issues; the next two presidential debates are to be in part or fully on foreign policy challenges (of which there are so many). When it comes to foreign?that is, military?policy, the gap between Barack and Mitt is <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/07/29/us/politics/obama-and-romney-strain-to-assert-foreign-policy-differences.html" type="external">slim</a> to the point of nonexistent on many issues, however much they may badger each other on the subject. That old saw about those who fail to understand history repeating its mistakes applies a little too easily here: the last 11 years have added up to one disaster after another abroad, and without a smidgen of new thinking (guaranteed not to put in an appearance at any of the debates to come), we doom ourselves to more of the same.</p> 
<p><a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com" type="external"></a></p> 
<p>So in honor of old Mr. Garrity, here are five critical questions that should be explored (even if all of us know that they won?t be) in the foreign policy-inclusive presidential debates scheduled <a href="http://www.2012presidentialelectionnews.com/2012-debate-schedule/2012-presidential-debate-schedule/%20O" type="external">for</a> October 16th, and 22nd?with a sixth bonus question thrown in for good measure.</p> 
<p>1. Is there an end game for the global war on terror?</p> 
<p>The current president, elected on the promise of change, altered very little when it came to George W. Bush?s Global War on Terror (other than dropping the name). That jewel-in-the-crown of Bush-era offshore imprisonment, Guantanamo, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/30/world/americas/canadian-held-at-guantanamo-bay-is-repatriated.html" type="external">still houses</a> over 160 prisoners held without trial or hope or a plan for what to do with them. While the US pulled its troops <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/the-us-withdrawal-from-iraq-marks-the-end-of-american-supremacy/2011/12/12/gIQAStpTyO_story.html" type="external">out of Iraq</a>?mostly because our Iraqi ?allies? flexed their muscles a bit and <a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2012/09/10/why_mitt_romney_cant_talk_about_iraq" type="external">threw</a> us out?the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/30/2000-us-troop-killed-afghanistan-insider-attack_n_1926536.html" type="external">war in Afghanistan</a> stumbles on. Drone strikes and other forms of conflict continue in the same places Bush tormented: <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2012/09/yemen-drone-war/" type="external">Yemen</a>, <a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2012/06/27/somalia-s-prisons-the-war-on-terror-s-latest-front.html" type="external">Somalia</a>, and <a href="http://www.longwarjournal.org/pakistan-strikes.php" type="external">Pakistan</a> (and it?s clear that <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/white-house-secret-meetings-examine-al-qaeda-threat-in-north-africa/2012/10/01/f485b9d2-0bdc-11e2-bd1a-b868e65d57eb_story.html?socialreader_check=0&amp;amp;amp;denied=1" type="external">northern Mali</a> is heading our way).</p> 
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0805096817/ref=nosim/?tag=tomdispatch-20" type="external"></a>A huge national security state has been codified in a host of new or expanded intelligence agencies under the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/dhs-fusion-centers-portrayed-as-pools-of-ineptitude-and-civil-liberties-intrusions/2012/10/02/10014440-0cb1-11e2-bd1a-b868e65d57eb_story.html" type="external">Homeland Security</a> umbrella, and Washington seems able to come up with nothing more than a whack-a-mole strategy for ridding itself of the scourge of terror, an endless succession of killings of ?al-Qaeda Number 3? guys. <a href="http://www.salon.com/2012/05/22/john_brennans_new_power/" type="external">Counterterrorism tsar</a> John Brennan, Obama?s drone-meister, has put it <a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2012/09/18/the_seven_deadly_sins_of_john_brennan?page=full" type="external">this way</a>: ?We?re not going to rest until al-Qaeda the organization is destroyed and is eliminated from areas in Afghanistan, Pakistan, Yemen, Africa, and other areas.?</p> 
<p>So, candidates, the question is: What?s the end game for all this? Even in the worst days of the Cold War, when it seemed impossible to imagine, there was still a goal: the ?end? of the Soviet Union. Are we really consigned to the Global War on Terror, under whatever name or no name at all, as an infinite state of existence? Is it now as American as apple pie?</p> 
<p>2. Do today?s foreign policy challenges mean that it?s time to retire the Constitution?</p> 
<p>A domestic policy crossover question here. Prior to September 11, 2001, it was generally assumed that our amazing Constitution could be adapted to whatever challenges or problems arose. After all, that founding document expanded to end the slavery it had once supported, weathered trials and misuses as dumb as Prohibition and as grave as <a href="http://law2.umkc.edu/faculty/projects/ftrials/saccov/redscare.html" type="external">Red Scares</a>, Palmer Raids, and <a href="http://www.ushistory.org/us/53a.asp" type="external">McCarthyism</a>. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution" type="external">First Amendment</a> grew to cover comic books, nude art works, and a million electronic forms of expression never imagined in the eighteenth century. Starting on September 12, 2001, however, challenges, threats, and risks abroad have been used to justify abandoning core beliefs enshrined in the Bill of Rights. That bill, we are told, can?t accommodate terror threats to the Homeland. Absent the third rail of the <a href="http://caselaw.lp.findlaw.com/data/constitution/amendment02/" type="external">Second Amendment</a> and gun ownership (politicians touch it and die), nearly every other key amendment has since been trodden upon.</p> 
<p>The First Amendment was sacrificed to silence <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/archive/175526/peter_van_buren_the_whistleblower's_piece" type="external">whistleblowers</a> and <a href="http://www.salon.com/2011/06/23/risen_3/" type="external">journalists</a>. The <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2012/09/14/warantless_wiretapping_bill_james_clapper_despite_schakowsky_efforts_house_votes_to_renew_fisa_provisions_.html" type="external">Fourth</a> and <a href="http://investorplace.com/investorpolitics/what-obama-slipped-by-us-on-new-years-eve/" type="external">Fifth</a> Amendments were ignored to spy on Americans at home and kill them with drones abroad. (September 30th was the one-year anniversary of the Obama administration?s first <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2011/09/30/us-born-terror-boss-anwar-al-awlaki-killed/" type="external">acknowledged murder</a> without due process of an American?and later his teenaged son?abroad. The US has <a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2012/09/18/the_seven_deadly_sins_of_john_brennan?page=full" type="external">similarly killed</a> two other Americans abroad via drone, albeit ?by accident.?)</p> 
<p>So, candidates, the question is: Have we walked away from the Constitution? If so, shouldn?t we publish some sort of notice or bulletin?</p> 
<p>3. What do we want from the Middle East?</p> 
<p>Is it all about oil? Israel? Old-fashioned hegemony and <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/09/25/us-un-assembly-obama-excerpts-idUSBRE88O0F520120925" type="external">containment</a>? What is our goal in fighting an intensifying <a href="http://wemeantwell.com/blog/2011/04/18/proxy-war-us-v-iran-in-the-middle-east/" type="external">proxy war</a> with Iran, newly expanded into <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/01/world/middleeast/obama-ordered-wave-of-cyberattacks-against-iran.html" type="external">cyberspace</a>? Are we worried about a nuclear Iran, or just worried about a new nuclear club member in general? Will we continue the nineteenth century game of supporting thug dictators who support our policies in <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/blog/175594/marlowe_terror_and_tear_gas" type="external">Bahrain</a>, Saudi Arabia, Egypt, and Libya (until overwhelmed by events on the ground), and opposing the same actions by other thugs who disagree with us like Iraq?s Saddam Hussein and Syria?s Bashar al-Assad? That kind of <a href="http://wais.stanford.edu/USA/us_supportforladictators8303.html" type="external">policy thinking</a> did not work out too well in the long run in Central and South America, and history suggests that we should make up our mind on what America?s goals in the Middle East might actually be. No cheating now?having <a href="http://world.time.com/2012/10/01/after-november-five-mideast-headaches-looming-for-the-u-s/" type="external">no policy</a> is a policy of its own.</p> 
<p>Candidates, can you define America?s predominant interest in the Middle East and sketch out a series of at least semi-sensical actions in support of it?</p> 
<p>4. What is your plan to right-size our military and what about downsizing the global mission?</p> 
<p>The decade?and counting?of grinding war in Iraq and Afghanistan has worn the American military down to its lowest point since <a href="http://www.strategicstudiesinstitute.army.mil/pubs/display.cfm?pubID=1020" type="external">Vietnam</a>. Though drugs and poor discipline are not tearing out its heart as they did in the 1970s, <a href="http://nation.time.com/2012/08/16/grim-record-soldier-suicides-reach-new-high/" type="external">suicide</a> among soldiers now takes that first chair position. The toll on families of endless deployments is hard to measure but easy to see. The expanding role of the military abroad (reconstruction, peacekeeping, disaster relief, garrisoning a long <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/archive/175338/" type="external">necklace of bases</a> from Rota, Spain, to Kadena, Okinawa) seems to require a vast standing army. At the same time, the dramatic increase in the development and use of a new praetorian guard, <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/archive/175426/nick_turse_a_secret_war_in_120_countries" type="external">Joint Special Operations Command</a>, coupled with a <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/petraeus-would-helm-an-increasingly-militarized-cia/2011/04/27/AFwoDM1E_story.html" type="external">militarized CIA</a> and its <a href="http://hnn.us/articles/our-drone-planet-interview-tom-engelhardt-and-nick-turse-past-present-and-future-drones" type="external">drones</a>, have given the president previously unheard of <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/archive/175551/assassin-in-chief" type="external">personal killing power</a>. Indeed, Obama has underscored his unchecked solo role as the ?decider? on exactly who gets <a href="http://news.antiwar.com/2012/05/29/officials-confirm-obama-decides-who-lives-and-who-dies" type="external">obliterated</a> by drone assassins.</p> 
<p>So, candidates, here?s a two-parter: Given that a huge Occupy Everywhere army is killing more of its own via suicide than any enemy, what will you do to right-size the military and downsize its global mission? Secondly, did this country?s founders really intend for the president to have unchecked personal war-making powers?</p> 
<p>5. Since no one outside our borders buys American exceptionalism anymore, what?s next? What is America?s point these days?</p> 
<p>The big one. We keep the old myth alive that America is a special, good place, the most ? <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2011/dec/02/opinion/la-oe-engelhardt-american-exceptionalism-20111202" type="external">exceptional</a>? of places in fact, but in our foreign policy we?re more like some mean old man, reduced to feeling good about himself by yelling at the kids to get off the lawn (or simply taking potshots at them).</p> 
<p>During the Cold War, the American <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2006/sep/10/post348" type="external">ideal</a> represented freedom to so many people, even if the reality was far more ambiguous. Now, who we are and what we are abroad seems so much grimmer, so much less appealing (as global opinion polls <a href="http://www.pewglobal.org/2012/09/19/wait-you-still-dont-like-us/" type="external">regularly indicate</a>). In light of the Iraq invasion and occupation, and the failure to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/25/us/politics/arab-spring-proves-a-harsh-test-for-obamas-diplomatic-skill.html" type="external">embrace</a> the Arab Spring, America the Exceptional, has, it seems, run its course.</p> 
<p>America the Hegemonic, a tough if unattractive moniker, also seems a goner, given the <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/blog/175587/tomgram%3A_engelhardt,_losing_it_in_washington/" type="external">slo-mo defeat</a> in Afghanistan and the never-ending stalemate that is the Global War on Terror. Resource imperialist? America?s failure to either back away from the Greater Middle East and simply pay the price for oil, or successfully grab the oil, adds up to a ?policy? that only encourages ever more instability in the region. The saber rattling that goes with such a strategy (if it can be called that) feels angry, unproductive, and without any doubt unbelievably expensive.</p> 
<p>So candidates, here are a few questions: Who exactly are we in the world and who do you want us to be? Are you ready to promote a policy of fighting to be planetary top dog?and we all know where that leads?or can we find a place in the global community? Without resorting to the usual ?shining city on a hill? metaphors, can you tell us your vision for America in the world? (Follow up: No really, cut the b.s and answer this one, gentlemen. It?s important!)</p> 
<p>6. Bonus Question: To each of the questions above add this: How do you realistically plan to pay for it? For every school and road built in Iraq and Afghanistan on the taxpayer dollar, why didn?t you build two here in the United States? When you insist that we can?t pay for crucial needs at home, explain to us why these can be funded abroad. If your response is we had to spend that money to ?defend America,? tell us why building jobs in this country doesn?t do more to defend it than anything done abroad.</p> 
<p>Now that might spark a real debate, one that?s long, long overdue.</p> 
<p>Peter Van Buren, a 24-year veteran Foreign Service Officer at the State Department, spent a year in Iraq. Now in Washington and a <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/blog/175583/van_buren_imperial_reconstruction_and_its_discontents" type="external">TomDispatch regular</a>, he writes about Iraq, the Middle East, and US diplomacy at his blog, <a href="http://www.wemeantwell.com" type="external">We Meant Well</a>. Following the publication of his book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0805096817/ref=nosim/?tag=tomdispatch-20" type="external">We Meant Well: How I Helped Lose the Battle for the Hearts and Minds of the Iraqi People</a> (the American Empire Project, Metropolitan Books), the Department of State began termination proceedings, stripping him of his security clearance and diplomatic credentials. Through the efforts of the <a href="http://www.whistleblower.org/" type="external">Government Accountability Project</a> and the <a href="http://www.aclu.org/" type="external">ACLU</a>, Van Buren instead retired from the State Department with his full benefits of service. To stay on top of important articles like these, sign up to receive the latest updates from TomDispatch.com <a href="http://tomdispatch.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=6cb39ff0b1f670c349f828c73&amp;amp;id=1e41682ade" type="external">here</a>.</p></article>
<article id="0000090" published-at="2013-08-13" title="John Lewis? Advice for Young Activists: March"><p>I jumped in the car with two of the young people, and I drove to Selma, late at night, got there at three or four in the morning, got our sleeping bags out, got up the next morning, got dressed, went to the church, and we lined up and we marched. The rest is history.</p> 
<p>As the 50th anniversary of the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom approaches, the spirit of protest seems to be rekindling in many parts of the country. The Dream Defenders remain camped out in the Florida capitol, demanding justice for Trayvon Martin and an end to racial profiling; North Carolina's <a href="" type="internal">Moral Monday protesters</a> have rallied and committed civil disobedience each week, defying the far-right agenda of their state legislators. In New York, the <a href="" type="internal">coalition against stop and frisk</a> won its victory in court, but it took organizing, rallying, and yes, marching, to make it happen.</p> 
<p>It's a good time, then, for a new memoir by congressman and 1960s civil rights leader John Lewis. In March: Book One, out today from <a href="http://www.topshelfcomix.com/catalog/march/760" type="external">Top Shelf Productions</a>, Lewis' history and the highs and lows of the civil rights movement are brought to life?vividly, as the memoir is in comic format.</p> 
<p>The first of three books follows a young Lewis from his family's farm in Alabama to college and to the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), to lunch counter sit-ins, jail cells and a showdown with the mayor of Nashville. Co-written by Andrew Aydin, a staffer who's been with Lewis for years, and drawn by award-winning comics artist Nate Powell, the book makes history feel real and present in a way that few accounts of civil rights legends have managed to.</p> 
<p>Lewis and Aydin sat down with me during a visit to New York to discuss the new comic, their goal of inspiring and instructing a new generation, and where they're finding hope these days.</p> 
<p>Sarah Jaffe: This book is the first of three volumes, all with the title March. Why did you pick that title?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: March is the spring, it's life, it's the beginning. So much happened in March. But it's also moving feet.</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: There was a quote that stuck with us very early on, it was something Dr. King said: ?There's no sound more powerful than the marching feet of the determined people.?</p> 
<p>But March is so many different things. It is the need to march. It is March 7, 1965. There's so much meaning behind it, it seemed almost self-evident.</p> 
<p>Book 2 contains a very famous march. During the movement, the Congressman was so committed to action. There were so many moments where people wanted to talk, and he wanted to do. There's this scene in Book 2, when they're saying the violence is getting to be too much, we have to work out a solution, and they'd turn to John Lewis and say, ?What do you think we should do?? And he would say, ?We should just march.?</p> 
<p>They would ask him again and he would say, ?We should just march.? Finally they say, ?John, everything you're saying is that we should march, but people are going to get hurt, people are going to get killed, it's your own foolish pride that's getting involved with that, you're just nothing but a sinner.?</p> 
<p>And he's like, ?I may be a sinner, but we're gonna march.?</p> 
<p>It so typifies his view on how to get things done. We can sit around and talk about it, we can make speeches, but really when it comes down to it, the hard part is doing the work. Taking action.</p> 
<p>John Lewis: This may sound a little self-serving here, but my own organization, the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, objected to the march in Selma. We had an all-night discussion, a debate whether we should march. It's clear to me that I should march. And I said, ?I've been to Selma many many times, I've stood in line at the courthouse, I've been arrested, I've been to jail there. The local people want to march, and I'm going to march.?</p> 
<p>So I jumped in the car with two of the young people, and I drove to Selma, late at night, got there at three or four in the morning, got our sleeping bags out, got up the next morning, got dressed, went to the church, and we lined up and we marched. The rest is history.</p> 
<p>Sometimes you just have to do what your spirit says do. Go for it.</p> 
<p>Why did you decide to do this as a comic?&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: I was working for the Congressman on the 2008 campaign as his press secretary, and we started talking about what we were going to do after we had our nights and weekends back. I admitted I was going to a comic book convention?in politics that gets you laughs, snickers, a little jeering. But the Congressman said, ?You know, there was a comic book during the movement and it was incredibly influential.? That comic book was ? <a href="http://www.ep.tc/mlk/" type="external">Martin Luther King and the Montgomery Story</a>.?</p> 
<p>I went home that night, Googled it, and read the story about how it <a href="http://theubs.com/features/themontstory.php" type="external">inspired the Greensboro 4</a>. I came back the next day and asked him ?Why don't you write a comic book??&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>The Congressman looked at me like I was crazy there for a second, but we talked about the comic from the '50s, and a couple weeks later I asked again, and the Congressman said, ?OK, but only if you write it with me.?</p> 
<p>It just seemed to make sense, the idea of a comic book inspiring young people to get involved and also teaching them the tactics.</p> 
<p>The book uses President Obama's inauguration as a framing device. Can you talk about the decision to do that?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: People ask me from time to time whether the election of Barack Obama was the fulfillment of Martin Luther King's dream, and I say, ?No, it's just a down payment.?</p> 
<p>Because we're not there. More and more, people are saying that we still have a distance to travel, and that we cannot be at peace or be at home with ourselves in America until we create a truly multiracial democratic society, where no one is left behind, and it doesn't matter whether you're black or white, Latino or Asian-American or Native America, whether you're straight or gay. . And there's a way to do it. If you want to change things, you got to find a way to make some noise. You cannot be quiet.</p> 
<p>The lessons of March say, This is the way another generation did it, and you, too, can follow that path, studying the way of peace, love and nonviolence, and finding a way to get in the way. Finding a way to get in trouble?good trouble, necessary trouble.</p> 
<p>The book relates some of the experiences you had as a young person that led you to civil rights activism. Most people probably wouldn't think of raising chickens as a thing that would shape a civil rights leader.</p> 
<p>John Lewis: It may sound sort of silly, sort of strange, but I wouldn't be the person I am today if it was not for those chickens.</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>It was my calling to take care of these innocent little creatures. I'm convinced those chickens that I preached to in the '40s and the '50s tended to listen to me much better than some of my colleagues listen to me today in the Congress. Really! Most of those chickens were a little more productive. At least they produce eggs.</p> 
<p>They taught me discipline, they taught me patience, they taught me hard work and stick-to-it-ness.</p> 
<p>You talk about Emmett Till's death as a pivotal moment for you, and it seems like Trayvon Martin's death has been a touchstone for a new generation of activists. Yet both of their deaths came at a time when violence against young black men was not rare. Why do you think each case hit a nerve?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: I think there are certain periods in our history?just a spark. &amp;#160;</p> 
<p>I was 15 years old, working out in the field when I heard what happened. I kept thinking that it could happen to me, but especially to some of my cousins who lived in Buffalo, New York, who would come South in the summer to spend time with us.</p> 
<p>A few months later, when Rosa Parks refused to give up her seat, one thing she said in later years was, ?It's not just my feet that were tired, but also, I thought about Emmett Till.? I remember that very, very well.</p> 
<p>One of the things that the comic format does so well for this story is capture the violence and brutality that practitioners of nonviolence went through, both in preparation for and during actions. I particularly loved the sequence where one person quit training, saying it was too hard. Talk about the process of getting those moments on paper.</p> 
<p>John Lewis: We provided the words, but [the artist] Nate Powell?I love his capacity to capture the drama, to bring it to life, to make it real. You can see it; you can feel it. Even though I lived through it, to see it there makes the words sing.</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: This is very much centered around stories that I've heard the Congressman tell to all these people over the years. Nate lifted that off the paper and made it something at a whole other level. He's very good at finding a natural flow for your eye.</p> 
<p>We tried make sure that it wasn't just accurate for the sake of telling the story, but accurate for the sake of instructing, so that people who have never been to a nonviolent workshop could read and understand what one was. Nate really captured that.</p> 
<p>Another thing I think the book did well was capture the real work that went on behind the scenes. We're so rarely shown how many years of preparation and organizing went into making movements happen. I'd love to hear about the challenges of showing that part of the story.</p> 
<p>John Lewis: The planning, the training, the nitty-gritty organizing?you may wait for days or weeks or even months before you see something. But you do it. You're consistent and you're persistent, day in and day out.</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: You see how this work ethic has just been such an omnipresent force in the Congressman?s life since he was 17, 18 years old?or even before that, on the farm. I remember at several points asking ?What time did that take place?? and he'd be like ?Oh, 5:00, 6:00 a.m.? And you realize these are college kids. How many college kids today get up at 5:00 in the morning, much less to go to an organizing meeting before class?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: On April the 19, 1960, the attorney for the Nashville movement who had defended the students, his home was bombed around 6:00 a.m. And by 6:30 or 6:45 we were in a meeting. Students came from all over the city and we made a decision?it was a consensus?that we would have a march from the heart of the student community down to city hall. We sent the mayor of the city a telegram to meet us at high noon. There were more than 4,000 students saying, ?Mr. Mayor, do you favor desegregation of the lunch counters?? And the next day, the banner headline in the local paper read that the Mayor said Yes to the integration of the lunch counters.</p> 
<p>It was that sense that we had to act, we had to do something, we couldn't wait.</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: You always say, ?You gotta get up! You can't sleep through the revolution!?</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>The anniversary of the March on Washington is approaching quickly, and it's never seemed more relevant in my lifetime. We're seeing renewed attacks on civil rights and voting rights, along with a renewed movement for racial and economic justice. How are you feeling about the present day?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: In spite of all the problems and difficulties, all the apparent setbacks, delays, I feel very hopeful, very optimistic. I think we are in the process of building a very powerful movement.</p> 
<p>North Carolina's governor just yesterday signed into law one of the most unbelievable pieces of legislation that would lead to a systematic, deliberate effort to suppress the votes of minorities, young people and the elderly. But in spite of that, I'm hopeful that we're going to continue to push, and it's going to start the fire for a real movement. Look at what's happening in North Carolina now, the Moral Mondays. It's a good sign. It'll spread around, not just the South, but around America.</p> 
<p>What do you hope that some of those young people involved in North Carolina, camping out in the capitol in Florida, what do you hope that they take away from this comic?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: It's my hope that many of the young people will have an opportunity to read March and be inspired, and see another generation got out there and did what they could, and that we too must pick up and push the ball further down the road.</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: Some people have started getting advance copies, and one of them gave the book to his 9-year-old son.</p> 
<p>John Lewis: It's a white man, right?</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: Yes. His kid read the book, enjoyed it, had a little trouble with Emmett Till's death, but it resonated with him, and so now he's put on a suit and is marching around his house demanding equality.</p> 
<p>What does that say about what we have to look forward to?</p> 
<p>John Lewis: They shall lead the way. Like the children in Birmingham and Selma, Albany, Georgia and other parts. They led the way.</p> 
<p>Andrew Aydin: That's part of the bigger message that I think we'll really be able to get into after this book. Because the tactics that worked in Birmingham didn't necessarily work in Albany, and they had to change. Tactics in one city didn't work for every foe or every objective. From that original idea of the Montgomery bus boycott being useful as an example of successful nonviolent direct action, the whole premise is showing more and more examples of different tactics used to express different forms of opposition. As activists today look for new tactics to address their own opposition, they have inspiration and they see concrete examples of how things were reimagined but still stuck to the basic tenets, the philosophy and discipline of nonviolence.</p> 
<p>Panels from March: Book One courtesy of <a href="http://www.topshelfcomix.com/catalog/march/760" type="external">Top Shelf Productions</a>. All rights reserved.</p> 
<p>Like what you?ve read? <a href="https://secure.actblue.com/contribute/page/itt-subscription-offer?refcode=WS_ITT_Article_Footer&amp;amp;noskip=true" type="external">Subscribe to In These Times magazine</a>, or <a href="https://secure.actblue.com/contribute/page/support-in-these-times?refcode=WS_ITT_Article_Footer&amp;amp;noskip=true" type="external">make a tax-deductible donation to fund this reporting</a>.</p> 
<p><a href="http://sarahljaffe.com" type="external">Sarah Jaffe</a> is a former staff writer at In These Times and author of Necessary Trouble: Americans in Revolt , which Robin D.G. Kelley called ?The most compelling social and political portrait of our age.? You can follow her on Twitter <a href="http://twitter.com/sarahljaffe" type="external">@sarahljaffe</a>.</p></article>
<article id="0000094" title="Who Was Marjory Stoneman Douglas and Why Would Donald Trump Have Hated Her?"><p>Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School, the Parkland, Florida school, where fourteen kids and three adults were murdered by a maniac with an AR-15 assault weapon, has become a flash point in the debate for gun safety. That debate has been driven mainly by the student survivors themselves. Their passionate and articulate commitment to finally making change happen is one of the few signs of hope in the aftermath of yet another massacre.</p> 
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/NewsCorpse/posts/2045669458781172" type="external"></a></p> 
<p>However, little has been reported about the namesake of the school, Marjory Stoneman Douglas. As it turns out, she was an inspiring woman who was a fierce advocate for speaking out on matters of importance. During a life of activism and personal sacrifice she was quoted as saying ?You have to stand up for some things in this world.? She lived those words throughout her life and inspired others to do the same. In 1993 she received the Presidential Medal of Freedom from Bill Clinton. And while in the White House that day she was <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/before-the-massacre-at-the-school-named-in-her-honor-marjory-stoneman-douglas-was-there-when-the-brady-bill-was-signed?via=newsletter&amp;amp;source=Weekend" type="external">invited to witness</a> the signing of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brady_Handgun_Violence_Prevention_Act" type="external">Brady Bill</a>).</p> 
<p>But that isn?t the only eerie coincidence about Douglas and the specific focus of her activism. According to a <a href="https://www.nps.gov/ever/learn/historyculture/msdouglas.htm" type="external">biography</a> on the National Park Service website:</p> 
<p>Marjory Stoneman Douglas, born April 7, 1890 in Minneapolis, Minnesota, graduated from Wellesley with straight A?s with the elected honor of ?Class Orator.? That title proved to be prophetic.</p> 
<p>In 1915, following a brief and calamitous marriage, she arrived in Miami, working for her father at the Miami Herald. She worked first as a society reporter, then as an editorial page columnist, and later established herself as a writer of note. Here she took on the fight for feminism, racial justice, and conservation long before these causes became popular.</p> 
<p>So Douglas began her professional career as a journalist. Or as Donald Trump would say ?an <a href="" type="internal">enemy of the American people</a>.? She went on to champion women?s rights, something Trump has ridiculed and whose personal history of sexual harassment and assault demonstrates extreme disrespect and misogyny. Douglas was also a proponent of civil rights and racial justice. That contrasts with Trump?s overt bigotry and that of his base, which includes KKK and Nazi leaders and organizations. And finally, Douglas was best known for her environmental activism and her work to conserve the Florida Everglades. She wrote a landmark book on the subject titled, <a href="http://amzn.to/2ETIWrQ" type="external">The Everglades: River of Grass</a>.</p> 
<p>Trump surely doesn?t anything about Douglas or her lifelong dedication to service and social change. But if he did he would certainly despise her and attack her with a flurry of furious and derogatory tweets. He insult her and make up stupid nicknames. And he would express his opposition to everything she stood for. All of this adds a rather somber poignancy to the tragedy in Parkland. But it may explain the stirring and righteous reaction from the students who probably do know Douglas and her work. They are likely inspired by quotes like this one: ?I believe that life should be lived so vividly and so intensely that thoughts of another life, or of a longer life, are not necessary.?? And it may explain the heartrending intensity of their oratory as exemplified in this speech by student Emma Gonzalez:</p> 
<p>How Fox News Deceives and Controls Their Flock: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00QSSMOES/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00QSSMOES&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=newscorpsecom-20&amp;amp;linkId=TLI6JC2OYE22MUTS" type="external">Fox Nation vs. Reality: The Fox News Cult of Ignorance.</a> Available now at Amazon.</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000100" published-at="2018-01-16" title="Social Democrats push back against German ?grand? coalition"><p>BERLIN (AP) ? The head of Germany?s center-left Social Democrats lobbied party members Tuesday to vote in favor of opening coalition talks with Chancellor Angela Merkel?s conservatives, amid strong opposition from grassroots members.</p> 
<p>Martin Schulz made the rounds in the populous state of North-Rhine Westphalia, talking with party members to push for their approval at a party convention Sunday to open formal negotiations with Merkel?s Union bloc.</p> 
<p>A rejection of talks would be a setback for both <a href="" type="internal">Schulz and Merkel</a> , who has already failed to forge a coalition with two smaller parties.</p> 
<p>The Social Democrats and the Union bloc, who have governed Germany in a ?grand coalition? since 2013, suffered heavy losses in September?s national election.</p> 
<p>In non-binding votes, Social Democrats in the smaller states of Berlin and Saxony-Anhalt have indicated they?ll vote against opening coalition talks, while party members in Brandenburg voted in favor.</p> 
<p>In North Rhine-Westphalia Schulz met with party members in Dortmund before heading to the state capital Duesseldorf for similar meetings in the evening.</p> 
<p>The Social Democrats in North Rhine-Westphalia aren?t planning any poll ahead of time on whether to approve the talks, the dpa news agency reported, but with about a quarter of the delegates to the Sunday convention their support is key.</p> 
<p>BERLIN (AP) ? The head of Germany?s center-left Social Democrats lobbied party members Tuesday to vote in favor of opening coalition talks with Chancellor Angela Merkel?s conservatives, amid strong opposition from grassroots members.</p> 
<p>Martin Schulz made the rounds in the populous state of North-Rhine Westphalia, talking with party members to push for their approval at a party convention Sunday to open formal negotiations with Merkel?s Union bloc.</p> 
<p>A rejection of talks would be a setback for both <a href="" type="internal">Schulz and Merkel</a> , who has already failed to forge a coalition with two smaller parties.</p> 
<p>The Social Democrats and the Union bloc, who have governed Germany in a ?grand coalition? since 2013, suffered heavy losses in September?s national election.</p> 
<p>In non-binding votes, Social Democrats in the smaller states of Berlin and Saxony-Anhalt have indicated they?ll vote against opening coalition talks, while party members in Brandenburg voted in favor.</p> 
<p>In North Rhine-Westphalia Schulz met with party members in Dortmund before heading to the state capital Duesseldorf for similar meetings in the evening.</p> 
<p>The Social Democrats in North Rhine-Westphalia aren?t planning any poll ahead of time on whether to approve the talks, the dpa news agency reported, but with about a quarter of the delegates to the Sunday convention their support is key.</p></article>
<article id="0000103" published-at="2018-07-14" title="GOP?s Top Campaign Whisperers for 2012 Presidential Candidates"><p><a href="/content/dailybeast/cheats/2011/10/12/mitt-romney-outshines-debate-opponents.html" type="external">Mitt Romney</a>?s economic advisers are as squarely establishment as he is.</p> 
<p>This is reassuring to old-school conservatives like <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/04/opinion/brooks-in-defense-of-romney.html" type="external">New York Times columnist David Brooks</a>, who calls them the ?gold standard of adviser teams,? and it could appeal to middle-of-the-road voters in a general election. They aren?t purists or populists, but then, Republican primary voters already know Romney?s not that guy.</p> 
<p>The people who whisper advice into a candidate?s ear don?t usually get much attention, but they were a hot topic at <a href="/content/dailybeast/articles/2011/10/11/gop-debate-bloomberg-washington-post-wbin-tv-daily-beast-contributors-respond.html" type="external">Tuesday?s GOP debate on the economy</a>. Asked whom they?d rely on for economic guidance, the candidates gave answers ranging from ?the American people? (Herman Cain) to ?my own father? (Jon Huntsman) to pioneering conservative economist Milton Friedman (who is unavailable; he died in 2006). That last came from Romney, perhaps trying to soften the impact of who his advisers really are?two Ivy League academics and two Capitol Hill veterans who are as mainstream as they come.</p> 
<p><a href="/content/dailybeast/articles/2011/09/27/rick-perry-s-missing-platform-in-the-2012-presidential-policy-wars.html" type="external">Rick Perry</a>, who will unveil his economic plan starting with an energy speech on Friday, did not get a chance to answer that question during the New Hampshire debate. But his campaign told me Wednesday that Steve Forbes is among those advising the Texas governor. Forbes, chairman and editor in chief of Forbes Media, ran for president in 1996 and 2000 and pushed both times for a flat tax, <a href="http://www.issues2000.org/Celeb/Steve_Forbes_Social_Security.htm" type="external">private Social Security accounts</a>, and medical savings accounts.</p> 
<p>The most obscure name that came up onstage was Rich Lowrie, a Cleveland-area wealth manager for Wells Fargo?not to be confused with National Review editor Rich Lowry. Lowrie is Cain?s senior economic adviser and the man who helped him work up the <a href="/content/dailybeast/articles/2011/10/12/michael-tomasky-herman-cain-s-9-9-9-plan-revolutionary-for-the-rich.html" type="external">9-9-9 plan that?s drawing new scrutiny</a> as Cain surges and even leads in some state and national polls. Lowrie has a degree in accounting, not economics, from Case Western Reserve University. He served three years on the advisory board of the conservative group Americans for Prosperity, backed by the billionaire Koch brothers, at a time when Cain headed its ?Prosperity Expansion Project.? Lowrie is now on the <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rich-lowrie/a/74b/805" type="external">advisory board of the American Conservative Union</a>.</p> 
<p>The 9-9-9 plan would replace the current tax code with a 9 percent national sales tax, a 9 percent individual income tax, and a 9 percent corporate income tax. Lowrie has been <a href="http://twitter.com/#%21/richlowrie" type="external">playing defense on Twitter</a> as Cain?s rivals go on the attack. It was back to the future?and supply-side economics?Wednesday when Lowrie retweeted praise from Karol Hansen, a Southern California wife, mother, Sunday school teacher, and author of a children?s book called <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B003C8AWQ4/thedaibea-20/" type="external">Easter Egg Hunt for Jesus</a>. ?I respect Art Laffer who was one of Reagan?s economic advisors and he says he likes the 9-9-9 plan very much!? she tweeted.</p> 
<p>Cain, who is running a shoestring campaign, said he has other advisers but declined to name them.</p> 
<p>The Romney brain trust includes Columbia Business School dean Glenn Hubbard and Harvard professor Gregory Mankiw, each of whom served as chief economic adviser to George W. Bush. Also on the team are two former swing-state members of Congress: former Sen. Jim Talent of Missouri, now a defense expert at the Heritage Foundation, and former Rep. Vin Weber of Minnesota, a lobbyist and GOP strategist. All were lying low on Wednesday.</p> 
<p>Both economists have displayed flashes of ideological independence. Hubbard was influential in designing Bush?s signature 2001 and 2003 tax cuts. But he has said he grew uneasy about the tax cuts as deficit spending surged during Bush?s eight years on such big-ticket items as the Medicare prescription drug benefit. Hubbard <a href="http://voices.washingtonpost.com/ezra-klein/2010/12/hubbard_i_wouldnt_support_a_pe.html" type="external">told The Washington Post?s Ezra Klein</a> last December that he does not support a permanent extension of the Bush-era rates.</p> 
<p>In a <a href="http://finance.fortune.cnn.com/2011/07/11/glenn-hubbard-why-raising-taxes-wont-work/" type="external">July interview with Fortune</a>, Hubbard said he was ?mystified by both sides? emphasis on the Bush tax cuts as if those are religious articles to either attack at one side or defend on the other. What we need is tax reform?? He suggested going after deductions and other ?tax expenditures? to wring more revenue from the tax system in the near term.</p> 
<p>That?s what Romney did as governor of Massachusetts? <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/02/us/politics/romneys-strategies-as-governor-bucked-his-ceo-image.html?pagewanted=all" type="external">scour the tax code</a> for corporate loopholes?and it did not endear him to conservatives or the business community. Still, some national conservatives, such as Sen. Tom Coburn (R-OK), have been open to the idea, given the soaring national debt and Republican resistance to raising tax rates.</p> 
<p>Documentary lovers may recall Hubbard from his <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zlIoeTObmEk" type="external">cameo in the 2010 film Inside Job</a>. He lost his temper on camera when director Charles Ferguson asked him if there was a potential conflict of interest in his unreported consulting work for financial-services firms. ?This isn?t a deposition, sir. I was polite enough to give you time, foolishly, I now see. But you have three more minutes. Give it your best shot,? Hubbard snapped.</p> 
<p>Start and finish your day with the top stories from The Daily Beast.</p> 
<p>A speedy, smart summary of all the news you need to know (and nothing you don't).</p> 
<p>The academic had another moment in the spotlight at Tuesday night?s Washington Post/Bloomberg debate, when Perry told Romney that Hubbard, ?your chief economic adviser? who you know well, he said that Romneycare was Obamacare. And Romneycare has driven the cost of small-business insurance premiums up by 14 percent over the national average??</p> 
<p>Romney said his plan is not like Obama?s and added that ?Glenn Hubbard is a fine fellow.? But a 2010 paper co-authored by Hubbard backs up Perry?s points. ?Because the [Massachusetts] Plan?s main components are the same as those of the new health reform law, the effects of the Plan provide a window onto the country?s future,? the authors wrote. They said the Massachusetts experience suggests that federal policymakers ?should be concerned? about the impact of the law on the cost of private insurance.</p> 
<p>Mankiw succeeded Hubbard in the Bush White House despite objections on the right. <a href="http://old.nationalreview.com/moore/moore022803b.asp" type="external">Stephen Moore at National Review</a> upbraided him for calling Ronald Reagan?s supply-side advisers ?charlatans and cranks? and said it didn?t matter if his views had since changed because he had already been ?indoctrinating young economists with wrongheaded thinking.? <a href="http://gregmankiw.blogspot.com/2007/11/anti-mankiw.html" type="external">Mankiw says</a> he?s also been attacked from the left, by liberals who say his ideas are right-wing propaganda. He says his teaching reflects ?the economic mainstream,? which he defines as slightly right of center.</p> 
<p>As for Romney?s other two advisers, Talent is a supporter of robust defense spending whose views are reflected in Romney?s call to build more ships, ramp up missile defense, add 100,000 troops, and raise military spending from 3.8 percent to 4 percent of gross domestic product. Weber is the fifth most influential lobbyist in Washington, or at least he was in 2007, <a href="http://www.washingtonian.com/articles/mediapolitics/4264.html" type="external">according to Washingtonian magazine</a>. Being a lobbyist is not a selling point, but Weber has another credential, one that Romney sorely needs. Elected to the House in 1980, he was a soldier in Reagan?s supply-side revolution.</p> 
<p>In the end, Romney will win or lose the nomination on his own. But his gold-plated economic team may give conservatives yet another reason to be wary of him.</p></article>
<article id="0000106" published-at="2009-02-18" title="Al Sharpton Is Wrong About the Monkey Cartoon"><p>Photo from flickr user floridapfe</p> 
<p></p> 
<p>In today?s New York Post there?s a Sean Delonas <a href="http://www.nypost.com/delonas/2009/02/02182009.jpg" type="external">cartoon</a> that shows two policemen standing over a dead chimpanzee. One is holding a handgun while the other says, ?They?ll have to find someone else to write the next stimulus bill.?</p> 
<p>Al Sharpton is very offended. But he shouldn?t be because the cartoon isn?t offensive, unless you?re an ape.</p> 
<p>Sharpton issued a statement <a href="http://www.tmz.com/2009/02/18/al-sharpton-monkey-cartoon-obama/" type="external">saying</a>:</p> 
<p>The cartoon in today?s New York Post is troubling at best given the historic racist attacks of African-Americans as being synonymous with monkeys. One has to question whether the cartoonist is making a less than casual reference to this when in the cartoon they have police saying after shooting a chimpanzee that ?Now they will have to find someone else to write the stimulus bill.?</p> 
<p>Being that the stimulus bill has been the first legislative victory of President Barack Obama (the first African American president) and has become synonymous with him it is not a reach to wonder are they inferring that a monkey wrote the last bill?</p> 
<p>Well actually, yes, it is a reach. That?s why the New York Post refuses to apologize and issued this <a href="http://newsblogs.chicagotribune.com/race/2009/02/outraged-readers-complain-about-chimp-cartoon-.html" type="external">statement</a>:</p> 
<p>The cartoon is a clear parody of a current news event, to wit the shooting of a violent chimpanzee in Connecticut. It broadly mocks Washington?s efforts to revive the economy. Again, Al Sharpton reveals himself as nothing more than a publicity opportunist.</p> 
<p>I?ll leave Sharpton?s motivation alone, but this whole thing seems a little puzzling. Consider three recent events.</p> 
<p>Guess which one of these is irrelevant to the cartoon? If you picked&amp;#160; #1, you?re right. This cartoon has nothing to do with the ethnicity of Obama?s father and everything to do with the fact that the stimulus bill is messy. So messy, in fact, that it could have been written by a chimpanzee.</p> 
<p>The truth is, it?s not a good cartoon. Because it is an awkward attempt to combine two unrelated news stories, it doesn?t resonate, not in the way that <a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_q0ioDxOSoAA/Rwuul_0jFnI/AAAAAAAAABA/f1eVEc3HV2A/s200/nycover3.jpg" type="external">this</a> really wonderful cartoon does. You many not even get the cartoon at all (stimulus=monkey?), but that?s understandable because it?s not that funny; it?s just not racist either. Sometimes a joke about monkeys is, well, just a joke about monkeys.</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000109" published-at="2016-03-06" title="Ad Revenue Growth Helps Google's Second-Quarter Profit Trump Estimates"><p>Google Inc's posted a better-than-expected quarterly profit for the first time in the last six quarters, helped by strong growth in advertising revenue.</p> 
<p>The company's shares rose 7.5 percent in after-market trading on Thursday.</p> 
<p>Continue Reading Below</p> 
<p>Advertising revenue rose 11 percent to $16.02 billion in the second quarter ended June 30 from a year earlier, while the number of ads, or paid clicks, rose 18 percent, the company said.</p> 
<p>Advertisers pay Google only if a user clicks on one of their ads. "Cost per click", or the average price of online ads, fell 11 percent in the quarter, but was more than offset by the increase in ad volumes.</p> 
<p>Google's ad revenue has been under pressure from consumers accessing its online services on mobiles devices such as smartphones and tablets, where ad rates are typically lower.</p> 
<p><a href="http://listings.findthecompany.com/l/8520977/Google-Inc-in-Mountain-View-CA" type="external">Google Inc. - Earnings Surprise | FindTheCompany Opens a New Window.</a>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^https:/.test(d.location)?'https':'http';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+"://cdn1.findthebest.com/rx/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","ftb-widgetjs");</p> 
<p>The company's consolidated revenue rose 11 percent to $17.73 billion in the quarter. (http://bit.ly/1CGbMq5)</p> 
<p>Advertisement</p> 
<p>Net income rose to $3.93 billion, or $4.93 per Class A and B share, from $3.35 billion, or $4.88 per share.</p> 
<p>Excluding items, Google earned $6.99 per share.</p> 
<p>Analysts on average had expected a profit of $6.70 per share, and revenue of $17.75 billion, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.</p> 
<p>(Reporting by Anya George Tharakan in Bengaluru; Editing by Maju Samuel and Simon Jennings)</p></article>
<article id="0000111" published-at="2012-10-18" title="IVN Launches Local Edition of Non-Partisan News Platform The Treatment: Civil Discourse The Technology: Localization The Risk: Abuse The Protection: Etiquette"><p><a href="" type="internal"></a>Party central committees, partisan special interests, and courts overseen by party-appointed judges have <a href="" type="internal">steadily reframed election law</a> in such a way that the failure to affiliate with one of the two institutionalized political parties voids an individual?s ability to have meaningful participation in the political process. As a result, legislators are held accountable only by their partisan base.</p> 
<p>The partisan consolidation of power has accelerated rapidly over the past 75 years. Attempts to change our election laws and inform voters will not alone stop the polarization of our political system. Even traditional media has reorganized the dialogue around a superficial two-sided debate and accepted the notion that a virtual pre-requisite for full voter participation is party affiliation.</p> 
<p>To change the political process, we have to start with the political dialogue. <a href="" type="internal">IVN.us</a>&amp;#160;was established to promote such a change. The goal is to create a news source where the news is unfiltered by partisan interests. In short, IVN.us is an online news platform for communication between independent-minded voters, public officials, civic leaders, and journalists.</p> 
<p>The news network was BETA tested at the end of 2011, and Phase 1 was officially launched in January 2012. Today, IVN reaches over a million people online each week. Now, we are bringing IVN to the local level.</p> 
<p>On October 17th, 2012, IVN launched the first local prototype in its hometown:&amp;#160; <a href="" type="internal">IVN San Diego Edition</a>. In the old days, starting a news outlet was out of the question; unless you were a billionaire. IVN has taken today?s technology and created a platform that is more powerful, more dynamic, and more open to credible journalists than anything ever built. We will bring this technology to other cities that share a common desire for good and diverse journalism. And it won?t take a billionaire to get us there. Just you.</p> 
<p>The biggest risk of an open platform is abuse of its capabilities. The biggest challenge is maintaining credibility amid forces that will see IVN as competition and who don?t hold themselves to the&amp;#160; <a href="" type="internal">IVN etiquette</a>. We are qualified to overcome these challenges because we have gotten this far with a couple computers and some big hearts. We will overcome these risks and challenges with the support of people like you will.</p> 
<p>IVN?s reputation, credibility, and status as a news source are preserved through its adherence to a published etiquette and editorial guideline. These guidelines ensure that both contributors and readers benefit from robust and diverse content in a civil environment.</p> 
<p>1. No personal attacks.&amp;#160; 2. No self-promotion.&amp;#160; 3. Sources must be substantiated. 4. No partisan-based attacks.</p> 
<p>Please join us by making a pledge to IVN so that we can elevate the level of civil discourse and break down the barriers to participation in both news and politics.</p> 
<p>And if you haven?t already, please follow us on&amp;#160; <a href="https://www.facebook.com/independentvoternetwork?fref=ts" type="external">Facebook</a>,&amp;#160; <a href="https://twitter.com/IVNetwork" type="external">Twitter</a>, and&amp;#160; <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/101219378970530930435/posts" type="external">Google+</a>&amp;#160;if we haven?t asked enough of you already.</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000113" published-at="2017-05-22" title="Arms Deal Stories Omit War Crimes Arms Will Be Used For"><p>Reports on the Trump/Saudi arm deals focused on who would get paid?and ignored who it would cost.</p> 
<p>The Trump administration wrapped up a weapons deal with the Saudi Arabian government this week that will be worth up to <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/05/20/us-saudi-arabia-seal-weapons-deal-worth-nearly-110-billion-as-trump-begins-visit.html" type="external">$350 billion over the next ten years</a>. News of the deal came as Trump visited Riyadh and paid fealty to one of the United States? most enduring allies in the Middle East.</p> 
<p>The vast majority of the reports on the topic, however, omitted a rather key piece of context?namely, whom the weapons will be used to kill.</p> 
<p>The famine and brutal two-year-long war in Yemen being waged by the Saudis that has killed over 10,000 civilians wasn?t mentioned once in reports of the $300 billion deal to Saudi Arabia by CNN ( <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2017/05/19/politics/jared-kushner-saudi-arms-deal-lockheed-martin/" type="external">5/19/17</a>, <a href="http://money.cnn.com/video/news/2017/05/20/trump-arms-deal-saudi-arabia.cnnmoney/" type="external">5/20/17</a>), Washington Post &amp;#160;( <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/us-saudi-arabia-reach-tentative-pacts-potentially-worth-110-billion/2017/05/20/2a919826-3d91-11e7-9e48-c4f199710b69_story.html?utm_term=.3b890942b931" type="external">5/19/17</a>), The Independent ( <a href="https://www.independent.co.ug/us-saudi-agree-arms-deals-worth-almost-110-billion/" type="external">5/19/17</a>), New York Daily News ( <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/politics/trump-closes-110-billion-military-arms-deal-saudi-arabia-article-1.3181686" type="external">5/20/17</a>), CNBC ( <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/05/20/us-saudi-arabia-seal-weapons-deal-worth-nearly-110-billion-as-trump-begins-visit.html" type="external">5/20/17</a>, <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/05/22/defense-stocks-rally-on-110-billion-us-saudi-arabia-weapons-deal.html" type="external">5/22/17</a>), CBS News ( <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-signs-110-billion-arms-deal-with-saudi-arabia/" type="external">5/20/17</a>), Business Insider ( <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/ap-us-to-announce-110-billion-saudi-arms-sale-as-trump-visits-2017-5" type="external">5/20/17</a>), Time ( <a href="http://time.com/4787238/us-saudi-arabia-arms-deal/?xid=time_socialflow_twitter" type="external">5/20/17</a>), Fox News ( <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-arrives-to-saudi-arabia-for-his-first-international-trip-since-taking-office.html" type="external">5/20/17</a>), Reuters ( <a href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/uk-usa-trump-saudi-deals-idUKKCN18G0L3?utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+Trending+Content&amp;amp;utm_content=5920680204d3013d68debcf3&amp;amp;utm_medium=trueAnthem&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter" type="external">5/20/17</a>), ABC News ( <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-signs-110-billion-arms-deal-saudi-arabia/story?id=47531180" type="external">5/20/17</a>), Fortune Magazine ( <a href="http://fortune.com/2017/05/20/donald-trump-saudi-arabia-trip/" type="external">5/20/17</a>) or Chicago Tribune ( <a href="" type="external">5/20/17</a>).</p> 
<p>The arms deal was typically framed in vague ?security? terms, with an emphasis on Saudi Arabia?s role in fighting ?terrorism? (e.g., ?The White House says the package includes defense equipment? to help the Arab nation and the rest of the Gulf region fight against terrorism??Fox News, <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-arrives-to-saudi-arabia-for-his-first-international-trip-since-taking-office.html" type="external">5/20/17</a>), despite the fact that the bulk of its military activity is focused on bombing Shia Houthi rebels in Yemen that have nothing to do with terrorism as such.</p> 
<p>That hundreds of billions of arms would be going to Al Qaeda?s allies wasn?t touched on in reports on the arms deal.</p> 
<p>Indeed, the head of Al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20170501110714/http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/al-qaida-leader-group-fought-alongside-us-backed-47125267" type="external">claimed earlier this month</a> his forces were ?fighting alongside? the Saudi-backed Yemeni government. This detail was also omitted from reports on the arms deal, presumably because it would messy up the ?Saudi Arabia?as?partner?in?War on Terror? narrative the press was uncritically echoing.</p> 
<p>In his report on the arms deal, the Washington Post?s Steven Mufson ( <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/us-saudi-arabia-reach-tentative-pacts-potentially-worth-110-billion/2017/05/20/2a919826-3d91-11e7-9e48-c4f199710b69_story.html?utm_term=.d253455a7d7c" type="external">5/21/17</a>) got quotes from the CEO of Lockheed Martin and reps from General Electric and private-equity firm Blackstone, but found no time to interview a human rights expert or aid worker or victim of Saudi bombing of Yemen; indeed, that bombing wasn?t even mentioned. Likewise, CNBC ( <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/05/22/defense-stocks-rally-on-110-billion-us-saudi-arabia-weapons-deal.html" type="external">5/22/17</a>) issued a sexed-up press release Monday morning about how ?defense stocks soar to all-time highs on $110 billion US/Saudi Arabia weapons deal??with no mention of whom, exactly, said weapons were killing.</p> 
<p>Many outlets went with the ?jobs? frame, echoing the White House narrative that the selling of arms to a dictatorship waging a brutal war on a neighboring country was, in fact, good because it ?created jobs.?</p> 
<p>A Trump campaign ad wouldn?t have framed the issue differently than this CBS Miami report.</p> 
<p>?Trump Says Arms Deal He Signed With Saudi Arabia Will Create Jobs,? was the NPR headline ( <a href="http://www.npr.org/2017/05/20/529309106/trump-says-arms-deal-he-signed-with-saudi-arabia-will-create-jobs" type="external">5/20/17</a>). ?Trump Says Saudi Arabia Deal Will Create ?Jobs, Jobs, Jobs,?? CBS Miami ( <a href="http://miami.cbslocal.com/2017/05/20/trump-saudi-arabia-deal-jobs-jobs-jobs/" type="external">5/20/17</a>) reported. Neither of these reports used the words ?Yemen? or ?bombing? or ?famine.?</p> 
<p>To the extent the Saudi bombing of Yemen was gestured at, it was in vague, Risk game?like terms about how Saudi Arabia was a ?check? against ?Iranian aggression??an opaque framing that reduces all Shia populations in the Middle East into mindless Iranian drones in urgent need of an application of Saudi munitions.</p> 
<p>?The United States likes to see Saudi Arabia with a strong military because it is seen as a counter to the forces of Iran,? CNN Newsroom ( <a href="http://www.cnn.com/TRANSCRIPTS/1705/20/cnr.01.html" type="external">5/20/17</a>) euphemistically explained. It?s not spelled out that ?counter? here means bombing one of the poorest countries on earth for over two years, unleashing what the UN <a href="http://foreignpolicy.com/2017/03/15/yemen-famine-humanitarian-relief-conflict-food-insecurity-casualties-of-conflict-saudi-led-intervention/" type="external">calls</a> ?famine-like? conditions affecting nearly 7 million people.</p> 
<p>In stark contrast, <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-syria-russia-arms-idUSBREA0G0MN20140117" type="external">reports</a> <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-syria-crisis-russia-arms-insight-idUSBRE97S0WW20130829" type="external">in</a> <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/08/29/world/meast/syria-iran-china-russia-supporters/" type="external">US</a> <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/05/17/world/middleeast/russia-provides-syria-with-advanced-missiles.html" type="external">media</a> <a href="http://a.abcnews.com/International/obama-calls-syrias-assad-step-freezes-assets/story?id=14330428" type="external">of</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/russian-iranian-technology-is-boosting-assads-assault-on-syrian-rebels/2013/06/01/aefad718-ca26-11e2-9f1a-1a7cdee20287_story.html?utm_term=.839344623a57" type="external">Russian</a> <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/syria-and-iraq-full-of-russian-iranian-and-chinese-weapons-2015-4" type="external">arms</a> <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/russia-to-sell-mig-jet-fighters-to-syria-jet-maker-says/" type="external">sales</a> to the Assad government in Syria?even before Russia directly entered the war in September 2015?would always mention the stakes of the deals in terms of human life. Weapons sales by other countries are put in clear moral terms?as they should be. Those by the United States are sterilized, rendered abstract by omitting the deaths that will inevitably result.</p> 
<p>The New York Times ( <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/15/world/middleeast/trump-yemen-saudi-arabia.html" type="external">5/15/17</a>) did mention the famine and war in Yemen in the context of the arms deal last week, but one article on the subject from Thursday ( <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/18/world/middleeast/trump-saudi-arabia-summit.html?_r=0" type="external">5/18/17</a>), for unknown reasons, <a href="https://twitter.com/aaronjmate/status/865636012755566592" type="external">removed</a> this passage expressly noting the Saudis? history of buying US weapons:</p> 
<p>The Saudis have spent a fortune on US weapons over the years, and a series of new deals that could be worth more than $300 billion over the next decade are close to completion, Reuters reported this month.</p> 
<p>You can see the original, as reprinted in the Boston Globe, <a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/news/world/2017/05/18/saudi-arabia-will-give-trump-royal-welcome-ignore-his-slights/LeqkorxmQ67HwvgXLf1GfI/story.html" type="external">here</a>.</p> 
<p>As of Monday afternoon, no major newspaper?New York Times, Washington Post, Wall Street Journal, USA Today, LA Times, Chicago Tribune or Daily News?has run an editorial condemning Trump for cozying up with and selling massive amounts of arms to the Saudi dictatorship. As FAIR noted last week <a href="" type="internal">(5/17/17</a>), this outrage remains solely directed at dictatorships not in good standing with the US State Department.</p> 
<p>Such is most reporting on the US?s relationship with Saudi Arabia. The human rights framework so much of the pundit class lives by?the moral positioning that gives the US the unique right to interfere in conflicts throughout the globe?is suddenly, and without explanation, suspended. The US backs Saudi war crimes despite their brutality, never because of it. It sells arms in hopes they will reform, never because they have.</p> 
<p>And unlike our enemies, no one in particular is responsible. No ?Salman regime did X,? no ?forces loyal to Salman regime bombed Y.? Saudi Arabia remains a game of moral hot potato, no one is to blame and, somehow, everyone is a reformer.</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p></article>
<article id="0000115" published-at="2018-01-14" title="Winning numbers drawn in 'Megabucks Plus' game"><p>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) _ The winning numbers in Saturday evening's drawing of the "Megabucks Plus" game were:</p> 
<p>04-11-39-40-41, Megaball: 3</p> 
<p>(four, eleven, thirty-nine, forty, forty-one; Megaball: three)</p> 
<p>Estimated jackpot: $4.7 million</p> 
<p>CONCORD, N.H. (AP) _ The winning numbers in Saturday evening's drawing of the "Megabucks Plus" game were:</p> 
<p>04-11-39-40-41, Megaball: 3</p> 
<p>(four, eleven, thirty-nine, forty, forty-one; Megaball: three)</p> 
<p>Estimated jackpot: $4.7 million</p></article>
<article id="0000117" published-at="2018-01-15" title="Trump has kept many promises during his first year in office"><p>WASHINGTON (AP) ? President Donald Trump often brags that he's done more in his first year in office than any other president. That's a spectacular stretch.</p> 
<p>But while he's fallen short on many measures and has a strikingly thin legislative record, Trump has followed through on dozens of his campaign promises, overhauling the country's tax system, changing the U.S. posture abroad and upending the lives of hundreds of thousands of immigrants.</p> 
<p>A year in, Trump is no closer to making Mexico pay for a border wall than when he made supporters swoon with that promise at those rollicking campaign rallies of 2016.</p> 
<p>He's run into legislative roadblocks ? from fellow Republicans, no less ? at big moments, which is why the Obama-era health law survives, wounded but still insuring millions. His own administration's sloppy start explains why none of the laws he pledged to sign in his first 100 days came to reality then and why most are still aspirational.</p> 
<p>Nevertheless, Trump has nailed the tax overhaul, his only historic legislative accomplishment to date, won confirmation of a conservative Supreme Court justice and other federal judges, and used his executive powers with vigor to slice regulations and pull the U.S. away from international accords he assailed as a candidate.</p> 
<p>Courts tied his most provocative actions on immigration and Muslim entry in knots, but illegal border crossings appear to be at historic lows.</p> 
<p>The upshot? For all his rogue tendencies, Trump has shaped up as a largely conventional Republican president when measured by his promises kept and in motion.</p> 
<p>The Twitter version of Trump may be jazzed with braggadocio about the size of his (nonexistent) nuclear button and his "very stable genius." But the ledger of actions taken is recognizable to Washington: mainstream Republican tax cuts, pro-business policy (with exceptions on trade), curbs on environmental regulation and an approach to health care that's been in the GOP playbook for years.</p> 
<p>That's as of today and this moment. With Trump, you never know about tomorrow.</p> 
<p>A look at some of his campaign promises and what's happened with them:</p> 
<p>TAXES</p> 
<p>Trump and congressional Republicans delivered on an overhaul that substantially lowers corporate taxes and cuts personal income taxes, as promised. It's sizable but not everything Trump said it would be, and it is more tilted to the wealthy than he promised or will admit. He promised a 15 percent tax rate for corporations and settled for 21 percent, still a major drop from 35 percent. He promised three tax brackets; there are still seven. He did not eliminate the estate tax or the alternative minimum tax as he said he would. Fewer people will be subject to those taxes, however, at least temporarily.</p> 
<p>"Everybody is getting a tax cut, especially the middle class," he said in the campaign. Most will; some will pay more.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>TRADE</p> 
<p>Trump made good on his promise to withdraw the U.S. from the Trans-Pacific Partnership trade agreement and to reopen the North American Free Trade Agreement in search of a better deal.</p> 
<p>He's let China off the hook, though, on his oft-repeated threat during the campaign to brand Beijing a currency manipulator, a step toward potentially hefty penalties on Chinese imports and a likely spark for a trade war.</p> 
<p>"We're like the piggy bank that's being robbed," he said of the trade relationship, which has tipped even more in China's favor since. Trump now threatens trade punishment if China does not sufficiently cooperate in reining in North Korea.</p> 
<p>Trump promised to impose a 35 percent tariff on goods from U.S. companies that ship production abroad. He's not delivered on that. Instead, his tax plan aims to encourage companies to stay in the U.S. with the lower tax rate and to entice those operating abroad to come home by letting them repatriate their profits in the U.S. at a temporarily discounted rate. His approach so far is all carrot, no stick.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>IMMIGRATION</p> 
<p>Candidate Trump rocked the political landscape when he proposed a temporary ban on all non-U.S. Muslims entering the country. While he's long backed away from such talk, Trump has worked since his first days in office to impose new restrictions on tourists and immigrants, signing executive orders that would have made good on his anti-immigration promises had those orders not been blocked by courts.</p> 
<p>He's now succeeded in banning the entry of citizens from several Muslim-majority countries and in severely curbing refugee admissions. He's tried to deny certain federal money for cities that refuse to cooperate with federal immigration authorities.</p> 
<p>Trump is now deep in negotiations over an immigration deal that could deliver on other promises, including money for the border wall with Mexico and overhauling the legal immigration system to make it harder for immigrants to sponsor their families. That's in exchange for extending protections for hundreds of thousands of young people brought to the country illegally as children. They are protections he once slammed as an "illegal" amnesty and pledged to end.</p> 
<p>Mexico still isn't ponying up money for the wall.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>ENERGY AND THE ENVIRONMENT</p> 
<p>Trump promised aggressive action on the energy front and has pursued that.</p> 
<p>He announced his intention to take the U.S. out of the Paris climate-change accord. He gave swift approval to the Keystone XL and Dakota Access pipelines stalled by President Barack Obama, moved to shrink protected national monument lands in Utah and Arizona, and acted to lift restrictions on mining coal and coastal drilling for oil and natural gas.</p> 
<p>A provision in the new tax law opens the long-protected Arctic National Wildlife Refuge to drilling.</p> 
<p>As other countries turn harder toward green energy, Trump is making fossil fuels the centerpiece of his drive toward energy independence ? a benchmark that Obama closed in on during an era of surging natural gas development.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>HEALTH CARE</p> 
<p>Probably nothing exemplifies frustrated ambition more than the Obama health law Republicans have been trying to dismantle ever since it was enacted in 2010. Trump has declared it dead many times ? he just never got around to killing it.</p> 
<p>He made this overpromise in the campaign: "My first day in office, I'm going to ask Congress to put a bill on my desk getting rid of this disastrous law and replacing it with reforms that expand choice, freedom, affordability. You're going to have such great health care at a tiny fraction of the cost. It's going to be so easy."</p> 
<p>That hasn't happened.</p> 
<p>Republicans took several runs at repealing and replacing the law last year, only to fall short. The December tax law, though, is knocking out a pillar. As of 2019, the requirement to carry health insurance or pay a fine will be gone.</p> 
<p>Trump has come out with a proposed regulation to promote the sale of health plans across state lines. The goal is to make it easier for associations to sponsor plans that are cheaper than Affordable Care Act policies but don't have to meet all consumer protection and benefit requirements of that law.</p> 
<p>Insurance industry groups, patient groups and some state regulators are wary of the idea and see little chance it can make more than a dent in the ranks of the uninsured (nearly 30 million). Easing restrictions on the sale of health insurance across state lines has been a longtime mainstream conservative goal.</p> 
<p>He also promised to authorize Medicare to negotiate lower prescription drug prices. It hasn't been done.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>'AMERICA FIRST' ABROAD</p> 
<p>Trump promised swift victory over the Islamic State group. Over the past year, U.S. and coalition-backed local forces in Iraq and Syria did deal a crushing blow to IS, ousting the militants from most of the territory they once held. The success built on the strategy of the Obama administration to work with and through local forces. Trump did relax restrictions on the number of U.S. troops who could be deployed both to Iraq and Syria, and that aided the final push.</p> 
<p>U.S. commanders, however, stop short of saying IS is defeated, pointing to remaining militants and fighting in Syria. They also note the group has spawned affiliates in other countries, such as Afghanistan and Yemen, where they routinely attack U.S. forces and allies. While reeling as a territorial force, the IS group has inspired terrorist attacks in the West.</p> 
<p>The Pentagon has yet to see the massive increase in military spending that Trump has promised. That still might come, but the protracted struggle to pass a Pentagon budget of whatever size has hurt U.S. military readiness, defense officials say.</p> 
<p>More broadly, Trump's "America First" ethic has been reflected in his pressure on member NATO countries to step up their own military spending, in his wariness of international accords and in the seeming drift from a diplomatic tradition of promoting U.S. democratic values abroad.</p> 
<p>Past presidents made common cause with authoritarian figures, and their promotion of values could be cursory. But Trump has lavished praise on select strongmen, from the Philippines to China to Russia and beyond.</p> 
<p>Despite railing against the Iran nuclear deal as a candidate, Trump has so far passed up opportunities to get the U.S. out of it. On the other hand, he rolled back part of Obama's opening to Cuba. He also moved forward on recognizing Jerusalem as the capital of Israel, a goal that both parties have embraced in their platforms for decades but never acted on.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>INFRASTRUCTURE</p> 
<p>Trump pledged a $1 trillion effort to rebuild the country's airports, roads, bridges and other infrastructure. As with his tax plan, it's shaping up to be less ambitious than promised, though it still might be significant. Placed behind the failed effort to repeal the health law and the successful one to cut taxes, infrastructure may or may not emerge as a proposal in coming weeks. Trump's idea appears to involve using federal tax dollars to leverage state government and private spending, not to mount a New Deal-era explosion of federal projects.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>VETERANS</p> 
<p>Having previously criticized the Department of Veterans Affairs as the "most corrupt," Trump delivered on one campaign promise by signing legislation to make it easier for VA employees to be fired for misconduct.</p> 
<p>At least for now, its impact in bringing accountability to the department remains unclear. The pace of VA firings during Obama's last budget year was higher than during Trump's first, which covered the first nine months of his administration.</p> 
<p>Other Trump initiatives announced with fanfare in 2017 remain far from complete or have been limited because of questions about rising government costs: a multibillion-dollar overhaul of electronic medical records, expanded access to doctors to reduce wait times and a goal of hiring 1,000 additional mental health counselors in the first year. The VA has been clouded by a 2014 scandal at the Phoenix VA hospital in which employees manipulated records to hide appointment delays.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>... AND MORE</p> 
<p>Despite his promises, Trump hasn't pushed for a constitutional amendment to impose term limits on Congress members or worked to end birthright citizenship, and he hasn't made good on his pledge to drop "dirty, rotten traitor" Bowe Bergdahl out of an airplane over Afghanistan without a parachute.</p> 
<p>Trump, who spends nearly every weekend golfing at one of his properties, most certainly hasn't fulfilled his promise never to take a vacation while serving as president.</p> 
<p>Indeed, Trump has visited properties he owns nearly one of every three days he's been in office, raising a tangle of ethical questions about whether he's profiting from his presidency.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>THE BIG BOAST</p> 
<p>Trump didn't wait for his first 100 days to expire before boasting that his presidential achievements thus far surpassed anything in history, and he hasn't let up since. He's bragged of having signed more than 80 pieces of legislation into law, but there's little of consequence in that pile.</p> 
<p>He's signed laws naming federal buildings after people, appointing a Smithsonian Institution regent and other housekeeping steps that all presidents do but tend not to make a fuss about.</p> 
<p>In contrast, Obama signed an enormous stimulus package into law in his first month while also achieving a law expanding health care for children and other policy steps.</p> 
<p>Then there's Franklin Roosevelt, credited by historians Alan Brinkley and Davis Dyer with achieving "the most concentrated period of U.S. reform in U.S. history," starting immediately with emergency legislation to stabilize the Depression-devastated banking system and setting in place the New Deal with 14 pieces of historic legislation in 100 days.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>Associated Press writer Hope Yen contributed to this report.</p> 
<p>WASHINGTON (AP) ? President Donald Trump often brags that he's done more in his first year in office than any other president. That's a spectacular stretch.</p> 
<p>But while he's fallen short on many measures and has a strikingly thin legislative record, Trump has followed through on dozens of his campaign promises, overhauling the country's tax system, changing the U.S. posture abroad and upending the lives of hundreds of thousands of immigrants.</p> 
<p>A year in, Trump is no closer to making Mexico pay for a border wall than when he made supporters swoon with that promise at those rollicking campaign rallies of 2016.</p> 
<p>He's run into legislative roadblocks ? from fellow Republicans, no less ? at big moments, which is why the Obama-era health law survives, wounded but still insuring millions. His own administration's sloppy start explains why none of the laws he pledged to sign in his first 100 days came to reality then and why most are still aspirational.</p> 
<p>Nevertheless, Trump has nailed the tax overhaul, his only historic legislative accomplishment to date, won confirmation of a conservative Supreme Court justice and other federal judges, and used his executive powers with vigor to slice regulations and pull the U.S. away from international accords he assailed as a candidate.</p> 
<p>Courts tied his most provocative actions on immigration and Muslim entry in knots, but illegal border crossings appear to be at historic lows.</p> 
<p>The upshot? For all his rogue tendencies, Trump has shaped up as a largely conventional Republican president when measured by his promises kept and in motion.</p> 
<p>The Twitter version of Trump may be jazzed with braggadocio about the size of his (nonexistent) nuclear button and his "very stable genius." But the ledger of actions taken is recognizable to Washington: mainstream Republican tax cuts, pro-business policy (with exceptions on trade), curbs on environmental regulation and an approach to health care that's been in the GOP playbook for years.</p> 
<p>That's as of today and this moment. With Trump, you never know about tomorrow.</p> 
<p>A look at some of his campaign promises and what's happened with them:</p> 
<p>TAXES</p> 
<p>Trump and congressional Republicans delivered on an overhaul that substantially lowers corporate taxes and cuts personal income taxes, as promised. It's sizable but not everything Trump said it would be, and it is more tilted to the wealthy than he promised or will admit. He promised a 15 percent tax rate for corporations and settled for 21 percent, still a major drop from 35 percent. He promised three tax brackets; there are still seven. He did not eliminate the estate tax or the alternative minimum tax as he said he would. Fewer people will be subject to those taxes, however, at least temporarily.</p> 
<p>"Everybody is getting a tax cut, especially the middle class," he said in the campaign. Most will; some will pay more.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>TRADE</p> 
<p>Trump made good on his promise to withdraw the U.S. from the Trans-Pacific Partnership trade agreement and to reopen the North American Free Trade Agreement in search of a better deal.</p> 
<p>He's let China off the hook, though, on his oft-repeated threat during the campaign to brand Beijing a currency manipulator, a step toward potentially hefty penalties on Chinese imports and a likely spark for a trade war.</p> 
<p>"We're like the piggy bank that's being robbed," he said of the trade relationship, which has tipped even more in China's favor since. Trump now threatens trade punishment if China does not sufficiently cooperate in reining in North Korea.</p> 
<p>Trump promised to impose a 35 percent tariff on goods from U.S. companies that ship production abroad. He's not delivered on that. Instead, his tax plan aims to encourage companies to stay in the U.S. with the lower tax rate and to entice those operating abroad to come home by letting them repatriate their profits in the U.S. at a temporarily discounted rate. His approach so far is all carrot, no stick.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>IMMIGRATION</p> 
<p>Candidate Trump rocked the political landscape when he proposed a temporary ban on all non-U.S. Muslims entering the country. While he's long backed away from such talk, Trump has worked since his first days in office to impose new restrictions on tourists and immigrants, signing executive orders that would have made good on his anti-immigration promises had those orders not been blocked by courts.</p> 
<p>He's now succeeded in banning the entry of citizens from several Muslim-majority countries and in severely curbing refugee admissions. He's tried to deny certain federal money for cities that refuse to cooperate with federal immigration authorities.</p> 
<p>Trump is now deep in negotiations over an immigration deal that could deliver on other promises, including money for the border wall with Mexico and overhauling the legal immigration system to make it harder for immigrants to sponsor their families. That's in exchange for extending protections for hundreds of thousands of young people brought to the country illegally as children. They are protections he once slammed as an "illegal" amnesty and pledged to end.</p> 
<p>Mexico still isn't ponying up money for the wall.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>ENERGY AND THE ENVIRONMENT</p> 
<p>Trump promised aggressive action on the energy front and has pursued that.</p> 
<p>He announced his intention to take the U.S. out of the Paris climate-change accord. He gave swift approval to the Keystone XL and Dakota Access pipelines stalled by President Barack Obama, moved to shrink protected national monument lands in Utah and Arizona, and acted to lift restrictions on mining coal and coastal drilling for oil and natural gas.</p> 
<p>A provision in the new tax law opens the long-protected Arctic National Wildlife Refuge to drilling.</p> 
<p>As other countries turn harder toward green energy, Trump is making fossil fuels the centerpiece of his drive toward energy independence ? a benchmark that Obama closed in on during an era of surging natural gas development.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>HEALTH CARE</p> 
<p>Probably nothing exemplifies frustrated ambition more than the Obama health law Republicans have been trying to dismantle ever since it was enacted in 2010. Trump has declared it dead many times ? he just never got around to killing it.</p> 
<p>He made this overpromise in the campaign: "My first day in office, I'm going to ask Congress to put a bill on my desk getting rid of this disastrous law and replacing it with reforms that expand choice, freedom, affordability. You're going to have such great health care at a tiny fraction of the cost. It's going to be so easy."</p> 
<p>That hasn't happened.</p> 
<p>Republicans took several runs at repealing and replacing the law last year, only to fall short. The December tax law, though, is knocking out a pillar. As of 2019, the requirement to carry health insurance or pay a fine will be gone.</p> 
<p>Trump has come out with a proposed regulation to promote the sale of health plans across state lines. The goal is to make it easier for associations to sponsor plans that are cheaper than Affordable Care Act policies but don't have to meet all consumer protection and benefit requirements of that law.</p> 
<p>Insurance industry groups, patient groups and some state regulators are wary of the idea and see little chance it can make more than a dent in the ranks of the uninsured (nearly 30 million). Easing restrictions on the sale of health insurance across state lines has been a longtime mainstream conservative goal.</p> 
<p>He also promised to authorize Medicare to negotiate lower prescription drug prices. It hasn't been done.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>'AMERICA FIRST' ABROAD</p> 
<p>Trump promised swift victory over the Islamic State group. Over the past year, U.S. and coalition-backed local forces in Iraq and Syria did deal a crushing blow to IS, ousting the militants from most of the territory they once held. The success built on the strategy of the Obama administration to work with and through local forces. Trump did relax restrictions on the number of U.S. troops who could be deployed both to Iraq and Syria, and that aided the final push.</p> 
<p>U.S. commanders, however, stop short of saying IS is defeated, pointing to remaining militants and fighting in Syria. They also note the group has spawned affiliates in other countries, such as Afghanistan and Yemen, where they routinely attack U.S. forces and allies. While reeling as a territorial force, the IS group has inspired terrorist attacks in the West.</p> 
<p>The Pentagon has yet to see the massive increase in military spending that Trump has promised. That still might come, but the protracted struggle to pass a Pentagon budget of whatever size has hurt U.S. military readiness, defense officials say.</p> 
<p>More broadly, Trump's "America First" ethic has been reflected in his pressure on member NATO countries to step up their own military spending, in his wariness of international accords and in the seeming drift from a diplomatic tradition of promoting U.S. democratic values abroad.</p> 
<p>Past presidents made common cause with authoritarian figures, and their promotion of values could be cursory. But Trump has lavished praise on select strongmen, from the Philippines to China to Russia and beyond.</p> 
<p>Despite railing against the Iran nuclear deal as a candidate, Trump has so far passed up opportunities to get the U.S. out of it. On the other hand, he rolled back part of Obama's opening to Cuba. He also moved forward on recognizing Jerusalem as the capital of Israel, a goal that both parties have embraced in their platforms for decades but never acted on.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>INFRASTRUCTURE</p> 
<p>Trump pledged a $1 trillion effort to rebuild the country's airports, roads, bridges and other infrastructure. As with his tax plan, it's shaping up to be less ambitious than promised, though it still might be significant. Placed behind the failed effort to repeal the health law and the successful one to cut taxes, infrastructure may or may not emerge as a proposal in coming weeks. Trump's idea appears to involve using federal tax dollars to leverage state government and private spending, not to mount a New Deal-era explosion of federal projects.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>VETERANS</p> 
<p>Having previously criticized the Department of Veterans Affairs as the "most corrupt," Trump delivered on one campaign promise by signing legislation to make it easier for VA employees to be fired for misconduct.</p> 
<p>At least for now, its impact in bringing accountability to the department remains unclear. The pace of VA firings during Obama's last budget year was higher than during Trump's first, which covered the first nine months of his administration.</p> 
<p>Other Trump initiatives announced with fanfare in 2017 remain far from complete or have been limited because of questions about rising government costs: a multibillion-dollar overhaul of electronic medical records, expanded access to doctors to reduce wait times and a goal of hiring 1,000 additional mental health counselors in the first year. The VA has been clouded by a 2014 scandal at the Phoenix VA hospital in which employees manipulated records to hide appointment delays.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>... AND MORE</p> 
<p>Despite his promises, Trump hasn't pushed for a constitutional amendment to impose term limits on Congress members or worked to end birthright citizenship, and he hasn't made good on his pledge to drop "dirty, rotten traitor" Bowe Bergdahl out of an airplane over Afghanistan without a parachute.</p> 
<p>Trump, who spends nearly every weekend golfing at one of his properties, most certainly hasn't fulfilled his promise never to take a vacation while serving as president.</p> 
<p>Indeed, Trump has visited properties he owns nearly one of every three days he's been in office, raising a tangle of ethical questions about whether he's profiting from his presidency.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>THE BIG BOAST</p> 
<p>Trump didn't wait for his first 100 days to expire before boasting that his presidential achievements thus far surpassed anything in history, and he hasn't let up since. He's bragged of having signed more than 80 pieces of legislation into law, but there's little of consequence in that pile.</p> 
<p>He's signed laws naming federal buildings after people, appointing a Smithsonian Institution regent and other housekeeping steps that all presidents do but tend not to make a fuss about.</p> 
<p>In contrast, Obama signed an enormous stimulus package into law in his first month while also achieving a law expanding health care for children and other policy steps.</p> 
<p>Then there's Franklin Roosevelt, credited by historians Alan Brinkley and Davis Dyer with achieving "the most concentrated period of U.S. reform in U.S. history," starting immediately with emergency legislation to stabilize the Depression-devastated banking system and setting in place the New Deal with 14 pieces of historic legislation in 100 days.</p> 
<p>___</p> 
<p>Associated Press writer Hope Yen contributed to this report.</p></article>
<article id="0000118" published-at="2012-08-20" title="Indonesia: Earthquake kills at least 6, injures 49"><p>A 6.3 magnitude earthquake struck Indonesia's&amp;#160;Sulawesi Island on Sunday, killing at least 6 people, seriously wounding 8, and slightly injuring 35, according to the <a href="http://www.bnpb.go.id/website/asp/berita_list.asp?id=973" type="external">National Disaster Management Agency</a>&amp;#160;(BNPB). Hundreds of buildings were destroyed.</p> 
<p>"The quake was felt strongly for 15 seconds in Palu as people were breaking the fast" said a spokesman for BNPB, <a href="http://www.newser.com/story/152432/deadly-63-quake-hits-indonesia.html" type="external">according to Newser</a>. Sunday was the last day of Ramadan, the Muslim holy month.</p> 
<p>Sutopo Purwo Nugroho of BNPB told <a href="http://www.seattlepi.com/news/article/6-dead-in-earthquake-on-northern-Indonesian-island-3799991.php" type="external">&amp;#160;SeattlePI</a> that rescue workers are clearing roads to at least 14 towns cut off by landslides.</p> 
<p>Helicopters are delivering food and water to residents who cannot be reached by overland supply routes, <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2012/08/20/world/asia/indonesia-earthquake/index.html" type="external">CNN reports</a>.&amp;#160;BNPB says food, blankets and tents are urgently needed.</p> 
<p>On Dec. 26, 2004, an under water megathrust earthquake created a&amp;#160;tsunami that killed around 230,000 people, many from Indonesia's Aceh province.</p> 
<p>Indonesia sits within the Pacific "Ring of Fire," a horseshoe shaped area in the Pacific Basin that experiences frequent earthquakes and volcanic eruptions.</p></article>
<article id="0000119" published-at="2015-05-04" title="ER docs busier than ever since Obamacare, poll shows"><p>Emergency physicians in the U.S.&amp;#160;have reported&amp;#160;an increase in the volume of patients since January 1, 2014, when the Affordable Care Act requiring health insurance went into effect, and they are not confident that ERs across the country are prepared, <a href="http://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/844196" type="external">according to a new poll.</a></p> 
<p>?The reliance on emergency care remains stronger than ever,? said Michael Gerardi, MD, president of the American College of Emergency Physicians,&amp;#160;in a statement. ?It?s the only place that?s open 24/7, and we never turn anyone away.?</p> 
<p>The college invited 24,427 member physicians to complete the poll, 2099 of whom did, for a response rate of approximately 9%. The poll was conducted to gauge changes in ED patient volume and care since the Affordable Care Act went into effect.</p> 
<p>With the implementation of the ACA, 47% of emergency physicians reported a slight increase in the number of patients, and 28% reported significant increases in patient volume.</p> 
<p>56% of emergency physicians&amp;#160;reported an increase in the number of Medicare patients, and 70% fear their ED is not sufficiently prepared for an increase in patient volume. Despite these concerns,&amp;#160;83% have concerns about efforts being made by hospitals to reduce emergency visits; specifically, that patients will put off&amp;#160;medical care or&amp;#160;utilize facilities with less/poorer resources.</p> 
<p>?There is strong evidence that Medicaid access to primary care and specialty care is not timely, leaving Medicaid patients with few options other than the [ED],? said&amp;#160;Orlee Panitch, MD, chair of the Emergency Medicine Action Fund, which&amp;#160;ordered the poll.</p> 
<p>?In addition, states with punitive policies toward Medicaid patients in the [ED] may be discouraging low-income patients with serious medical conditions from seeking necessary care, which is dangerous and wrong.? Panitch continued.</p> 
<p>Dr Gerardi cited concerns about&amp;#160;the closure of hospitals and emergency care facilities&amp;#160;in states that have not expanded Medicaid.</p> 
<p>?Hospitals received less Medicare funding for charity care when the [Affordable Care Act] took effect, because more people were supposed to have health insurance coverage,? said Gerardi. ?But in states that didn?t expand Medicaid, hospitals are hurting. For example, the closure of a hospital in Baton Rouge resulted in a crisis for another hospital that inherited all the patients, many of whom are uninsured, and now this hospital may close as well. The average reimbursement for a Medicaid patient in the [ED] is about $43.00, but it?s much lower in many states.?</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>Perhaps most alarmingly, 34% of the physicians polled&amp;#160;have considered leaving the profession.</p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p></p></article>
<article id="0000120" published-at="2004-01-30" title="The David Kay Report"><p>&amp;#160;</p> 
<p>?We were all wrong?</p> 
<p>David Kay</p> 
<p>We can finally put Weapons of Mass Destruction issue to rest.</p> 
<p>With the publishing of the Kay report it is clear that the entire pretense for the Iraq war was nothing more than a hoax. Kay appeared before a Senate subcommittee to disclose his findings and admitted that he and his team had found no stockpiles of proscribed weapons in Iraq.</p> 
<p>At one point he opined, ?We were wrong, we were all wrong.?</p> 
<p>Wrong?</p> 
<p>An estimated 8,000 innocent Iraqis died in the invasion, more than 500 American servicemen were killed in action, an entire country was destabilized and plunged into insurgency, and David Kay talks about being wrong like it was some minor miscalculation on the phone bill?</p> 
<p>This is the reality of the Bush Administration?s new ?preemptive? theory; hundreds of billions of dollars are spent, countless lives are lost or ruined, and the world community is thrown into turmoil, and yet, no justification is provided.</p> 
<p>Even worse, the head of the weapons inspection team presents his case to Congress as though it was all ?just an honest mistake?.</p> 
<p>So, why did Kay choose to address the Senate in the first place?</p> 
<p>After all, Kay has been a reliable Bush loyalist, and that hasn?t changed.</p> 
<p>Kay?s real intention in addressing the Senate was to use the CIA as a scapegoat for the bad information that led to the war. Now, that the election is approaching, the President?s chief advisor, Karl Rove, is trying to put as much distance as he can between the White House and the myriad lies about the non-existent weapons.</p> 
<p>This is a delicate situation and has to be handled with great subtlety or intelligence agencies will see that Bush is trying to bury them in the media. Hence, the appearance of David Kay is intended to reinforce the false notion that the war was the result of faulty intelligence. Kay?s testimony challenged the reliability of intelligence gathering methods and suggested that we may need a ?major overhaul? of the intelligence services.</p> 
<p>Absent from the testimony was any detailed recounting of the many fabrications that were repeated with propaganda-like precision to support the war. Also, absent was the clear implication that the Administration was directly involved in ?cherry-picking? intelligence to suit its own purposes.</p> 
<p>Apart from Senator Edward Kennedy, there was no mention of the fact that the Vice President was pressuring the CIA with frequent visits to produce information that was compatible with his own warmongering objectives, or that an Office of Special Plans was developed in the Pentagon for the expressed purpose of selectively manufacturing evidence that Saddam was a threat.</p> 
<p>Most of this passed by completely unnoticed. Instead, the Administration has adroitly used its main inspector to ?move the shells? one more time, and shift the blame onto the undeserving CIA.</p> 
<p>But, the CIA doesn?t create policy and it doesn?t make the decision to go to war; the President does.</p> 
<p>The CIA was skeptical about the Iraq threat from the very beginning. Its reluctance to endorse the Bush preemptive policy was evident in an earlier report that clearly stated that a war in Iraq would increase the likelihood of terrorism in the region and, perhaps, force Saddam to give whatever weapons he had to terrorist organizations.</p> 
<p>This warning was ignored.</p> 
<p>It seems only appropriate that Kay would give his report on a day when six more American servicemen and eleven more Iraqis were killed. His loyalty to the Bush policy of unprovoked aggression provides an interesting contrast to the grim facts on the ground. Men and women are dying every day in what we know now was an entirely avoidable war.</p> 
<p>The testimony of David Kay only confirms that point.</p> 
<p>MIKE WHITNEY can be reached at: <a href="mailto:fergiewhitney@msn.com" type="external">fergiewhitney@msn.com</a></p> 
<p>&amp;#160;</p></article>
<article id="0000121" published-at="2017-11-07" title="Haunting Estate Planning Errors: The Case of the Zombie Documents"><p>For the Halloween episode of <a href="https://www.fool.com/podcasts/answers/?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;referring_guid=b48e2aec-c2db-11e7-a29c-0050569d32b9&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">Motley Fool Answers Opens a New Window.</a>, Alison Southwick and Robert Brokamp engage in a spirited discussion of the horrors some folks have visited upon their families' finances from the afterlife by making big mistakes in estate planning.</p> 
<p>In this segment, they discuss a nonfamous fellow, DuPont&amp;#160;employee William Kennedy, who -- as sometimes happens -- divorced his wife. At the time, the ex agreed to waive her rights to his retirement plan assets. When he died though, guess where the money went.</p> 
<p>Continue Reading Below</p> 
<p>A full transcript follows the video.</p> 
<p>10 stocks we like better than&amp;#160;Wal-MartWhen investing geniuses David and Tom&amp;#160;Gardner have a stock tip, it can pay to listen. After all, the newsletter they&amp;#160;have run for over a decade, the Motley Fool Stock Advisor, has tripled the market.*</p> 
<p>David and Tom&amp;#160;just revealed what they believe are the&amp;#160; <a href="https://www.fool.com/mms/mark/e-sa-bbn-eg?aid=8867&amp;amp;source=isaeditxt0000476&amp;amp;ftm_cam=sa-bbn-evergreen&amp;amp;ftm_pit=6627&amp;amp;ftm_veh=article_pitch&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;referring_guid=b48e2aec-c2db-11e7-a29c-0050569d32b9&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">ten best stocks Opens a New Window.</a>&amp;#160;for investors to buy right now... and Wal-Mart wasn't one of them! That's right -- they&amp;#160;think these 10 stocks are even better buys.</p> 
<p><a href="https://www.fool.com/mms/mark/e-sa-bbn-eg?aid=8867&amp;amp;source=isaeditxt0000476&amp;amp;ftm_cam=sa-bbn-evergreen&amp;amp;ftm_pit=6627&amp;amp;ftm_veh=article_pitch&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;referring_guid=b48e2aec-c2db-11e7-a29c-0050569d32b9&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">Click here Opens a New Window.</a>&amp;#160;to learn about these picks!</p> 
<p>*Stock Advisor returns as of November 6, 2017The author(s) may have a position in any stocks mentioned.</p> 
<p>Advertisement</p> 
<p>This video was recorded on Oct. 31, 2017.</p> 
<p>Alison Southwick: Just when you thought she was out of your life for good, it's Zombie Wife.</p> 
<p>Robert Brokamp: This is the case of William Kennedy. Not part of the famous Kennedy family. This Kennedy worked for DuPont and participated in the company's retirement plan. In 1994 he and his wife, whose name was Liv, got divorced and in the agreement she waived any rights to his retirement plan.</p> 
<p>Seven years later, William passes away. The money, however, was sent from the retirement plan to the wife. Why? Because William did not update the beneficiary form on his retirement plan. When you signed up for your 401(k) at work, you filled out the beneficiary form, but you also have that on IRAs. You have it on life insurance policies. There are all types of different assets and accounts in which you've filled out the beneficiary form.</p> 
<p>He didn't update it, so the daughter who should have [or at least she thought] should have inherited the money took it to court. Went all the way to the Supreme Court in 2009. They decided for Liv, the ex-wife. She's the one who gets the $400,000.</p> 
<p>Southwick: Oh, that's not bad! That's not too shabby.</p> 
<p>Brokamp: No, not too bad. The lesson here is to review and update your beneficiary forms and include copies with all your other important papers.</p> 
<p><a href="http://my.fool.com/profile/TMFAlison/info.aspx?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;referring_guid=b48e2aec-c2db-11e7-a29c-0050569d32b9&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">Alison Southwick Opens a New Window.</a> has no position in any of the stocks mentioned. <a href="http://my.fool.com/profile/TMFBro/info.aspx?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;referring_guid=b48e2aec-c2db-11e7-a29c-0050569d32b9&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">Robert Brokamp, CFP Opens a New Window.</a> has no position in any of the stocks mentioned. The Motley Fool has no position in any of the stocks mentioned. The Motley Fool has a <a href="http://www.fool.com/Legal/fool-disclosure-policy.aspx?&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;referring_guid=b48e2aec-c2db-11e7-a29c-0050569d32b9&amp;amp;utm_source=foxbusiness" type="external">disclosure policy Opens a New Window.</a>.</p></article>
</articles>